>> Welcome back everyone.
In this session, we have
a panel on NDN's
accessibility.
This is more of an
informal panel,
so we don't have slides,
we are going to go around,
talk about what it
means to be accessible,
what are the challenges
and how we can solve this.
For the panelists, we
have Alex from Clemson,
James from Air Force
Research Lab, Christos,
University of Memphis,
Matthias from Berlin,
and then make
Beichuan from
University of Arizona.
Welcome to the
panel. Maybe we
can go around and
introduce ourselves
to the audience.
Alex, you want
to go first?
>> Yeah, sure.
I'm, Alex Feltus.
I'm a professor at
Clemson University
in the Department
of Genetics
and Biochemistry.
I'm not network engineer.
We study plants
and animals.
I just had a lab meeting
where we were talking
about how bean
plants fix nitrogen
from the air and how
bone wasting disease might
be occurring genetically,
and also, we talked about
how we can estimate
Cloud resource
usage if we're to
run our workflows in
the same lab meeting.
We're using NDN to try
to aggregate data,
make a data
lake to be able
to access all the
genomes that had
been sequenced for anybody
that does any
real Biology,
a lot of people use
these datasets now.
>> Beichuan.
>> Hi, can you
hear me okay?
>> Yes, we can hear you.
>> Thanks. I'm doing
several mic checks.
I'm James Lyke,
I'm with the Air Force
Research Laboratory and I
work in Space
Vehicle Development.
I'm very interested in
networking in
a global sense
or spacecraft
play a role in
facilitating the
network connectivity.
I also have an
adjunct professor
at the University
in Mexico,
that's actually where
I'm sitting today.
I think the interest
we have in NDN is
using it in some
way to help
facilitate an improvement
in connectivity.
I think in some
sense it has
interesting features
that we wanted to exploit.
I'm interested in
more pervasive uses
in Department of Defense,
but then we have
also experienced some
significant barriers.
I think it's that
ossification that we hear
about with Internet
technologies,
Internet protocols,
and some of those
barriers are very
difficult and so in
research trying to
figure out ways
to make the benefits of
NDN more accessible,
more understood. Thanks.
>> Thank you. Beichuan,
do you want to go next?
>> Yeah, my name's
Beichuan Zhang.
I'm a Professor of
Neuroscience Department,
University of Arizona.
I am a network researcher.
I have been working on
NDN for last decade.
I'm not really a
real-world user
of NDN for this panel,
but I can talk about
my group experience of
developing some
applications
and the accessibility
issues we ran
into and effort we're
trying to solve
those issues,
but still they
solve a problem,
so also very interesting.
Let's hear what
other people
on this panel will
say about that.
>> Thank you. Christos.
>> I'm Christos
Papadopoulos,
I'm a professor at the
University of Memphis,
also in Computer
Science and
my background is also
networking like Beichuan.
I have been with the NDN
team since the beginning.
I spent a couple
of years at
the HS as a
program manager,
and that is where
I got exposed
to things such as
legal cybersecurity,
which I found
really interesting,
and my interest after
that is seeing
how to apply NDN
into legal
communication and more
broadly into
the transportation
infrastructure. Thanks.
>> Thank you,
Christos. Matthias.
>> Hello, my
name is Matthias
from F. Berlin.
I'm an Assistant
Professor heading
the Internet technologies
research group.
One of my research is
Internet of Things,
and this is one use
case that we try to
exploit for NDN
and IC in general.
I'm not only
doing research,
I'm also involved in
open source communities.
I'm also the co-founder of
RIOT operating system,
an open-source
operating system
for constraint
IoT devices.
This is where we
try to exploit
the benefits of NDN by
segment resources such
as battery power,
increased scalability
and and loss in networks.
>> Great, thank you.
I think we will have
a few diverse
applications as from
genomics and then
space and IoT.
I think that accessibility
challenges are going to
be different for this.
Maybe the panelists can
talk a little bit about
what were the challenges
that you faced when
you tried to use NDN.
Is it backup
documentation,
lack of customer
applications,
is it lack of
quantifiability?
Matthias, you
mentioned IoT,
maybe what are
the challenges
in using NDN for IoT?
>> From a software
point of view,
actually I do not see
much challenges from
the NDN companies.
It is well-documented,
the maintainers are
easily approachable.
It's definitely
a challenge from
a systems
perspective to bring
NDN's deck to
constraint devices,
but it's doable.
From this point of view,
I do not see
much challenges
even for our
research purposes.
in the end, I see
endish approaches
in larger testbeds.
Where maybe I
see a challenge,
is these testbeds,
is some more little
bit constrained,
confined
environments to have
actually easily
accessible testbeds
that spends several
universities and
they have in the
real inter-domain
type of connectivity.
This is something
that I actually miss.
The other thing
that I miss is
perspectives on
a global level,
global approach in the
sense, for example,
that there's not much
thought and effort in,
for example, how to
manage the
namespace in NDN,
and this is
independent of IoT.
But I think a very
crucial aspects
that we have a lot of
interesting and
challenging research
questions that
you all tackled,
but we somehow miss the
operational aspects,
and so that is how we
manage the
namespace in case
of NDN gets globally used.
>> There is the
challenge then
in deploying NDN
rather than using NDN
in a small-scale.
>> I mean, it's
definitely a challenge.
It is always a
challenge to get
a new protocol and
architecture deployed.
>> No, even within this
research community,
not in the
internet per se.
>> No. I mean using
NDN in the research
environment.
I don't think it's a
challenge actually,
it is straightforward
and useable.
>> When you say
global approach,
you mean the actual
commercial intranet.
>> Right. Getting
NDN out of the lab,
and in addition to
what I said before is,
I think we miss
awareness in
the operational
community about NDN,
and this is something
that probably
prevents larger adoption
of software system.
For example, I never
heard someone talking
about NDN on at
NANOG for example.
But if you want to get
NDN out of the lab,
you'll need to
raise awareness
outside of the
research community.
>> James you mentioned
ossification.
It's becoming hard to use
anything other than IP.
What's your take on this?
>> Well, I think
to that problem
specifically,
I experienced this
problem in other areas,
having nothing to do with
networking per se,
like interfaces.
For example, we have
something in
Department of Defense
called mill standard 1553.
I don't know if any of
you've heard of It,
but It was an
aircraft interface
invented in the 1970s.
It was really
first put to use
on the 15 aircraft.
It's a very slow but
very deterministic.
I guess I'd call it
layer two technology.
It's still in use
today and we can't
get rid of It.
It keeps
reasserting itself,
and a lot of It is because
people are
comfortable with It.
They've used It before.
That is just a
tiny example
of how the
ossification problem
happens in things
having nothing to do
with, say,
Internet Protocol.
It's just a much
worse problem if we,
I think there's
a lot of beauty
and elegance in
the NDN concept.
I think people
appreciate that
even with overview
presentations.
But, I think
the would-be
proponents are
soon running into a
type of a buzz saw.
Because we find
people want
to legislate
the use of IP.
I may almost say,
well, It must
be IP that works good.
It's worked good
for so many years.
I think the conservativism
has a strong barrier.
I'm a big fan
of being able
to create maybe
educational,
ideas that help improve
educational exposure.
I've made appeals
for people,
to create, for example,
a virtual like
maybe a single
click Install
that allows you
to kick the tires on
NDN to work through
simple examples
and tutorials.
I'm finding that
It's difficult to
simply just grab NDN
and explore It if you
are a casual user.
I think that the
degree to which
that could be
done would go
a long way to show
people the benefits.
Let's just put It this
way, it can't hurt.
But there are significant
barriers and I
don't have easy answers.
I've thought about this
for a while and we've
demonstrated some
research implementations
of the idea,
and people will say,
"Yeah, that's pretty neat,
but I'm not really going
to be able to use It
because I have all
these rules that I,
and none of them are.,
they're all hostile for
new ideas like NDN,
I wish it weren't
the case.
>> I mean, inertia
is a problem.
We have been seeing
this for some time.
What can we do as a
community to make
them at least
take a look at
NDN and explore
and say that well,
this might make sense
for my use case.
You mentioned
a single click
Install documentation.
Well, I guess
documentation
is not going to help.
It's more easy to use
turn on solutions.
Maybe a container,
is that?
>> I like to
think things like
that, for example,
maybe even very
simplified web only
demonstration.
I think people who
get their hands
dirty, so to speak,
with networking and
understand the concepts.
[NOISE] I'm sorry.
They can spend the time
and they can tackle
the learning curve.
I think when people
get an overview
presentation,
it's also at a high
level, It's encapsulated.
They get the ideas.
But then there's
this vast chasm
between those
two extremes.
The people who
have the time to
invest and can in
their laboratories
show the benefits
and the casual people say,
well that sounds
like a neat idea.
There needs to be a
few increments in between,
and I would just
say educationally,
you can't hurt the
cause by looking for
more creative ways to
get these ideas
out in the world.
But things that allow,
I know even like
with Docker,
for example, there's
a docker Labs,
which is a neat idea where
you can go to a
website and for
four hours you get
to play with Docker
and you can do a lot
in a short time,
things like that for NDN
I think would help a lot.
I would certainly be
front at the line trying
to explore that myself
and I would certainly
share that with
colleagues.
But right now it's
a very rarified
group of people who
have the ability
to really dig in
and look in real
life at NDN,
if there's a much
bigger world out there
and you should consider
ways of reaching
that world.
It's not just aerospace,
just many other sectors,
but aerospace is the
one that I work in.
I know people are
attracted by the idea,
but then they
just quickly run
into lots of barriers.
>> Thank you. I
think we're going to
go to Christos
and Beichuan.
You have lot of experience
in NDN for different
use cases.
What's your take
on how we can make
this simpler for James
and his colleagues.
>> Since you put
my name first,
let me jump in.
First of all,
I'm so happy to
see so many people working
on applications on NDN.
That is exactly
what we need.
I want to remind
people that NDN has
a very unique
advantage compared to
IP in terms of when
was developed.
When IP was developed in
the 60s and the 70s,
people didn't really have
any experience
with networking.
They didn't know
what applications
would use networking.
There were some people
who never believed that
networking was important
or interesting.
It is not surprising that
they looked at
the telephone
which was the only
application that
we had that uses
networking and they said,
this is what we need,
let's build a network that
resembles the
phone network
and we know how that went.
Today with NDN, we
have a vast experience
with all applications
that use the network.
I think we're all here
because we believe that we
have a better way to do
networking than with IP.
But we need to use
that wisdom that we
have acquired by looking
at 50 years of
experience worth
of applications and try
to convince people who
use those applications
about the merits of NDN.
I think the best
way to do this
is to just go out there to
people who use
applications
and talk to them and
try to capture
their imagination.
We need to convince
the networking
researchers,
but we really need to
capture the imagination
of people who run
applications.
I'm so happy to
see Alex Feltus on
the panel because
I remember
talking to him at the
cc star PI meeting
and introducing
NDN to him.
He was interested,
he got it.
He was a big supporter
from day zero.
I was shocked
at how quickly
Alex got the
concept behind NDN.
We did the same
thing with climate
and high-energy
physics people.
We found groups,
communities
that had a need
and we tried to
speak to that need.
I think that was very
important thing in terms
of capturing their
imagination.
I'm trying to do
the same thing here
with the automotive
community.
The reason I'm doing
that, first of all,
it's a big domain,
it's a big application.
They have real needs.
Deploying a networking
on millions of vehicles,
connected vehicles,
autonomous vehicles.
The networking needs
insider vehicle.
The networking
needs some vehicles
to connect to the Cloud.
I don't have to
be speaking to
the choir here.
NDN is perfect for those.
They are asking questions
as they're moving to
IP that we were asking
when we were talking
about NDN at
the beginning.
The interesting
thing about
the automotive community
when they started
with simpler networks like
Cantor Controller
Area Network,
which was invented back
in the 80s by Bosch.
If you look at it, it
is the first ICN network.
It communicates by putting
names of signals
on the wire.
Very simple, very
primitive network,
but it is an
ICN network and
the automotive
community is
used to that paradigm.
We're forcing them into
an endpoint
communication with
IP and they're attracted
because of all the
standardization
or the work that
has gone in IP.
But this is not
the way they're used to
doing communication,
they're forced
into these now.
To summarize, I think
the best way to
evangelize and for
obligates NDN,
is to just go out there
find the Alex Feltus
service community.
We have real needs.
Talk to them.
There are people
out there who will
understand the
technical aspect
of NDN, and their
advantages.
Let's find them,
talk to them,
and see if we can convince
them that we have
a better way to do
things. That's it.
>> Thank Christos.
Beichuan.
>> I totally agree
with Christos
what has said.
We need to get the ideas
from people who
actually use NDN in
their domain
and figure out
what are the problems
they run into
and try to solve
this problem to make
NDN being very used.
I want to follow up on
James' comments
about making this
more approachable,
more accessible to
cover users that
who don't have a lot of
time to go through
the learning curves.
I think that's a very
important point.
In our experience, we've
found out a
couple of things.
One is when we did
this browser-based video
streaming using NDN,
we find that it's a
very good approach
to involve everyday
user to use this.
Even though they may
now know they're
using NDN,
but they actually
using NDN video
streaming and it can
be a very good
demonstration.
From NDN researcher or
developer point
of view, I think,
strengthen this
browser support
is a good way to
improve the
accessibility of NDN.
I'm glad to see yesterday,
future topologies,
tap square library.
Varun talked about
his NDN play,
which is web-based demo.
I think those are
very good things.
Another thing there is
plug-and-play of NDN code.
My experience from
other people's
appearance I talk to,
UL they are two things.
One is, when you
set up NDN nodes,
let's say even
very small scale
and you want to run some
single NDN applications,
turns out you had to
set up the routes.
You have to know
the IP address and
set up the routes,
and this and that.
Is very counterintuitive
when we talk about NDN.
We develop the so-called
self-learning,
which you basically build
customer first packet and
find out where data is.
Then in the later,
later packets,
you automatically set up
routes based on the result
of the first packet.
Another thing is the
security bootstrap
is very big part of
this so-called
plug-and-play,
and that's really
non-trivial
because it involves
the policy,
involves a schema and
how you automate
all of this.
I think that's part
require a lot of work.
Coming together all this,
how to say how do
the falling states,
how to bootstrap security,
they are all
important so that
a user without
the time to deep
into the technical
details can actually
run and again say out of
the box without
too much hassle.
That's also very important
for improve the
accessibility of NDN.
Couple of other things,
I think also mentioned in
yesterday's either
talk or panel,
one is for the
application developers
who don't know a lot about
NDN network
details and who
shouldn't need to know
those details for
them to use NDN.
There should be a good
high-level library or
API for them to
easily cool run
NDN applications.
Probably a single library
will not be enough.
But say people work
in vehicle network,
they may come out
with their library,
that will be really good.
Or Alex come up with
his library for
people in this biological
research area,
that would be really good
to increase the
accessibility.
The last point I
want to make is,
my personal wish is if
there's some framework
so that people can
follow to migrate
existing applications
to NDN application.
In a real world,
there's so many
application people
have put in
so much time to
really develop
those applications.
But I see the
biggest obstacle
of NDN deployment is
you require changes
to the application.
In TCP, IP, they
all address to
some port numbers.
But now we need names,
and we need name come
from the application.
I see that's the
biggest hurdle
more than how efficient,
how scalable
your network is,
is people have to
make changes to
their application
in order to get
a lot of benefit from
any architecture.
It's not a simple question
like you just make
a few changes to
the function call
or somewhere,
it dependent with
applications.
Sometimes you have to
go deep into the
application,
and sometimes the
application itself was
designed with this
data-centric remind,
you just change the
network communication part
or some function course
that you ignore.
But sometimes you
have to go deep.
If there's some framework
to guide people go
through these courses,
I think that will
be very helpful.
These are the more
technical point,
I think what we need to
do in order to improve
the accessibility of NDN.
>> Beichuan, I'll
come to Alex
pretty soon and he
can tell us if I'm
thinking this correctly,
but you mentioned
that there're
simple applications
that we
can get them
started with NDN.
But I think
people like Alex,
they would take that
simple application.
They'll move
to the complex
stage pretty quickly.
Then that point,
the problem then
becomes on how
can I do this cool
thing with NDN.
It's not, can I get
started with NDN.
We need to have
more primitive
approach for
accessibility
and then more
advanced approach
where people
can actually play
the NDN libraries.
I think Alex,
you'd be better
suited to comment
on this one.
>> Can you hear me?
>> Yeah.. [NOISE]
>> If we're talking
about accessibility still,
I was trying to
think about that.
There's really
two versions
of accessibility for NDN.
Starting with the
real end-user,
the biologist,
I want to get it from
their perspective
that we need
a content delivery
system for genomes
where the genomes have
been processed and may
be downstream analysis in
those datasets where
we need to be able to
have them be
passed around and
a naming system is what
attracts me to NDN.
From an accessibility,
I need a data lake
and we're working
on the hydro project
together full
disclosure for
creating this
repository where
an application can
go in and say,
give me this version of
the human genome that's
been named properly,
then pull it into
a complex workflow
and then go out and have
all the troubleshooting
and everything
break after that because
whenever you're doing,
data intensive
genomics work,
it's always broken at
all levels of the
data lifecycle.
It's insane and I spend
a lot of my time teaching
how to troubleshoot just
the really bad
software systems.
But from
an NDN accessibility
perspective for user,
I just needed to
have the ability
for a person who
writes workflows,
writes links
applications together
to go and pull
data into it,
pull it in with a name.
That's really all
they need to know,
how to access this
documentation,
access the data lake,
pull data with the name
and move forward
with your stuff.
The other part of
the accessibility is
me trying to develop
the system and
I cannot do.
We've been doing it for
quite a while now and
I'm not a computer scientist
or network engineer,
I'm a bioinformatician
where
I know how to do stuff,
makes hack basically,
a lot of the data
and the workflows,
but I have to
work with Susmit
and Christos and
some other people
that I've been
working with on
implementing
this stuff with
people in my lab,
where I get part of
an FTE to program
on this for a few years
and get this to happen.
Then we've had major
accessibility problems,
even with working directly
with people in
the community,
they're awesome
with implementing
it on the system.
We have to have this stuff
work on a real system.
We use several distributed
Cloud-based systems,
again this
cluster we have,
and then there's problems
with networking.
Whenever trying
the test bed,
there's firewall issues or
just trying to get
containers to run on
a distributed
Kubernetes system and
being able to
have to turn on
some particular
networking aspect
that's been blocked
by the system
administrator, the system.
It's like trying to
get this thing
just to turn on
the switch and is
hard and that's from
an accessibility
perspective.
I wouldn't even begin
to do anything that I'm
trying to do
without direct help
from the computer science
network engineer community
that's here today.
I think the
accessibility is
basically zero
for somebody
like me based upon
the documentation and
things like that.
I wouldn't know how to
start to solve the problem
without having
my handheld.
I feel like it's coming
from the other
way too that,
I know what we need
after we get the data,
the usage after that
and try to make
the downstream
applications accessible to
the networking
community too
is what I'm trying to do.
Does that make any
sense? [NOISE]
>> Yeah, and I think
Beichuan talked about
this high-level
libraries and I think
Alex mentioned
[OVERLAPPING] its use
had been stopped.
Do you think if we had
high-level libraries that
implemented NDN primitive
that would be more?
I know we spend
a lot of time in
the first part
setting things up,
the forwarding and
getting all that working,
but that part can be
solved by having,
let's say,
virtual machines
or Docker containers.
The next part is
more challenging.
How do you integrate
NDN with your,
as Beichuan was saying,
existing workflows?
If we had high-level
libraries
that can take
care of that,
do you think that
would be more useful?
[NOISE]
>> Definitely, I have to have
a high level libraries, yes,
that will make it
more easy, but also
a system where I can
publish data from.
Right now, I'm
so interested
in creating the system,
creating the data
lake to be able to
use high-level
libraries to
interact with that place.
That's where we're trying
to get the containers and
everything packed
together right
now to have a system
that's functional.
[OVERLAPPING] The
answer is yes,
that'll be very helpful,
I'm sure, but
we're not even at
that stage for me.
>> You're saying the
accessibility challenges
are three levels, not two.
Getting started and then
getting the
infrastructure up,
and then doing the high
level applications.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Yes. We haven't
gotten there
yet to the high level
applications, yes.
We will need
that very soon.
>> The NDN community has
a couple of testbeds,
where NDN can run,
things can happen.
Do you think, and
this is the question
for all the other
panelists as well.
Just having a
testbed is that
sufficient or
do you want to
take this and run in on
your own system,
the infrastructure?
>> I would say that
the testbed is great.
I think the fact that
it has, I think,
36 notes as Zhang said
yesterday and
spans the world,
except Australia
and Antarctica
, I think you said.
That's wonderful,
and it's there
and a lot of
people can use it.
But it's a large
network Internet
style testbed.
We need more testbeds
for other applications.
Matthias, I think
will agree with me
that we need testbeds
to do IoT devices.
I'm looking at testbeds
that do automotive
devices.
I think as a community,
we should support
the big testbeds
and it's wonderful.
We should
definitely support
all other types of
testbeds where NDN can be
applied because that shows
generality of
application for NDN.
It is challenging to
do these testbeds because
each application that we
look at is different.
As an example, in
automotive applications,
they were looking at
creating testbeds
that yes,
are composed of ECUs,
which resemble
the sensor nets
approach, if you like,
constrained devices,
except that may
be the power concern
is not as big.
The automotive environment
wants applications
with networks that are
very light in
terms of weight,
I mean the physical
weight, because they
care about what
goes into the car.
That was an eye-opening
for me when I started
talking to
automotive people,
they said, "Well,
we're moving
into automotive
ethernet then you guys
use wires that have eight
conductors in them,"
and I'm like,
"Yeah, we need them to
do hundreds of
gigabits per second."
They are like, "Wait,
we don't need hundreds
of gigabytes per
second and your wires
are too heavy."
I'm like, "What are
you talking about?
Wires are light."
Then they said,
"Did you know
that the wiring
harness in a car is
the third most heavy
item in a car?"
I'm like, "No, I
have no idea."
We do need to get into
these domains and try
to understand what
the requirements
are and learn more
about these different
application
domains and speak
their language and
perhaps start looking
into these things.
Yeah, that's it.
>> Mathias, you want to?
>> Yeah. I definitely
agree with Christos,
but the other thing
is also that we
really need to
raise awareness.
I'm not really sure
whether the question about
accessibility is
the right question
because as we talked,
these things that
are there and
the infrastructure
that is there is
accessible and can
be used to this use,
but it may be used by
a quiet confined group
of people and users.
This is because
people who we
would like to see
that they are using
NDN are not aware of NDN.
We really should try to
engage other groups,
which means that the
NDN community should be
visible at other events
that are not NDN
or ICN specific.
>> That's a great point.
I think we can go back to
James' comment
about having
a Docker container
or something.
What would be
the specific way
of creating the
statements?
These are not
easy to create.
We can create a
docker container,
but creating a
testbed out of
docker containers,
that's more involved.
[NOISE] With the
accessibility needs,
creating different
testbeds
for different
applications,
that's something we need
to also think about.
>> Sorry, go ahead.
>> You go ahead, sorry.
>> You mean
that a user can
more or less
virtually create
his own test bed
out-of-the-box.
You mean something
like this?
>> Right. Test
bed in a box.
>> [OVERLAPPING]
I'm sorry.
I keep interrupting.
>> I was just going to
say, I think the idea
of something that can
be approached quickly,
easily, and put to use,
one form of that
is, for example,
either a web accessible
or a single click
install environment
with examples
and tutorials,
that would be helpful.
Those of you who play
with things like
Arduinos and
Raspberry ***,
of course there are
companies like SparkFun.
I can't remember the
name of one ecosystem I
saw where you could
buy different blocks
and put them together.
This is partly education,
partly lowering the
boundaries for access.
I think there's a
variety of ways.
But otherwise, test beds,
just as a generic idea,
I think certainly
in aerospace,
I've seen many multimillion
dollar test beds.
I think test beds
by themselves
without maybe something
more in mind,
it depends on
what the purpose
of the test bed is,
but I think that
you could create
essentially
a large number of
very easily
accessible test beds
in the form of
the things I've
mentioned and I
feel that it'll be
a great benefit to that.
>> Beichuan, do you
have any comments?
>> Can I go back to
Alex's [NOISE] situation.
She said she has
all the help
from Indian people,
but he has
really difficult
time to get the system up.
That's not due to
the configuration
setup on Indian,
but due to the
configuration of
underlying network
reachability,
is that right?
Like the firewalls and
other stuff are
blocking somehow
your nose or long
different size
come to each
other in India.
>> There's so
many problems.
I found that when I'm
developing systems,
that's always the
fundamental problem,
especially when I'm
using campus test beds,
is that getting
the person on
the phone to go and change
a firewall rule or fix
something or just reboot
the computer can be
very challenging.
We're trying to build
virtualized test beds
on democratized
Kubernetes systems
and fabric as well,
so that we could
just build it up
ourselves and have
control over it.
>> But this problem,
probably other
people will run
into similar
problem as well,
because when
they deal with
real-world network with
all these restrictions.
Thinking in terms
of accessibility,
what can we do to
solve this problem?
If we proxy
everything over HTTP,
you probably can get
through all the firewall,
but you have all this
downside of doing that.
But that's a real
problem people
can run into.
Even it's not your
Indian's code,
but it's
accessibility problem
in the real world.
>> Yeah, the
real world to me
is a system that's already
existing and being able to
layer Indian applications
on top of that,
because we're trying
to build this repository.
That's our use case
with big datasets.
We need 1-100 petabytes of
storage in this repository
to be able to do anything.
Even on a small
collaboration level,
that's the storage you
need to do genomics.
>> Alex, let me
ask you this,
is the problem setting up
the infrastructure
or is the problem
setting up the
infrastructure
and Indian software?
>> We have a
campus cluster,
two distributed
Kubernetes systems
that we do a
lot to work on,
and the Open Science Grid,
I won't even go there.
But the
infrastructure exists
and we need to be able
to have Indian function
in those existing
infrastructures.
That's got to map with
different
Kubernetes systems.
They're configured
differently.
The ability of
containers to
communicate with
each other is
dictated by the policy
of the person who
built the cluster.
We're lucky enough to
be able to work with
the leadership of some of
the systems in their
experimental systems,
NSF-funded systems to be
able to configure it.
My ultimate goal
is to be able to
have not a
button to press,
but complex
documentation to set up
a data lake in a
commercial Cloud,
then I have the ability
and get funding
for that and keep it up
for as long as I want,
and have control
over that.
I have to pay the bills,
but not trying to
map this to
different campuses,
because no one campus has
enough resources
including my own.
We have a top 300 cluster,
but it's not enough
to do my work.
We're entering a phase in
genomics where we're
going to have,
I don't know, the
private sector,
a million Exascale users
who need to work
at the Exascale
to be able to
do their work.
We're running out
of electrons.
>> What you're saying
implicitly is that
it's important to get
the DevOps
people involved.
>> Yes.
>> Those who manage
the network for
you and they
should start to laugh
and like in the end.
Then if they do this,
and they take care
that basic stuff
is running.
They configure
the firewall
automatically and so on.
Getting DevOps
super involved
seems to be a
crucial point.
>> They're involved,
but I have
to be very careful where I
don't get them involved
too much where
they don't want
to talk to me anymore.
>> No. [LAUGHTER] I
also means in the end
community actually.
Maybe you should
approach DevOps people,
since they already know
in the end concepts and
software and so on,
it's already
prepared if you
want to use it in advance.
>> We're working with
FIA, Tennessee Tech, UCLA.
I would assume
that if there is
a need that we need
from the community
that the Indian people
that I'm working with
will help identify
the DevOps people
or whenever.
We need to get
the job done.
>> I'd like to mention
one thing about the,
I don't know what
the word was,
but to be able
to get people
excited about NDN.
This is, I think,
an overlooked thing a lot.
I see this from a lot
of IT perspectives,
is that there's faculty.
I have 100 student
bioinformatics class.
Their Linux labs
where they go in
VMs and run workflows,
I teach them how
to do that stuff
at the undergraduate
level.
Once I have a
test bed working,
instead of going
and teaching them
some complicated
way to go click and
all these different
things and pull down
a genome from some
weird web service,
where I'll have them go,
take the name and pull
out of the test bed.
What I'll do is
I probably train
300 people a year
in my classes and
workshops and I would
expose 300 people a year
to a system where they
can get the data
from a NDN system.
I would take the time
to explain what NDN is,
the philosophy of it,
and how cool it is,
all that stuff.
Let's say you put
in classes from
the educational
perspective and people
will not know they
weren't supposed to
know what NDN was,
so they've been
taught about
it. They'll think
it's normal.
>> I think we started
with ossification.
How do we end?
The other panel also
talked about it.
How do we put
our interface
existing applications
with NDN.
For some applications,
it's easy,
so they're starting from
scratch, maybe IoT.
Some applications
already have
so much time
invested in it,
they don't want to
get the grid of that.
What's your take on this?
How do we interface
existing applications
with NDN?
What's the best
way of doing this?
>> I can answer what
we're doing with that.
We're going to see,
we have to have
the test bed
that has enough
functionality.
It's got enough
performance to be
able to use it to
pull data from.
But then once we do that,
we already have
existing data
transfer mechanisms,
IP-based things from
the repositories
and we'll just
swap that out
in our workflows.
We have a workflow manager
system that we use
for running our
applications.
We'll just make
that a data stream.
We'll swap it out from
our existing things.
I don't think
it's going to be
hard for us to do that.
But we have to have a
functional test bed.
I use the P word.
I need a
production system.
Most people don't like
that word production.
I need a system
that is production,
meaning that it works
95 percent of the time.
That's my definition of
a production system.
>> Christos, you were
saying something.
>> Yeah. I mean,
it's a really
tough question.
But it's a very
important question
because if we tell people
we don't know
how you can take
your existing application
and run it over NDN,
then they're going
to just walk away.
I'm not sure if we have
done that exercise,
but maybe doing
an exercise
where we take an existing
application and try
to put NDN under
it might be worthwhile
and doing it for a
few applications.
I'm going to go out on
a limb here and say
that if maybe we can find
applications that
were written well
from a software
engineering point
of view and they
are modular,
and maybe we can try to
yank out IP and
put in the end.
I know that this is
oversimplifying things,
but I think we
can be selective.
If we can find
these applications
and do a few
demonstrations,
then we will at least
have proof that
it can be done.
Going from zero
to one or two,
it's a huge step.
Then yes, we can argue
and somebody says,
"Well, I tried to do it
and it was terrible."
Then we can write
our finger and say,
well,
your application wasn't
written properly.
Otherwise, look we did it,
and it was easy,
with an application
that was well-written.
But I think that this is
a really important
exercise
that we should
try to deal with.
The problem is
that I don't
know if I can get an
NSF funding to do
that and I don't
know if I can
graduate a student
doing that.
Hopefully, I
can get a paper
in place here and
if I do that.
But we need to find
the right incentives
and absolutely do this.
I think maybe
it's going to
take a little bit of
time finding the
right application so
that we can put our
NDN, but we shouldn't.
>> I'm going to go to
Matthias and
then Beichuan,
I know Beichuan worked
on this before.
Matthias, I think
for IoT It's easier,
we have the new devices.
Well, I don't know.
[OVERLAPPING].
>> You're right.
It's easy because
we just start
from scratch.
That means I had to
use devices that we're
looking on vary
constraint.
We do not have
much memory,
which means that we cannot
easily integrate
some middle value.
Our applications for
NDN are written from
scratch base for
our NDN ICN.
If you ask whether
we can challenge by
implementing
specific use cases
based on the NDN.
I mean, there have been
ongoing discussions
about push and
pull this stuff,
but this is not
a real challenge
that you can solve.
>> Okay. Thank you.
I'm thinking this is
accessibility problem
because most
of the people,
as James was saying,
coming from IP,
they have already an
application model
or application in mind.
They look at NDN
and say well,
I don't want to
rewrite the whole
application.
Beichuan, I think your
student did a lot
of work in translating
between IP and NDN.
>> Susmit, can I
interrupt for
just a second?
You have a raised
hand in the audience,
someone who wants to
get some real-world
experience.
>> Unfortunately,
I don't see it.
Maybe Kevin you can help.
>> Guys, it's
right here. I just
unmuted my microphone,
I think it's me.
>> Okay. Yeah, sure.
>> Okay. I've got a
lot to get through,
so I'm going to talk
really quickly.
What you really
fundamentally talking about
here is diffusion
of innovation.
Everett Rogers wrote
the book titled
that and the core of it.
This is everything
you've been talking
about and then I can
share what we've
done here.
He says that to
diffuse innovation
into a market,
you have to be accessible,
not complex, compatible,
observable, tolerable.
The core things that
you're talking about,
Christos is exactly right.
You've got to find
a green field site
and a green fields
customer and
that's almost impossible,
except I think we might
be this close to
having got it done.
The other thing
that you keep
saying is the world is IP,
and that is an
incredible battleship
that frankly,
I don't think we're
going to turn.
The approach that
we've taken is to work
with the network
equipment vendors
because they are the
guys [inaudible] here.
We're working
with Nokia and
some very smart guys in
Australia to get this.
Our plan is to build
a joule stack on
a Nokia service
rather in a new open
SO Bluemix service
rather and to
build our stack,
which is half of
which is effectively
a known domain that
we're making or an
information centric
networking protocol.
The other thing we
combine, which I think,
Alex addresses some of
your issues and I talked
about this in one of
the forums before,
it's distributed
storage to get
this mass-scale storage
thing happening.
We're going to build
this into a stack
so that it will sit in
the router and hold
the switch and
you'll be able to do
TCPIP or recognize a
packet and say okay,
well, this is a content
centric packets,
it's a span AI packet
which is our protocol.
I know about this,
I can deal with it.
Then you would obviously
have to build gateways.
What that does is
that then addresses
those two problems.
Then to get it
up and working,
Christos, you're
absolutely right.
You got to find
green fields.
Like I said, well,
I think hopefully
a week or two
away from something
very [OVERLAPPING].
>> I think we lost
you for a moment.
>> Am I back yet? I'm on
a pretty dodgy connection
in Australia. Sorry,
guys. Am I back?
>> I can still hear him.
>> I think we lost Susmit.
>> Yeah I can hear you.
>> Rhett, you can continue
talking. Hopefully,
Susmit will come back.
>> Okay. Where was I?
My train of thought
got interrupted.
Yeah. That's what
we're proposing to do.
The process of
diffusion is you guys
need to find your
early adopter
and guess what? Here I am.
Because I'm some
crazy guy who has
been doing private
research on this,
privately funded research;
chunk of my own money,
chunk of my mates
money for 10 years.
Here's the thing to the
observability pace,
I didn't discover you
guys until we were
doing some work with
Protocol Labs on
IPFS and helping them to
optimize some of the
unfortunate decisions
that they have taken.
In one of their RFPs
for R and D was
this little one
line paper that I
think we've seen and you
may even have been
an author of.
It said, "Hey,
we think this might
be a useful thing to
unify IPFS in the
end," and I'm,
oh yeah, that's a
very useful thing.
I know I've got
to cover a lot of
ground there,
but in essence,
that's the challenge
and I relate to
it completely because like
I said in the comments,
this is what I
do for a living.
But it's about
finding who wants
what you got.
That's the essence of it.
I'm that weird guy,
right now I'm here.
[LAUGHTER] Then we've
got a weird guy,
I'm amazed, that we found,
who has very
serious budget
to spend on this and build
a global network that will
be a content-based
network.
[OVERLAPPING] Try
it, it helps.
Specifically Alex,
before I go,
you might want to get
in touch with an advisor,
a guy called
Jonathan Hall,
who works with
the Protocol
Labs and talk on guys.
He built a
genomic database.
He's the Chief
Medical Officer
currently for
ConsenSys Medical,
spelled with an S-Y-S,
which is Joe
Lupin's company
for commercializing
a theorem.
Joe gets this.
Joe understands.
You have to put it
out in the market.
If you look at ConsenSys,
with a Y-S,
that's the model.
If you look at
Protocol Labs,
they have done a
genius job admittedly.
They had 200 million
bucks that they
raised in a prions
here to play with.
But they have done
this brilliantly.
They've just gone
from basically,
a library of p to p
storage applications to
a complete system that's
now out in the market
and got a market cap.
Well, I think it
changed today,
but billions and
billions of dollars.
That's the prices.
Read Everett Rogers,
find who wants
what you've got.
I'm here. I'm
happy to help.
>> Well, thank you.
>> Thank you for
the comments,
those are very useful.
I have a question for you,
I think you're
the right person
to answer this.
With NDN we often run into
this brick wall
that says, well,
you guys don't have
any standards and we
are an industry,
we need standards.
We need to prove we
only work with
things at work.
How do you have
the conversation
with customers?
We say that, when they
come back to you
and they say, well,
IP checks all
the boxes that
I need and then we scream
and yell we'll look
inside that box
is checked.
It's really not
as great as we
think you are. How did
you deal with this?
>> Very good
question. The answer
is a big part
of what we're
going to do is we're
going to publish
standards,
so we're going
to design it,
we're going to build it,
and then we're going
to publish the APIs
at a couple of levels at
the routing level and at
the AI level because we
use a lot of AI in this,
but you're absolutely
right, you
have to publish
the standards,
you have to first of all,
you got to write them.
This is how every
network technology has
gone out, in fact,
Jonathan wrote
the ITF standard
that now means
you can type IPFS://
into a browser and
it will work now,
I forget what
that's called.
I agree totally,
you've got to write
those standards.
We're going to
do part of that.
You guys obviously you're
the guys to do that.
The big one and this
is one of our areas of
innovation that's
in our patents,
is as everybody has said,
we need a unified naming
and addressing scheme
that everyone can use.
You're absolutely
right there's
a whole bunch
of standards,
so it's got to
be written here.
The classic example with
one of our advisors guy
called Terry Personal,
who was the guy who ran
the project at CSIRO
that invented Wi-Fi.
I know the
stories of fact.
They solve the problem,
they filed a patent and
then they created
attitude at one.
Terry and his guys
started the ADA to D21,
it got adopted
by the IEEE.
The IEEE sent them a
thing and said, Hey,
do you have any
patents and will you,
a, never sell them,
b, give them away or c,
sell them at a reasonable
price and they tick
box C and the
rest is history,
but absolutely,
it's standards are
fundamental thing here.
This is Everett
Rogers observability
and compatibility pot,
and it won't work
unless you do that
but I think it's too much
to try and change
or retrofit, and
I think this is,
some people have a problem
with this of trying to
graph TCPIP concepts into
NDN to make it work
quote-unquote.
I think I'm going to
have to keep them
separate and you're going
to build them
side-by-side.
It's the same thing
with the Internet.
Day 1, 1969,
there was no Internet, day
2 there were four nodes,
and here we are day
whatever it is,
and there's millions of
them and that's
the process.
Fortunately, it's a little
easier, and thank you.
My understanding is
that the NFD daemon is
supported in Ubuntu
and that's like it's
already on 400 million
servers. Job done.
Just sighted people
plugging into that guys.
That's what we're doing,
so there are ways to
do this that's
simplified for people,
and this is the
fundamental thing.
I always quote Paul Baron.
Who invented
packet switching
and he went to see
AT&T in the 60s and
explained it to them,
and the Chief Engineer
of AT&T turns to
his guys and rolls
his eyes to inspect
to Paul Brandon and says,
son let me tell you
how telephone work,
it's a one person at
a time conversation
to convert people,
but you've got to try
and find that leverage.
Crazy guys like me and
the guys that we've
found that just
get you there,
and I had this
conversation with
supposedly the head of
finding new
technology at Akamai.
Turns out he's the
guy who's in charge
of killing new technology
that might be a threat,
and he said to me,
he obviously is a
source of threat,
and he said, how are you
going to get it out there?
At the time I said,
given the Internet story
and he said, Yeah,
but back then Akamai
didn't exist,
and then quite had
cut back to him and
all the rest of it,
innovator's dilemma etc,
but it turns out
Akamai's doing our
marketing for us.
Does massive
failures recently,
thesis is that the
Internet is too
complex for human
beings to manage.
We are going to fix that,
and the only way to fix
that is with some MLI.
I'm sorry, I'm
writing because
I'm trying to summarize
10 years of
experience in pioneer
in a shorter space
of time as I can.
>> Maybe that will be
a future tunnel system
it up with we
are after all,
being hosted at Nest.
Maybe that could be
a good topic
for the future.
>> Yes, absolutely, and
thanks for the comments,
and I think let's
continue the
conversation even
after the panel and
the conversation.
Happy to reach out.
I don't know if we're out
of time or we have
10 more minutes,
I'd like to have 10 more
minutes if we have it,
but I think the
last question
I had was we started with.
>> Excuse me, you
have 15 more minutes.
>> Greta. Thank
you. We started
with the community meeting
with the goal of
creating a wish list.
In terms of accessibility,
what would be
your wish list?
That goes to the panelist
and then also
the audience.
The panelist first.
>> My wish list is
to have DevOps,
if NDN engineers
working directly
with me on my project and
my wishes had
been granted.
>> James, you mentioned
a docker easy to
use applications.
Is there anything else?
>> Well, as I said,
just creative ways to
increase exposure.
I think one of
the problems
with the half-century
existence
of Internet and
precursor technologies
is that everyone,
practically
everyone has grown
up in the age of networks.
There already is a
lot of conditioning,
specifically people
thinking they
understand how
networks work,
and like I said this
contributes to that
ossification problem,
and so you have to
counter that and then I
think any of the means
that we've talked about,
again, web accessible,
single click Install,
very simple.
Do It Yourself, Kits,
I think are things
like mosquito, MQTT,
things that there are
hobbyists at
play with those.
I don't hear of hobbyists
playing within NDN.
I think one
important problem
that I was not able to
crack so far was you
need in aerospace,
this is very important
maybe and other sectors,
you don't switch to
something because it's
beautiful or elegant.
You switch to something
because it has
a concrete proven benefit,
and so one of the things I
wanted to do and I
was not able to,
or had not so far been
able to do was to
create a benchmark suite.
Well, so this would be
possibly a testbed,
but a simulation
where we show,
I don't know, I'll
pick an example.
Latency or energy where
we demonstrate
concrete benefits.
If I use an NDN
implementation,
I gain x over an
IP implementation,
and I haven't heard
anyone talk about
why from
a measurable performance
standpoint NDN,
I think we have
ideas about how
content based networks
can outperform,
but that is how you sell
things in
certainly the
Department of Defense.
That example I talked
about in the beginning,
the mill standard 1553
was adopted in
the F-15 program.
Before that, believe
it or not, was analog.
It was analog,
lots of wiring,
and the way that they
were able to sell 1553,
which of course
now I'm saying I
wish they would
get rid of because
it's such an old
technolog the way
they were able to sell it
was they demonstraY.
Ted white savings.
We're talking
hundreds of pounds,
and I think it was
mentioned earlier
that wiring harnesses are
a significant element of
weight in systems
aerospace system.
I know if one,
I think GPS,
I think it's rumored
that I want to
say 400 pounds of
wiring harness and or
kilograms and it's
like $50,000 a kilogram
to launch something.
There was an incentive.
When they were
able to say, Look,
I can save you a lot of
weight on the
F15 aircraft.
If you switch
to the standard
that put it over whatever
the tipping point,
and at that point,
since the F-15 did it,
then the F-16 copied it
and many other
systems copied it.
That incentive
structure helps
another question
about accessibility,
but I think that
part of this is,
what is the idea?
The idea is elegant,
but why elegance that
in itself is not enough.
What is it that I
need to push us over
the top? I'll stop there.
>> Now, I think
that's a great point.
It's the economy
of things.
I think we need to have
a panel on that as well.
>> I just wanted
to throw out
something quickly.
Thinking into
what resources
made research
on the internet
useful and valuable,
one of them that I
don't think we've
covered so far
is datasets.
There were a lot of
datasets that were
collected over
the internet that drove
a lot of research,
the study of TCP
congestion control
and lots of other things,
and I don't think we
have NDN datasets.
We don't have many
applications,
but we do have some.
We have climate,
we have genomics.
Would it be
useful if people
who run these
applications,
if we collected some
data sets and made
those available
to the community,
may have to be a little
different because
obviously there's
caching and this
retrieval from
multiple locations
and so forth?
But I wonder if
the availability
of datasets something that
a graduate student can
delay the hands-on in
and look at India and
studied and even some
an animation tool.
I wonder if those
things would
help propagate in the
end a little more?
>> When we start
doing a lot of
simulations on fabric,
we could generate
that data
in our genomics
experiments,
I presume, if I understand
what data you're
talking about.
>> Yeah. I have a couple
of comments on that,
but let me see if there
are any questions or
comments from the audience
and then we'll
come back to that.
If you have any questions
from the audience,
feel free to
speak up, please.
It doesn't look like
there are any questions.
But this is also
going back to
the testware
discussion and
the docker discussion.
Is it enough to have
just a dataset or
the testware or
the docker or
should we try to create
an example use cases
where the genomic
students can go
play with the data
and the software
and the workflow?
The aerospace researchers
can go play with
that particular set
of containers and
so should we have
distributed systems
that allows
you to play with NDN,
with actual data sets?
>> Nothing beats having
the applications
and play with the
applications themselves.
But I was thinking
if there was
a dataset where it
demonstrated the
fact that you set
an interest and then it
takes so much time
to get it back,
and then you send
somebody else who has
an interest and they
get it from a cache or
showing things
like failover,
some robustness
and so forth,
I think those are simple
things that we could
do that could demonstrate
some of the
aspects of NDN,
not everything, of
course, but some of them.
>> Christos,
by dataset you
also include the traffic.
>> Exactly. Yes,
I do want to see
that net flow traces
that demonstrate
how NDN works.
>> I'm saying
proof of evidence.
Here it is we see,
here's the real traffic,
it looks better.
>> When we get started,
we'll come back and
talk to you,
Christos, about that.
We'll generate
that for fabric,
but also for the
distributed Kubernetes
specific research
platform.
It's actually across
the country now and we'll
capture that
networking data
and I'll make sure
we capture the
right stuff.
We're capturing resource
data just not at
that granularity at
the network level.
We're already
doing that for
AI algorithms to predict
our usage patterns in
the future so that we
can ask estimator
in the Cloud.
>> I think we
are coming to
the end of the time.
There's an eco somewhere.
I still want to see
once more if there are
any questions or comments
from the audience.
>> Final very quick
comment, Susmit.
When we talked about
standards, the other thing
that I would
really like to
see some work is,
what about putting
NDN in hardware?
Are we not ready
yet or are there
some basic simple
functionalities that we can
define that can actually
get NDN in silicon?
If we're not
ready yet, great,
but I think having that
conversation will
be interesting.
>> I raised my hand,
I guess it's hard to
see. Can people hear me?
>> Yes.
>> I was just typing
in my comments.
Personally, I
believe the price,
the selling points for
NDN wouldn't be a
unique functionality.
Being an old person,
being through the
old days of how
IP went over the world,
performance wasn't
IPs strong points
at the very beginning.
I remember that my
former advisor,
David Clarke,
had to write papers
explaining to
the world why TCP wasn't
intrinsically slow,
rather just there is
an early days of
implementation.
Nobody is talking about
TCP being too slow now,
but in the early days,
there's lots of
criticism about
IPs, TCP/IPs poor
performance.
I think that new things
are not polished
and it's hard to
beat the legacies
which has been
debolished over the
package of deployment.
That is just my
little thoughts on
the competing and
performance front
based on the past
observation. Thanks.
>> Susmit, we
cannot hear you.
>> Susmit, you're muted.
>> He's unmuted but
just not talking.
>> Looks like
we lost Susmit.
>> Release the other.
>> It's 2:15,
so I guess its all time
to end the law, I guess.
On behalf of Susmit,
thank you-all
the panelists
and the agenda has
scheduled for a 15 minutes
break starting now.
Thank you very much.
>> Thank you, Clemson.