>> Hey, welcome
back everyone
to session number 6,
which would be chaired
by Christos Papadopoulos.
Christos is known to
most of you and was
just introduced to in
panel that just ended.
Christos you can
go ahead, please.
>> Thank you Lotfi no
need to introduce me.
For the for the
sake of time,
but I think I'm
going to jump
directly into
introductions.
I think we have
about a 100 minutes
and five presentations.
About 20 minutes
per presentation.
To the presenters,
I'll try to
turn on my video
when we're getting
close to the end
of your time
so you can see me and
then I'll give you
a verbal cue also.
The first presenter
is Kathleen Nichols,
who is the CTO of Pollere.
She received a PhD
in electrical
engineering from
UC Berkeley and she
says she claims
a long time ago.
Her current interests
are in using
NDM to solve edge
network problems,
which has led to
the development of
the open source
Delta Centric
tool kit or DCT.
Although she retains
a soft spot for
network measurement.
Kathy, please go ahead.
>> Okay. I guess I need to
start sharing my screen.
[NOISE] Let's try this
out and it worked,
but there's key note.
Are you seeing it?
>> Yes. This is
good thank you.
>> Okay. I just
wanted to say that
I was doing this in
the general spirit of
a community meeting
and talking
about this is some
things that we
should be thinking
out taking
a look at and I'm
definitely not an expert
in industrial
applications,
like many of the people
in the panel
earlier today,
which was really
just a great animal.
I wanted to make
sure I got that
out of the way.
[inaudible] I
wanted to say,
a couple of things
that I think
are really important
to keep in mind.
I feel like it's
time for NDN to
show its value by solving
some hard problems.
I really think we have to
show and not tell and I
don't think I'm alone
in that based on
some things that were
said earlier today.
In this particular area,
in addition to
the things we
heard about in the
panel earlier,
our NIST colleagues are
also able to point us
at the value that
has been solving
hard problems,
try and get rid of
all those chunks.
You see, I can't
tell exactly what
I'm sharing.
[LAUGHTER] I think
that we should
look at the operational
technologies because it
has issues that
conventional networking
doesn't address.
I also think that
this requires
a somewhat different
approach from
the NDN-based Future
Internet work.
It just how NDN
got started.
We need to think a
little bit about that.
What is it that we need
for these types
of applications?
I'm using these
particular definitions.
The one for operational
technology is
coming from this
website and
also Wikipedia has
some further calls
it like this,
so-called IT in the
non carpeted areas.
I also want to use
the term conventional
networking
because a lot
of times people
talk about like
NDN versus IP.
But NDN does run over
IP and that seems,
with few
exceptions, that's
mostly the way
we're using it.
It's certainly the way
that I've been using it.
But yet NDN is not
conventional networking.
I'm thinking of it
as NDN versus CN.
Finally, things,
I'm going to use
RFC8520 definition of a
group of objects that
are specifically
not intended to be
used for general purpose
computing tasks.
That here.
[LAUGHTER] The OT networks
have increasingly
become wireless and
this makes it really
difficult for it to use
its traditional
security approaches,
which were things
like firewalls and
air gaps and the idea,
if you had this a wire
where there was
only one thing at
the end of the wire
that authentication
becomes easier.
The area of Zero Trust
Architectures with
their never trust and
always verify approach.
They tried to address
this by using
TCP and TLS encryption.
But in CN these
the ad hoc conversational
communications
are going to make
it really hard
to establish trust
relationships.
Unlike IT networks,
OT networks are
restricting the roles in
communications and
intent for their things.
That makes it really
different where in IT,
we want more of
the ability to
say many things
to many places.
In RFC 8520 notes
that there's just
a small number of
communications patterns
that come out of
those restricted
roles and intentions,
which important
to think of too.
It says, while these
patterns can be
expressed as
Manufacturer Usage
Descriptions,
and we have
similar concepts
in Matter and ZigBee and
the OneData Model
descriptions
we're really
describing things
in a very constrained
way and the
ways they can interact
is constraint.
We're trying to use that
and go one further
than that.
But what they do with MUD
is they can only enforce
those patterns using
conventional
network through
this things like
externally applied
Access Control Lists.
There's NIST publication
that discusses
applications of
MUD to small business and
home IoT, which
is interesting.
This picture is
from RFC 8520,
and I've inserted in it,
this which is in the
NIST publication,
the idea that
you could have
the threat
signaling server.
But if you look at this,
everything that
has to do with
security is external
to the things.
This is a great
way to make use of
existing things in
conventional networking.
But then when we go
to the use of DTLS,
which is required by
architectures
like the matter.
Now suddenly
we're blinding
deep packet inspection.
They are giving you
an either or choice.
But in NDN,
we can enforce those
communication patterns
on every thing,
and we don't
have to rely on
external servers the
routers and we can
also take advantage of
robust multicasts
properties that
we could get by using
NDN primitives.
Because of this,
I'm saying, okay,
the VerSec
architecture that
fans started talking about
in 2019 provides a
better way to secure OT.
The key elements are,
you have this trust
schema that's
integral to
transport and also
you're using a sync
protocol to distribute
your signing
certificates in
your group keys as
well as your data.
Everything is all being
distributed through
your sync protocol.
A really important aspect
of the trust schema for
VerSec is that it's a
declarative approach
to specifying things.
You can get these
arbitrarily
fine-grain rules
and those are used to
check the soundness
to construct valid
data names and to
enforce the validity of
the data that you receive.
When I say arbitrarily
fine-grained,
that also means
you don't have to
be very fine-grained
at all.
I've have an example
on the website
that is listed
below of really just
securing things
by signing,
which is a little
bit closer
to what you would
get with conventional
networking.
But it's still
a little bit harder
security teams
and what they can provide.
Then another
aspect of this
is that any
communicating entities
have to publish
the public search
that they're
signing chain before
they can communicate.
We don't have any
issues with you get
something and then go
out and try to get keys,
which opens you up to
performance issues,
denial of service,
all bad things.
The trust schema,
along with
its particular
root of trust,
the trust thinker,
it defines a
trust zone and
they think someone
mentioned that earlier.
Our reference
implementation along
with a Pub/Sub API,
which is vaguely
inspired by
MQTT is available on
GitHub at this site.
With using VerSec,
data movement is always
governed by the
trust schema.
This is a slightly
different concept
and I'm going to use
this example which
is home IoT because
it's always easy to
wrap your head around.
If you look at
the trust schema,
this is how we're
defining the search.
This is a device which
is something that
any particular
device would have to
have and it's signed
by the netCert.
Within this, we've
got a Switch Cert,
which is a device
Cert with its role
set the switch.
We've also got
a Light Cert
and it has its
role set to light.
The way that we make
things correspond
to each other is we
have correspondences
between
these components
that are located
in the trust
schema rule for
the Cert as well as
a trust scheme
of publication.
If we take a look
at some switch
and one of the search
that we've given it,
what's in that
location field,
It's quitting
in coffee bar.
Now, that's saying
that this is
a switch for the light
over the coffee bar.
Now, if it makes
a publication and
it's publishing a sub
command to a light,
and it says coffee bar.
It's telling it to turn
on, act that light.
It's able to use the
trust schema to say,
is this signed by
something that has
coffee bar
corresponding to look,
and I have coffee bar,
I'm the coffee bar
light and it turns on.
This is a really
different way of
thinking about the
movement and use of data.
I guess I should say,
so here's the
trust schema.
That's written
ahead of time.
Then the switches
get put into
devices by
the enrollment tools
that you're using.
Then this is what's
happening at runtime.
I think something that
Alex had mentioned I
guess yesterday is,
maybe we could
have approaches or
architectures
where we take
the trust
architecture first.
I just want to say this
is a step in
that direction.
We have to think
about ways of
making the writing of
this trust schemas
friendlier,
because I think
this is a way
that a lot of people think
about their problems in OT
is how do I want to
design the trust.
I want to say a
little bit more
about how this can
become a little
bit more flexible
because we can
then turn around
and say, "Well,
I'm also going to
enroll this
particular switch,
it's switch number 42
with a cert that
has counter in it,
which now says, oh,
I can now issue
commands that have
counter in it."
If it does that,
counter doesn't have to be
one particular light like
the one that's over
the coffee bar,
it can be the counter
that's all sprinkled
throughout the kitchen.
This could be talking to
several different
lights that say,
I'm listening for counter.
Then it can always
check and say was
this publication issued by
someone who has
that attribute
in their certs.
Just some features
of the approach I
want to reiterate is
that then a thing signing
id restricts what
I can legally say.
Now everything that's
in the trust zone
knows what is and
what is not legal.
Here we're
deliberately not
liberal in
what's accepted.
That was saying we're
moving away from
that Internet model,
here are the IT model.
A Thing can also
listen for and accept
communications
from multiple name
prefixed data and it's
trust schema-enabled
transport
ensures that those are
valid before it even
passes it to the
application.
When Things come in,
if it's not valid,
you toss it away early.
We always try to toss
Things as early
as possible.
A light in a
building system can
listen for data that's
for its specific location.
If it's what he said,
their coffee bar
or it's room,
the floor that it's
on or all lights
you could turn
them all on at
once or turn them all off.
That same light
is only able to
report its status and they
can't cause any actions.
I think probably
many of you are
aware of this
nice work that
checkpoint did
showing compromising
a Philips light
bulb and then being
able to take over
an entire network,
so we really need to
limit those devices.
They're not as dumb
as we think they are.
They're running
processors.
If we let people take them
over and we let them
issue any command because
they're inside
of our network,
then we're dead.
If we use trust
schema-based enrollment,
then the
communications are
now enforced at
every single Thing
or every entity
and we don't need
those external
servers and routers.
That gets rid of having
this single
point of attack,
where if you think back to
the picture I
showed earlier,
if you were
trying to attack
the system, you
would say, "Oh,
look at these servers,
here's the place it
says attack me here".
Finally, I want
to note that
now the communications can
exploit that
broadcast nature
of having wireless,
but without
compromising security
because every
single entity
has the trust scrolls
and has built-in
enforcement.
I want to move on
thinking more about,
so data movement is
governed by the
trust schema.
I want to think a
little bit more about,
well, how do we
work with that?
Everything that's on the
same network segment
might not be in the
same trust zone.
If you look over
on this side,
maybe this laptop isn't
a member of the
trust zone,
but it doesn't
really matter
because it can't publish
anything the green stuff
is going to listen to,
it doesn't have the
right identity.
The other problem is that
we might want to
have entities
that are in the same
trust zone that
aren't the same
network segment.
Currently in the DCT stuff
that cuts out
in the GitHub,
we only have one
trust zone, per Face.
But we're working on
relay applications
that extend the trust
zone between the Faces.
That would be the
idea here is that
this relay app is
talking through
the modem and
a relay app on
the other side is
passing things on.
Now, those relay
applications could filter
the publications
that go through them
or they can just
pass them through.
But you might envision
a default deny because
you want to be
really careful
about what goes
across the
physical boundary.
It's not a trust,
it doesn't go across
a trust boundary.
Since signing
identities are
associated with
the trust zone,
those would be
used everywhere.
But the way we're
setting this up is that
our data encryption
keys are face specific,
so if data is encrypted
everything on this side
uses one group key,
use a different key across
here and yet
another one here.
This is something
that it's
the current area
of work for me.
Now here's some
half-baked ideas,
oops I've got to
wrap up here.
The reason I put the
half-baked ideas out
is to try to
inspire people to
realize that
there's a lot of
cool things to work on
here and we need to
solve these problems in
order to move forward
and present
solutions for OT.
Here's some of
the opportunities
I've thought about.
Crystal, should I
just stop here or
should I run through
these quickly?
>> We are at the
one-minute mark.
Please wrap up.
>> Okay. Here's some
opportunities I
can think of that if
we can solve the
hard problems in
a wide range of
special-purpose applications,
we might be able
to make NDN
immediately relevant
commercially for some
sense of relevancy.
Then if we're applying
this NDN architecture
to an OT problem,
it should lead to creating
a new data-centric
innovations and
new understandings of
non-endpoint-centric
communications.
Some things with the
trust schema is,
maybe we get a
form-based trust schemas
and they would
be specific to
particular classes
of problem,
or maybe we would have
MUD-to-trust
schema translator,
but there's just
various things
that could be
worked on there.
NDN-specific
approaches to updating
identities and
trust schemas
that maybe make use of
TPM or other hardware
security modules.
I think the work
that we saw earlier
today of bootstrapping
over the network,
that's, one beginning
in this area.
There's the other idea of
extending the
communication model
APIs that DCT has
for other types
of transit carts.
Everything we've put
out as open source.
If you don't like some,
take what you want and
put your own stuff in.
Also, maybe we won't
listen or subscribe
only applications
that create
audit trails for
trust zones,
recording the names and
the signers time a day,
those kinds of things.
Work on hierarchical
and federated trust zones.
I had to sit through.
What about
security audits?
Do we have people who
could do that for us and
understand how do we
systematize the
security audits
that we want to do here?
Then the use of
identifiers and identities
other than just using
the ones that you give
out in a trust zone,
could we do something
with self sovereign
identity?
Also, we just wanted to
exploit NDN
characteristics to
make communications
that are both robust to
failure and robust
to cyber threats.
I think there's lots more.
That's my presentation.
I'm done.
>> Thank you.
Appreciate it.
Just one question
on select if you wanted
to [OVERLAPPING].
>> No worries,
I'm here to help.
>> Very good.
>> Varun, please
go ahead and share
screen so we can start
seeing your slides.
Brief introduction
to Varun.
Just giving you a very
brief introduction.
He is a computer science
graduate student at
UCLA working with Alicia.
His research
interests are in
systems in data-centric
networking.
He is currently working on
the NDN sync protocol.
Varun, go ahead,
take your way.
>> Thank you Christos.
Can you see my
slides and hear me?
>> Yes, you go good.
>> Cool.
I'm going to be
talking about building
high-level
transports over NDN
in particular over sync.
The first thing we
want to identify
before building
anything is that,
what do the
applications want?
The way we can do
this is by looking
at what do the
applications have already.
The first thing is
that they have IP,
but none of the applications
use IP directly.
It should be easy to
use because dealing
with individual data
packets is hard.
The apps produce objects
of an arbitrary sizes
and any number of them.
You can just use IP
directly for this.
That's why we have TCP
as the transport in IP.
Then we also need
built-in security.
Apps can't do
encryption and
signing themselves.
You have TLS
that works with
TCP/IP to do
security for you,
and the application
will just give
a certificate or
a key to TLS.
Third, is that
we also need to
have communication
between multiple parties.
TCP/IP is just
point-to-point.
We do have solutions
like MQTT that support
secure transport
for applications
of between
multiple parties.
It's like
basically pops up.
Then applications
also want
all this to be
decentralized.
Well, that is the
place where you don't
really have a very
concrete solution in IP,
there are some solutions,
but they end up doing
some N cross N
communication
because of the
node-centric nature of IP.
Trying to identify
the solution,
we think that
decentralized
Pub/Sub running over
NDN is a potential
solution
that solves all
these problems.
By creating such a system,
we will be supporting
a popular design
pattern that has
been very widely
deployed successfully
in industry.
It is multiplied
party and pops up
itself while it is mostly
centralized in IP,
there's nothing
about pops of itself
that cannot be
decentralized.
We can decentralize
pops up.
The question is,
how do we support
Pub/Sub over NDN?
To do that, we
first look at
the protocols
that we have.
The closest that we
come to is sync.
The sync provides
namespace
synchronization in IP.
Basically, it informs
the consumers
of what new data is
available for fetching.
It's a transport of NDN.
There are existing
sync protocols.
I've listed them
here and we build
our implementation on
the synchronization
protocol.
Just the switches take
rehearsing because it
is resilient and
efficient in its job.
Let's identify first
that what does sync
provide us and what is
it missing from what
applications want?
Sync synchronizes
namespace
for individual packets,
but developers need
higher level APIs.
That's the one that
I mentioned earlier.
If you use sync directly,
you still need
to deal with
interest data
exchanges and
you still need to
sign every packet.
Sync will just
inform the consumers
about a certain packet
being available.
It doesn't do anything
more than that.
We still need to fill
this gap between
what is needed and what
does sync provide,
but before we do that,
let's just take a
look at sync itself.
That is our
lowermost layer,
that is a transport
itself, which is sync.
We take a look at
State Vector Sync.
State Vector Sync encodes
the entire state in
a single sync interest.
What is the state?
The state is
just a list of
tuples which are producer
and sequence number pairs.
For each entity in
this sync group,
we'll keep a
sequence number.
They will put their
sequence number and
their producer prefix
into the state vector.
Now, this entire
state vector will be
put into a single
sync interest.
The sync interest
is multicast to
everyone else in
the sync group.
This way, if anyone
updates their
sequence number,
which is my update,
they increase their
sequence number,
then they just send
out a sync interests
and everyone else
will know about it.
When next time,
if someone misses
the sync interest
when anyone
else sends the
sync interest,
then they will also know
its state changes
both of them.
This way, state of records
sync interest is
very resilient to
losses because of its
encoding the
entire state in
single sync interest
and its use of
sequence numbers as
the resilient
transport identifier,
but if you miss
something in between,
you can just know it
later because you
know that you are
missing some
sequence numbers.
Sync interest is a
very simple design.
One point is that
sync interest does
not follow a set of
replies to the multicast
sync interests.
This avoids the
negative impact
of having potentially
multiple replies.
Sync Interest serves as
just a modification to
everyone else
in sync group
about new data
that is available,
there is no reply to
the sync interest,
but let's instead
look at what
the application
actually publishes.
We can say that
the application
will publish a
name data BLOB.
The naming of
the blob will
be done by the
application.
We don't worry about that.
It's application
define semantics.
The applications
don't want
to know about the
network layer.
They don't care about
the MTU limitations,
or they don't want to
manipulate interests
data directly.
This blob can
be of any size.
As I said earlier,
sync will only
provide a namespace
synchronization
for individual packets.
It will not do any kind of
segmentation on its own.
We need this
segmentation in
one layer above
sync where we
can publish objects
of any size on sync
and then this object
will become available
to everyone else.
The second problem,
if you notice,
is that because of
the use of sequence
numbers in sync,
you cannot have
the semantic name
of the application
to fetch
the data and documents
as well as particular.
Sync uses
sequence numbers,
so you just know the
producers prefix
and the sequence number
corresponding to
that producer.
You have no idea about
the semantic name of
the application
object when you get
the update from SBS.
That becomes
our next step.
How do we do data
delivery over sync?
This is our approach
to this problem,
that we first get
the name and the blob
from the application.
It's a name that
is defined by
the application and
it's defined here.
It's the topic or
something and the blob
is just a binary
data of any size.
Then the transport library
that is the data
delivery layer
will chop this blob up
into smaller pieces
such that when it
creates the final
data packet,
it will still fit
in the network MTU.
These are these B0-Bn
and these are
parts of the blob.
Then we put each
of these blobs
into NDN data packet and
this data packet
will be named using
the application
semantic name
and a segment number.
This encapsulated data
packet as mentioned
here is semantically
a complete NDN data
packet that you can fetch.
It is named using the NDN
conventions and you can
fetch this packet directly
to get the application
data blob.
But we still have the
problem that Sync only
informs others about
the sequence numbers.
We put this data
packet inside
another data
packet that is
named using the
sequence number.
We put the
producers prefix
and the sequence number in
the name of this
outer data packet.
As soon as when
the producer produces
this data packet,
they inform everyone else
about the new
sequence number,
and using just
the information
inside the sink
interests in SVS,
they can actually fix
this data packet.
When they fetch all of
these data packets,
they can then
encapsulate them and
put the blobs together and
return it to the consumer.
By doing this,
what we achieved
was that we got
this application
data unit of
arbitrary size to
everyone else in
the Sync group.
We fill that
requirement gap
partially and now the
consumers can also
fetch the data and
use the contents
of the data which
is of any size.
But now there is one
more problem that
we can identify
here is that
the consumer does not
know what it is fetching
before actually fetching
it because of again,
the use of
sequence number,
the application
name is not
exposed to the consumer.
The consumer will know
only after fetching
it what data is
and whether they
actually need it.
We need a mechanism to
inform the
consumers of what
is published so that
they can fetch it
only if they needed.
That brings us up to
the layer of Pub/Sub
where we want to
fetch only what the
application needs.
Doing Pub/Sub over SVS
we take this approach.
A fundamental
problem is that
the subscriber of
Pub/Sub needs to know
the data name before
fetching the object using
the sequence number and
SVS provides only
the sequence number.
To do this, we do
what we do
elsewhere in NDN.
We ask for the data name.
For this, we sent out
a mapping interest,
we simply ask the
producer that what is
the application data
name corresponding to
this producer and
the sequence number.
Then you send
the mapping interest and
the producer will just
reply with the
application name
for that particular
sequence number.
Then the subscriber can
just look up the list
of subscriptions
and if they
are subscribed
to that object,
then they can
just fetch it
using the data interests.
We can optimize
this step by
just putting the
application data name
onto the Sync
interest itself.
Every time you publish
something new,
you send out an
event-driven
Sync interest in SVS.
We just put the
application data name
into the Sync interest.
This way you can skip
this mapping interest and
data retrieval if you
got the first
Sync interest.
If you did not get
the Sync interest,
then of course
you still need
to fetch the name
before deciding whether to
fetch the data object.
Now by doing this,
what we already have
is fetching data of
arbitrary sizes but now
only the consumers who
need that data will
actually fetch it.
Now we are left
with one problem
that we didn't talk
about security
in all of this.
The application still
needs to sign into
our packets and
so where does
this really go
in all of this?
That's our last layer
which is security.
The question is how
do we do security?
The first thing is who
signs the data packets?
The answer to this
is that that was
the first thing that
applications do
not sign individual
data packets.
The transport or some
security framework
should sign every
data packet.
The second question is,
how do we sign
this packet?
Well, someone has
to give the keys
and that has to be
the application
and it might also be
the security framework
that gets keys.
For example, if you have
encryption on the
data packets,
then you have to have
a security framework
that we'll distribute this
group keys to everyone
and then that will
give the key to
the transport
and that'll be
used to encrypt and
sign the data packets.
The next two
questions, which
I will go into more detail
are what to sign and
how often to sign.
The first question is that
what to sign
and we want to
minimize the sign-in
cost as we do this.
The first observation
is that we have to sign
the application
data blob because
everything has to be
signed whether it's in
transit or it's at rest.
When you put
the data packet
inside another
data packet,
we have to sign the
inner data packet.
That means that
the encapsulated
data packet can be signed.
We can reduce this
cost by aggregating
the inner data
packet which is
what I'll talk about next.
But what about the
outer data packet?
We can assign
each data packet
that we put on the network
using asymmetric
key signatures.
The problem with
this approach is
that producing this
signature creates
a lot of overhead and if
the application
is producing
a large number of objects,
then this is going to
add to the overhead a lot.
The one way to
reduce this overhead
is to use symmetric
key signatures.
For this, we need
a group key
distribution mechanism
that is somewhere in
the security framework.
One advantage that
we get by doing this
is that we can
also encrypt
the outer data packet.
If we encrypt the
outer data packet then
no one can read the name
of the inner data packet.
It provides the
application with
name privacy for the
application data name.
The next thing is that we
can reduce the
sign-in cost further
by aggregating the
application data into one.
The simple idea here is
that the application
might produce
multiple data objects of
small sizes and
we cut this into
one before publishing
a single page
application data object.
This will reduce
the signing
overhead because
now you don't have
to sign each of
these smaller packets
individually.
Here's an example that
if you have a
temperature sensor
which generates
temperature readings
every 15 minutes,
then you can just club
them 30 minutes at
a time and put them into
a single application
data object,
and then publish
this object.
You need to sign
them only once now.
The advantage of doing
this is obvious,
you reduce the
signing overhead,
you can have
network throughput
because you have
lower channel access for
wireless just lower
packet count.
The problem with this
approach is that
semantic naming
may be difficult.
In this case, naming
this outer bigger
aggregated object
was easy but it might
not always be so.
An example of
this is here that
you have temperature
data and
you have humidity data
so now you cannot
aggregate all these into
one single object and
name it which makes
sense as well.
Here's a secondary
approach
that we can also do
to reduce the sign-in cost
is that of a
signature manifest.
We take individual
data packets,
we publish them
immediately,
and then instead of
signing each data packet,
we periodically publish
a signature for
all of these.
For doing this we take
the names of each
of these data
packets that are
already published
and then we take
the dieses which
might be part of
the name and we
put them all into
one data packet and we
give this data packet
a name that identifies
that this is the signature
for these data packets
which is just
represented over here.
Then we assign
this data packet.
As soon as you get
this big data packet,
the signature
manifest, then you can
verify all of the
previous data packets.
By doing this, we
retain semantic
naming for each
of the individual
data packets
that we published earlier.
All of these smaller
packets will also
be published
earlier and
then we publish
the signature manifest to
verify all of these.
There are two
more questions.
What do we do with
this aggregation?
The answer is that
the Pub/Sub library
or the transport
library must do this.
Again, we don't
want to leave this
to the application
to actually do
this because you need to
know other network
layer stuff to do this.
But whether we
want to do this,
this should be defined
by the application.
It's behaviorally
defined by
the application than in
the Pub/Sub library.
There is a
downside to doing
this which is
that it would add
delay because
you cannot now
fetch and
verify the data in
real-time anymore.
If you're using
signature manifest,
then you still need to get
the manifest to actually
verify the data and
it's the same
for aggregating
the data into one
packet that you still
need to wait before
the producer
actually sends
out the big data packet.
>> Three minutes left.
>> Thank you. There are
two use cases where we
can demonstrate
this aggregation.
The first is that we have
generation plant
status updates
where we have
regularly scheduled
readings and we
need to get this
to the consumers
as fast as
possible with
minimal latency.
The second is that we
have nuclear power
plant sensors.
There are a lot of
these and we just
need to get
updates from these
at every hour and we have
very limited wireless
data bandwidth
and capacity.
It's obvious that
for the first case,
we cannot do
aggregation because
we cannot tolerate
that delay
that it brings,
and for the second case,
the aggregation will
bring about a lot of
benefits because
we are going
to reduce the
channel access and
we have to better
utilize our
network capacity.
At the end of all of this,
what we have is we
built a system in
which we have
the application
producing data units of
arbitrary size
and these are
signed and it can also
be encrypted by either the
security framework
or the transport
using the keys provided by
the application or
the security framework
or the transport.
Then these are
delivered by
the transport only
to the consumers
that actually
need this data
regardless of the
size or the number of
data units and
this is done
efficiently regardless
of what they are.
The entire process
is summarized in
this slide which I
don't really want to
cover because it's
a bit complicated.
The future directions
for this work is
that we want to
investigate how
do we scale SVS because we
put the entire
dataset into
one Sync interest
which is obviously not
going to work if you
have a lot of producers.
This needs working that we
can send out
partial state
vectors or something
like that and
we also want to
investigate data
aggregation further.
Those are our ongoing
and future directions.
I guess that's it for
our presentation.
Thank you.
>> Thank you. I
really appreciate it.
Go ahead and stop sharing
and there's some
discussion on slack.
Well, if you want to join,
I think Lisa is
already working on it.
The next
presentation will be
by Proyash who is
a PhD student at
Florida International
University working
with Alex Afanasyev and
his research interests
include the security of
computer networks
and future internet
architectures,
specifically at the end
and he's also
working on projects
that involve using NDN in
vehicular environments.
Go ahead Proyash.
>> You're actually
muted. Proyash,
can you guys hear
me? You're muted.
>> Yeah.
>> Can you hear me now?
>> I can hear you now,
but we lost your screen.
>> Can you see
the screen now?
>> Yes, you're good
to go. Thank you.
>> Thank you Christos for
the introduction
and hello everyone.
I am Proyash Podder
and I will be
presenting our work sV2Pc.
Where we will try to
scale the communication
in vehicle or environment.
We are specifically
focused on
the V-to-P communication
using Indian.
This is a collaborative
project between
Florida International
University
and Ford Motor Company.
The very high
level objective
of the project is
to demonstrate
the advantageous of NDN
in CV2X environment.
We have sorted
out some issues
in the current system,
mainly scalability
issue in the context of
pedestrian safety
applications and propose
some insights that we
might use to solve
such issues by leveraging
the benefits of using NDN.
Based on that, we
have developed
sV2Pc and NDN
forwarding strategy,
which is a better suit
in vehicular environment
to ensure scalability.
Before a deep dive
into our presentation,
I first wanted to provide
an overview of PSM
or a personal
safety message,
which although not
implemented yet,
but it is
considered a viable
solution for ensuring
pedestrian safety.
In PSM, all vulnerable
roadside users,
like the pedestrian,
the cyclist, etcetera.
They will broadcast PSM
messages periodically.
Those messages contain
some basic information
like their speed,
their position in
which direction
they're heading
to, etcetera.
The period of the
broadcast is one second.
In each second, all
of these entities
actually generate
one new message
and transmit to
the network.
Now,
imagine a crowded
intersection like this,
and what will happen
if all of them
broadcasting PSM messages
in every second.
In this case, we
need to facilitate
a huge amount of
bandwidth for that.
We can say it
like this system
is not scalable at all.
To address this
scalability issue, mainly,
we think of using
NDN to solve
this issue and
first simulation,
we have used a simple
intersectional
awareness application.
We have designed
a forwarding
strategy as sV2Pc,
which is completely
distributed and simple,
and works on by
suppressing similar type
of interesting
data packets.
Then also work on like
geographical boundaries
for interest forwarding.
To identify the
communication issue and
also highlight the
proposed design decisions.
We have developed
a simplified
use case application named
NDN-PSA or
NDN based pedestrian
safety application.
More specifically
it will enable
communication
between cars who
are like approaching
to the intersection,
and pedestrians who are
like crossing the
intersection are located
near the
intersection using
our request response
based NDN mechanism to
avoid any potential
coalition.
For example, the
cars will send
interest to know whether
there would be
any pedestrian
in any particular area
that may be on
its trajectory
and relevant pedestrians.
I mean, like who might be
present in a
close proximity
of the target location,
will reply with a data
packets and by this,
the car will know that,
they're pedestrians
presence
and take decisions
accordingly.
Designing the
naming scheme is
a very crucial factor
for NDN application.
To keep things simple,
our naming scheme consists
of just three components.
The app name, which is
NDN-PSA in our case.
We will have the region of
interest which is actually
our coarsely defined area
about what a car
wants to query,
like whether there'll be
any pedestrian or not.
We also include the time
of sending the interest.
However, as sV2Pc mainly
works on suppressing
similar types of interest,
or maybe the
packets we'd have
the same name or
similar name.
These components, that
region of interest time,
this must be
coarse enough,
so that we can get like
a repeatable names and
how we have made the
name of details,
we will discuss in
the later slides.
In this slide,
I will provide
a high level overview
of our use case
application.
Suppose this
blue-marked car
is approaching to
the intersection
and wants to
know if some pedestrian
might be there.
It sends an interest,
and the interest name,
we can see the
application name,
then the target location.
For simulation
purposes it is like
a geo coordinate and
also the current time.
Imagine these
two pedestrian
the green one and
the orange one.
They are in the
transmission range
of the car and they
receives the interests.
Then they will calculate
their own position
or geolocation and
compare if they are in
a close proximity with
the target location,
which is actually
expressed
in the interest name.
The green guy, it
says that, "Hey,
I'm far away
from the target
location" and it can
ignore the interest.
But the orange one is
located in close
proximity and
thus he sends
a data packet
back with its position,
speed, etcetera, to
alert the
approaching vehicle.
It may seem to some of you
that we just shift
the paradigm of
PSM where I like
interest instead of
the pedestrian
broadcasting messages,
the car sending interest
periodically and the
pedestrians respond,
if it's simpler level
and which is true.
But however now
the question is,
will any request response
based system will
solve the issue?
The answer is no. Think of
this busy intersection
with lots of cars.
If all of them start
asking question,
or sending interest
in NDN term,
in every second,
a huge network traffic
would be generated.
Again, the crowded
intersection,
if all the
pedestrian reply
with every interest
they have received,
again, we will generating
a huge network traffic.
In both cases, these
are no better than PSM.
Here comes NDN to solve
the issue with some of
it's unique feature
NDN can provide
solution to solve
this issue and build
a physical communication.
Inspirit from the
previous two issues,
we first ask the question,
do all the cars
actually need to send
interest packets?
Think of a scenario
where these two
mark cars want
to know about
the presence of
any pedestrian in
the same location.
As like they are running
in the same lane,
they will cross
the steam portion
with the crosswalk,
their region of
interest would be seen.
We can assume that they
are trying to send
the same interests,
at least with the
same interest name.
Instead of sending our
new interest package,
it may happen that one of
them can ask and other can
simply use the answer
instead of
transmitting a new
interest packet.
Based on this assumption,
we have used the interests
separation mechanism
so that if a group of
car wants to ask
the same question and
one of them has
already asked,
then the others will
suppress their
own interest.
Now lots of interest
has been suppressed.
But think of
this again for
all the interests
that being sent.
If all the pedestrians,
they reply with
data packets back,
then again, we will
generate a huge
amount of traffic.
The same question
now we can
ask for the
pedestrian also,
do all the pedestrians
need to reply?
Suppose this
blue-marked car
want to take a right turn,
at the intersection
and wants to
know if there would be
any pedestrian
in region one,
and thus sends an
interest packet.
Now, all of the
pedestrian in
region one would
receive the interest.
Theoretically
they can try to
reply for the
interest packet
and send individual
data packets.
But at least for
the context of
our application.
Which is like the car
wants to know
if there would
be any obstacle in his
trajectory or not.
At least in our context,
we can say that this is
quite unnecessary
and single reply
is sufficient to alert
the vehicles
from R1 region.
Based on this assumption,
we have used that data
suppression mechanism
to suppress any
unnecessary
and redundant traffic.
In data suppression,
if any pedestrian receives
any interest and
is able to reply,
but some other
pedestrian has
already replied for
the same interest packet,
then it will not
reply anymore.
We have also introduced
some other types
of suppression.
This suppression
mechanisms have
been used in lots
of previous world,
but we find them to
be better used
in our context,
like in a multiple
hops scenario,
for order should
only follow up
the interest in
the direction of
reporting shared
data producer.
For example,
this car sends
an interest packet and
all these three cars,
receive the interest and
theoretically they can all
rebroadcast the
interest again.
But in our scenario,
a potential data
producer will be present
on or near the
intersection.
Now the question is,
will this red marked
car rebroadcast
would be helpful or not?
It is obvious that
these rebroadcast
will not be
helpful because
this is in the
opposite direction
from the potential
data producer.
In this case, this
car just discard
the interest and
the other scheduling
broadcast.
Again in this example,
these cars sends interest
and both of these cars,
receive the interest now.
Both of them can
rebroadcast actually.
But based on our example,
this red markers
rebroadcast
would be more helpful
because it is closer
to potential
data producer.
This is our
design approach
from consumer's
perspective,
like when a car is close
to an intersection
by certain limit,
then it expresses
an interest
from the application side,
and then it moved to
our sV2Pc Forwarder,
which actually based
on some suppression logic.
Besides like whether to
actually foward the
interest or not.
This is our
design approach
from the producers
perspective,
like when a node
receive the interest it
first check whether it
is relevant to him or not.
That means if it is
close proximity to
the target
location or not,
and if yes, then
it publishes
the data from the
application site,
which later moves to
that sV2Pc Forwarder.
That actually
decides whether
to forward that
data or not.
How interests suppression
works and before
describing that loop back
at what suppression is.
These two cars will
try to send the
same interest
and so one of
their interest will
be suppressed.
The question is now as
our system is
completely distributed,
one car might not know
whether other car has
send the same
interest or not.
To solve this issue,
before transmitting
a new interest,
you know to first check
if it receives the
same interests before.
If yes, that means someone
else has already sent
the same interest,
and then it can discard
the new transmission.
But if all the car
send the interest
at the same time,
say at the beginning
of each second,
then one would not hear
like what others across
meeting and
no-interest population
would happen.
We have added a random
delay to the cars to
transmit so that
the cars who
are scheduled
transmit later,
they can get a
chance about
what other cars
are transmitting,
and interests
suppression can happen.
I think we have this slide
before content of these,
because to be the
same interests
the name should be same,
and we have three
components here.
The application name
is always same.
We need to make
this target location at
time a bit coarse because
if they're too much
granular then it
would be a rare case that
two interest name
would be seen,
and we can see no
interest suppression.
We have made this
location portion
and the time a
big granular.
Let's assume this
blue mark car
wants to know how about
blue region and this
orange mark car
wants to know about
the orange region.
Now as the target
location varies here,
their interest name
would not be seen.
Instead, if both of
them wants to know about
the yellow region,
which is the combined
of both their resumes,
then their target portion
of the interest
name will be same.
In similar way, blue mark
car send the interest
in 25.02 seconds.
As we mentioned that we
have introduced
a random delay,
and see these
orange mark car
send the interest
at 25.07 seconds.
In the name instead
of 25.02 or
25.07 if we
mentioned like 25,
just only, then
the time component
will also be seen
for disinterest.
That will make this
two interest same,
which actually
paves the way
for interest
suppression to happen.
Data suppression
also works in
the same way as
interests suppression,
so before sending
data packet,
a node checks like
if it receives
any data packet at
the same interest
name or before.
Again, like if all
the pedestrian
from a group of
closely located
people replies
immediately after
receiving an interest,
then no separation
will ever happen.
We can think of like
any closely located area.
There are a number of
people and all
of them receive
interest at the same time
and immediately reply.
Lower node will here
like what others
are transmitting.
In this case like no
data separation
will happen.
We have also added
random delay that
actually ensure that
other pedestrian who are
transmitting a bit
later position can
have the chance to hear
what others are saying,
and this will help
us to make data
suppression work.
We have evaluated
our application
by comparing our
application with PSM,
which is also a
pedestrian safety
application as baseline,
and we have compared
the bandwidth to total
number of packets,
and we have done
the evaluation
for the device scenario
like different
pedestrian count,
different that
vehicle density and
for both single and
multiple hops scenario.
As evaluation
tool, we have
used the Indian
Sim and Sumo.
This is the
resulting graph
describing a single
hub scenario.
In the x-axis, we have
the number of pedestrians,
and growing
exponentially from 40,
80, 160, 320 to 640.
In the y-axis we
have the number of total
transmitted packet.
We have around
10 simulations
and then take the
mean value for that.
We also tried to
simulate different
densities of car,
like low, medium
and high densities.
Besides for the
comparison,
we also created
a scenario that
mimic WSM as
baseline scenario.
From that scenario
we actually round
with all the
same parameters
that our Indian one like.
We have calculated
the total
transmitted amout
which we have denoted as
baseline in that
yellow color.
We can see that for a
single hop scenario,
in all cases,
our approach like
outperforms PSM.
While PSM has an
exponential growth,
I mean it's
like the 40-80,
it has an
exponential growth
with the number of
pedestrian counts.
But our approach has
almost a constant result.
Now in this slide,
we have actually
tried to compare
the results in a
multiple hops scenario.
But for your information,
this is not an apple to
apple comparison
because in PSM,
our packet can
travel only one hop.
Whereas in our
Indian approach,
a packet can transmit
it through multiple hops.
This actually is
very much helpful
because a car can learn
about the presence of
any obstacles from
a longer distance
and can decide his action
accordingly within
a longer time.
Although this is an apple
to an orange comparison,
but still we can see
that when the number of
pedestrians are a bit
high, for example,
in a crowded intersection,
so our approach can still
outperform the PSM.
We have tried to
break the bars in
accordance with
the distance of
the consumers and
the intersection,
to compare in a
more similar way.
>> Proyash you
got two minutes.
>> Yeah, this is the
last slide actually.
[LAUGHTER] We also
identified actually
a large corpus of
future work to
[inaudible] improve
the scalability
of vehicle to pedestrian
communication.
The first one is,
we have considered
the applicability of
very general Indian
security mechanisms
in our use case
application.
But eventually,
if we want to make it
a more robust work,
then we need to
ensure a proper
security mechanism.
For example, we need to
define a trust schema.
We need to think of
how to distribute
keys in
a vehicle environment
and other stuff.
Secondly, it is evident
that we only show
one use-case
application that
leverages the benefits
of this sV2Pc.
However, we need to
explore similar
applications
where we can give
some benefits from
the interest name
repeatability,
and geo bound can
be helpful while
forwarding,
and in those application
we can also use
the sV2Pc, and it's good.
Finally, for the
current state of sV2Pc,
we think of a completely
distributed mechanism.
However, we can use
some centralized
knowledge that
may be from the ISCU
of an intersection or so,
that might be helpful to
improve the suppression
logic a lot more.
Well, thank you very
much for listening.
[inaudible].
>> Thank you. Go ahead
and stop sharing.
Always happy to see you.
Automotive
applications of India.
Our next presentation
will be by Ashiq,
who is a computer
science PhD student
at the University
of Arizona.
His research
interests involve
future Internet
architectures
and wireless
communication.
He's currently working on
datacentric wireless
networking from
the link layer to the
application layer.
Ashiq, go ahead.
>> I believe video, audio,
and slides are okay.
>> Yes. You're good.
>> Thank you.
[NOISE] Today
I'll be talking
about BLEnD
: Improving NDN
performance over
wireless links using
interest bundling.
I'm Ashiq from the
University of Arizona.
Everyone's saying
that wireless devices
are practically taking
over everything.
Just a few quick
examples, AR VR,
even in military networks,
I hit the satellite
links a little bit,
but it's also there.
Then we have IoTs and
of course, Edge computing.
Everywhere wireless
networking is
becoming the
part and parcel.
However, they also expect
high throughput
and reliability.
But in reality,
when we talk about
wireless communication,
we can see that when we
talk about a
particular channel,
it's half-duplex, either
sends or receives.
We also have channel
access contention.
That is, a pretty
cool ascender
would pause until the
channel is available.
Then of course, we also
have other challenges
such as collision and
of course congestion.
When we talk about data is
changing in
wireless medium,
[NOISE] we come
to talk about
the congestion control and
loss recovery a lot.
To balance this,
what happens is that
there is an
exchange between
signals for data packets.
What are the
signal packets?
In TCP/IP we know them
as acknowledgments,
and in NDN,
we can consider
the interests packets
as the signals.
We have the signal
and data packets.
Let's say that we have
this theoretical
channel capacity.
There is a signal packet,
and with respect to that,
some data packet comes in.
However, we can
see that there's
a small gap between
the signal and data.
Inter-frame
spacing, link-layer
acknowledgment, RTS/CTS,
and channel excess delay.
This takes place in
between the two packets.
When we consider
multiple signal
and data packets,
what happens is that
when we combine
the data packets,
we can see the
effective bandwidth is
actually much lower
than the channel capacity.
Then we ask the question
is that how can we
increase the channel
access for data?
The basic idea is to
reduce signal frequency.
It asks for a trade-off
between the amount
of signals that we
provide to the network
or the amount of
channel that
we access that
we want to increase
for the data packets.
In TCP/IP, the
basic idea is
to have one acknowledgment
for multiple data packets.
In the end, what we
can do is that we can
use one interest packet
to fetch multiple
data packets.
Again, we have the
signal and data.
Then again, we have
the channel capacity.
We have our old
effective bandwidth.
In this particular
example,
we have one single packet
that touches multiple
data packets.
If we sum them
up together,
we can see that the new
effective bandwidth
is much more than
the old one.
This is an interesting.
We can also already see
that it can be done.
Let's try to put
it into test
and see what can be
done or what can
be achieved.
We see that interest
bundling improves
throughput.
We tested it on
single-hop Wi-Fi
in infrastructure mode,
just an access point
as a producer and
a consumer that sends
a single interest to
fetch continuous data.
What we see here is
that when there is
no bundling going on
or it's only one interest,
one data communication,
effective bandwidth
extremely low
compared to what we have.
If we send only
one interest
to fetch continuous data,
we can see that
goodput can be
improved almost
like 60 percent
or even up to more
than 90 percent
in simulated environments.
Next question we
want to ask is that
where do we bundle
or unbundle?
By where I mean in the
network stack itself.
The reason I'm presenting
a reverse triangle
is to present
the amount of
difficulty from
top in terms of the
size of the area.
If we consider bundling
at the application layer,
what happens is
that we end up in
an end-to-end
communication and it ends
up breaking everything
at the lower layers.
If we tried to do it at
the transport, again,
it's tightly coupled with
the application is still
almost end-to-an end,
breaks the
forwarding part.
If we tried to do it
at the network layer,
it requires
complex changes
to this stateful
forwarding.
The safest part
that we could
find is the link
layer that would need
the least number of
changes and would
also be able to hide
all the bundling,
unbundling operations
from the upper layer.
That would be
really helpful.
That's where the
high level idea
of this work comes
into play that
is blanked like
bundling interests
with link layer
encoding and decoding.
At the higher level idea,
what happens here
is that we consider
only a single hub for
this part because it's
at the link level.
At the sender, the
forwarding steps
takes place as usual.
Let's say we have multiple
interest packets.
The link would bundle
those interest
packets into one,
send over the
wireless channel,
and at the receiver side,
the link receives it,
unbundles into multiple
interest packets,
and it goes to
the forwarder.
Caching aggregation,
routing, everything is
practically unaffected.
This is good.
Let's look at a little bit
deeper at the technical
aspects of it.
We have two
parts in BLEnD,
sender-side encoding and
receiver-side decoding.
When we talk about the
sender-side encoding
is actually has two parts.
Like a cross layer design
between the transport
and the link layer.
It starts at the
transport scheduler
where an interest packet,
we assume it
contains name,
and also sequence number,
and also the nonce.
The transport
scheduler what
it does is that,
it adds an LP tag to
the interest packet,
and marks if it's a
retransmission or not,
and also the current
congestion window.
The bTAG is practically
a 64-bit LP tag.
The first field marks
if it's a
retransmission or not.
The second field
contains the
congestion window.
Then this packet carries
over through the NFD.
NFD, all the
states pit FAPE,
everything is based on
the main sequence
and also nonce,
so everything is
pretty much unchanged.
At the link layer,
magic starts to happen.
Sorry for saying magic,
but what has happened is
that the link layer
first checks if
it's a retransmission
or not
based on the bundle
tag or bTAG.
If it is, then
what it does is
that locally it
calculates a start and
ending sequence
and it sets to
the sequence number
that it already
cedes from the
interest packet.
If it's not, then
it checks if
a sequence is sent
in a previous
bundle already.
If it's yes, then it
will just drop it
because it's already
sent it out in a bundle.
If not, then it
calculates the start and
end sequence based on,
of course, the
sequence number of
the current interest and
some sequence
in the future.
It would be the minimum of
the congestion window
or some constant
bundle interval.
Yes, practically is
the end sequence which
points to future
sequence numbers.
Then the link layer
would make a bundle.
Where it would remove
the sequence number from
the main part
and re-encode
the start and end
sequence on the bTAG.
We can see that the bTAG
carries the start
and end sequence.
It's practically a range.
When it goes,
so again, bTAG,
it updates the updates
with the start
and end sequence,
and then we move to
the receiver side decoding
when the receiver
side receives it.
The receiver side decoding
is purely on
the link layer.
Interest comes
in. It checks
if it has a bundle
tag or not.
If no, directly send
it to the forwarder.
If yes, it looks at
the start and end
sequence are equal,
practically indicating
a retransmission.
What happens here
is that if yes,
then it would
have a decode,
start sequence and decode
end sequence that assigns
to the start sequence,
if it's a retransmission.
Otherwise, it looks at
if an end sequence has
been previously seen.
What it means is that,
this bundle has
already been received
and unbundled so we
can ignore it safely.
That's what it
does, drops it.
If it's a new
end sequence,
what it does is that it
assigns the decode start
sequence to the previous
end sequence plus one.
We will come into
explanation of it a
little bit later.
After doing so, it
has a start sequence
and end sequence for
the decoding information.
Then it goes to
the next step.
Basically a loop, where it
loops over from
the decode start
sequence to the decode
end sequence and
just adds back
the sequence number
to the name itself.
We can see that we
are reconstructing
from a bundled interest to
multiple unbundled
interests and
forwarding them to
the upper layers.
The sequence and
the name part
is pretty much untouched.
After that, what
happens here,
I talked about that,
it keeps track of the
previous N-sequence,
so the reason has to
handle lost
bundle interest.
Let's say that we have
a bundle interval
of 10 at the center.
We have the sender, and
looking at the
transport and link,
we also have the producer
or the receiver,
and from left to
right we have the
sequence numbers.
Of course, the first
sequence number comes into
play depending on
the bundle interval,
there would be
10 data packets
scheduled from the
producer side,
and we can see
that the previous
N-sequence is also 10.
Now, all the other
interests packets from
the sender side would
be suppressed at the link,
and then for the next
interest packet,
there would be
a new bundle.
However, assuming that,
that bundled interest
was lost at the link,
so the receiver is
practically sitting idle,
and not sending out
any data packets.
But there should be
some recovery because
we're losing all the new
10 interest packets.
What happens is that
when the next bundle
comes in, the
receiver side,
would assign the
start sequence
to the previous
end sequence
to fill the gap of
the lost bundle,
so we call it receiver
side gap-filling.
At least it provides
some amount
of reliability from
the receiver side.
Let's take a look at
some simulation results on
goodput and also effect
of bundle interval.
When we talk about
goodput improvement,
test on a 802.11b and
simulated maximum
capacity of
11 and 24 megabits
per second.
We can see that
with BLEnD we can
achieve more
than 30 percent
of goodput improvement.
When we start to
play around with
the bundle size,
we can see that even
a small amount of
bundling can improve
the goodput by
a large amount,
and increasing the bundles
gives small increments
of improvement in goodput.
But the main
reason is that,
why do we see these
improvements?
Is because the
reduction in
the link layer
transmission events
at the sender side.
You can see that with even
a small amount of bundle
the link layer
transmission events
has been significantly
lowered.
Where we would have like
70,000 without
any bundling,
we would drop below
10,000 transmissions
at the link.
Now, talking about
the challenges
and these are
the most significant part
of this overall talk.
The first one is
RTT fluctuation.
The producer processes
the bundle interest
immediately and
sends the data back.
Also, we saw that the
receiver side handles
the lost bundle interests
which is a
delayed reaction,
so there is RTT
fluctuation going on.
The way we prove
it is that we
played around with
the RTT variance
multiplier,
and for 100
megabytes of file,
we expect roughly
71,000 data packets.
What we see here
is that for
the default
multiplier of four,
the retransmission
events and the Psent
or the producer send
events are very high.
As we increase
the multiplier,
the retransmission
events goes down.
Also the producer send
events goes down as well,
which in terms
improves the goodput.
The next challenge is
duplicate data in
multiple hops.
What happens here is that
although we didn't present
in the paper that's
accepted at Moe Kong,
we tried to play around
it a little bit,
and in here see
the consumer D is
the data node,
and we look at
the pitch of C and
the middle node A.
It has two interests
to send at the
application.
But at the link,
we have just the name
prefix slash eight,
and the sequence is
basically in the
bundled tech.
The nonce for this
bundle tag is
the same for both the
interests packets.
It goes to the next hop,
and then is again the
same for the next hop.
When node A is
going to send
or brought the
interest packet,
to the next hop,
the overseer overhears it.
Given the nonce is
different for the
other sequence number,
there are two
entries in the pit.
What happens is that when
the data comes back,
C receives the data,
it looks at two entries,
one from the app
and one from
node A to C
ends up forwarding the
data packet to pay.
This is bad for
channel utilization and
also duplicate data,
which is
practically useless
in this particular case.
We can keep a name
non-stable at the
senders link,
so just keeping
track of the nonces.
One good thing is that
this duplication
happens at the
discovery phase,
considering that we are
using self-learning.
This table size of the
link should be very
small and would
have low overhead.
Talking about more
research opportunities,
maybe a rate-base
congestion
controller to avoid
the RTT filtration.
Dynamic bundle interval to
scale well over different
link capacities.
Sender side bundle
loss reaction that
would help to reduce
the producer's
side idle time.
Of course, given
that we see that
we are optimizing
channel utilization,
so this would also
be helpful to reduce
the hidden station effect
and minimize loss,
and last but not
least, hop-by-hop
transport opportunity.
When we have
multi-hop networks,
less mobility may be
explore multipath
for load balancing.
But when we talk about
this hop-by-hop transport,
it's currently not
present there,
so maybe extends sync
for transport
functionalities
of each hop with some
rate management.
This, and of course,
there are many
more possibilities
in the overall work.
This was the early
work that we
presented and
thank you for
joining in and
any questions
I would really
like to take
those and explore
future opportunities.
Thank you.
>> Thank you Ashiq,
you actually
ended a couple of
minutes early.
There's quite a bit of
a discussion going
on on Slack.
If you want to join
in and chime in.
>> Yeah, absolutely.
>> Go ahead and
stop sharing,
and we'll have Saurab,
step up with his
presentation.
Saurab, go ahead and start
sharing your screen.
Saurab is a PhD student
at the University
of Memphis,
working with land,
he received his master's
degree in computer science
from Memphis in
December 2020,
and his bachelor's degree
in Computer Engineering
from Tribhuvan
University in Nepal.
I hope I said
that somewhere
close to right, so
I can [inaudible].
His places of interest,
of course, include
data networking
and distributed computing.
Saurab, if you are here.
Ashiq, you can
mute your mic.
>> Oh sorry about that.
>> I need to quit
re-join because
I can't share the screen.
Give me a moment.
>> Check your
microphone is still not
muted. There you go.
[BACKGROUND]
A little bit,
if you're having
difficulty,
I could try to
display your slides.
Just let us know
what you prefer.
[BACKGROUND]
Did we lose him?
>> Can you hear me?
>> Yes.
>> Sorry for the delay.
>> That's okay,
you're going to go ahead
and share your slides.
>> Yeah,
can
you see my screen?
>> Yeah, we're seeing
the speaker's view.
We're going to try
going to full-screen.
>> Is it fine now?
>> Excellence.
Yes, perfect,
you're good to go.
>> To there moving right?
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you so much
Christos for the
introduction.
Our work is on
adaptive duplicate
suppression for
multicasting in a
Multi-Access NDN network.
We have little
bit more about
the problem statement from
the previous
speaker as well,
but I'm a little bit
repeating it here again.
On the multicasting,
we can run into
a scenario where a lot of
redundant traffic flows
into the network.
You can see
here some nodes
can send an interest
out for some files.
While the data
hasn't come back
some other nodes can
send the same
interest out,
and then there can be
a lot of traffic and
all other nodes also
can send the
same interests,
which it can make the
situation even worse.
The similar
scenario occurs
in case of data reply
over the networks.
The situation
even get worse
when unsolicited
data occurs
because the node can
just reply the data
from the cache.
In that scenario,
many nodes
can reply the same
data packets,
so there can be
taken to a lot of
duplicates in that
scenario as well.
Our goal for this work
is to reduce the number of
redundant requests
and data replies
and to increase the
overall bandwidth.
Right now we mostly focus
on the single-hop
scenario.
Ideally, the suppression
should add up to the
network condition.
In case of lossy
environment,
only one
interesting data of
the same name
can be sent by
a node and then on
the multicast, same
multi-access link.
If the environment
is lossy,
then small number of
duplicates it's fine.
We also want to place
this functionality in
the multicast face so
that it can support a
lot of applications,
so it'll be intrinsic
to the end of itself.
The high-level design is,
we have two
different cases.
One is look
behind case, and
the other one
is look ahead
case which I'll talk
about in a minute.
The strategy is here
to record all
the interest,
that is name and
duplicate count receive
from or sent to
a multicast face into
a measurement table,
so just record all
these names and
duplicate counts.
Each of these entries
in the measurement
table has a
short lifetime,
order of
propagation delay.
Approximately
that's the lifetime
of this intro in the
measurement table.
If the interests
satisfied or timed out,
remove
the corresponding
interest from the table.
Also before sending
that interest
of data packet to
a multicast face,
check if it is
already in the table.
Which means if
the interests
of data is already
in the table,
which means it's in
a flight so you don't have
to duplicate that
interests of data.
If it is in the table,
just drop the
interests of data.
If not, then you go to
the look-ahead case.
In the look-ahead
case, which
obviously means when
there is no record
in the measurement
table before forming
an interest to a
multicast face
, you wait for some time.
This is a
suppression timer.
Wait for some
time, and then if
another interest
of data is
overheard during
this weight,
you can cancel
the forwarding.
They don't need to
send a duplicate out.
The suppression timer
should be adopted.
As we mentioned the goal,
this is one of
the other goal.
It's adaptive to the
network conditions,
if there is a large
number of duplicates,
then suppression
timer can be higher.
If it's not, then the
suppression timer
can be decreased.
For the lossy
link permitting
a few duplicates
would be fine,
so the wait time
can be relatively
smaller for that case.
The design logic is we
implemented this in
the link service and
we hope that it
should be applied.
We implemented
here because
can be applied to all
the applications.
They can find a work in
progress in this link.
This is our incoming
data and interests
pipeline.
How does the
suppression worksheet,
when something is
received from
the neighbors,
interested data is
received from
the neighbors?
If the same interests
of data it already
scheduled for the
transmission,
then just cancel the
previously scheduled.
If the same
interests of data
is received and
it will check
whether the same
as it already
scheduled for
transmission,
you cancel that one.
If not, then check in
the measurement table.
In the measurement
table, if there is
no measurement for this
intercept data that
is just received,
then you add a bunch
of other things
in the table.
Add interests or data,
record to the table,
and initialize a
duplicate counter.
This duplicate
counter necessarily
means how many
duplicates you
received from the network
but that's the counter.
You initialize the
duplicate counter
for that interests
of data.
Then also schedule that
interested data
record expression.
This record in
the table doesn't
stay forever,
as we mentioned
earlier so it
expires in a short
period of time.
Also scheduled
that expression.
But if it is already in
the table and we
check whether that
is interest of data.
If it is
interests, then we
increase the duplicate
count of the interest
and then handle
this interest
to the local
forwarding pipeline.
If it is a data,
then there's a bunch
of stuff to do.
This is EWMA,
which
means Exponentially
Weighted Moving Average,
I'll talk about this
in the next slide.
We compute the exponential
weighted moving
average of the interests
prefix if it's data.
Because when the
data comes back
it means the interest
is satisfied,
so we have to remove
the interest
from the table.
We compute that for the
interest prefix and
remove the
corresponding interest
record from the
measurement table.
After removing we
also update the
suppression timer.
The suppression timer will
be highly
correlated with the
duplicate count,
as we said, so it
has to be adaptive.
That's why we update
a suppression timer for
this interest prefix.
Finally, we increase
the duplicate data
count for the data.
Also as we mentioned here,
there is a record
scheduling
of interest and
data in the table,
if interests of data,
if it expires, we update
the corresponding
suppression timer
of the interests or
the data prefix.
But this is how the
incoming interest in
data works.
For the outgoing
interest with data
when the interests of data
is received from
the local forwarding
pipeline,
we check if that is in
the measurement table.
If it is in the
measurement table,
we simply drop
that interest
of data you don't have
to fold that duplication
for network.
If it is not in the
measurement table,
then we set a suppression
timer for this,
the suppression timer
that we compute here.
This will be used to
set the suppression timer.
Once the suppressant
timer expires,
we add this record
whether it is
an interest of
data in the
measurement module.
Which means the nodes
its own forwarding is also
added to the
measurement module.
This is a measurement
[inaudible] that I
talked previously.
Nodes on folding
is also added
to the module,
and then finally
the interests
of data it is forwarded
to the network.
The exponential weighted
moving average,
we compute the
exponential weighted
moving average of the
duplicate counts.
Previously I showed
it in the slides,
here, when we
receiving interest on
data we can insulate
the duplicate counter and
then distribute
the counter.
We use this to compute the
exponential weighted
moving average.
Basically, we use
this formula to compute
the moving average.
This is a smoothing
factor. We basically
also considering the
previous duplicate counts,
not only the present
duplicate count but
also considering
the previous
duplicate counts
for the same prefix.
That's why we smooth
this duplicate count.
As I said, the
granularity is
name minus the
last component,
also the moving average is
reset after
the maximum measurement
inactively period.
Which means it will
computed for the prefix.
If nothing is received
for that prefix for
quite a period of time,
then we remove
that measurement
because it might not
be relevant for the
future prefixes anymore.
The suppression
time and the timer.
We use one algorithm
to compute the
suppression time
and the
corresponding timer.
The main goal
of this is to
maintain the
duplicate count
below the duplicate
threshold.
This duplicate threshold,
it's configured based on
the loss rate of
the environment.
If the network is very
lossy then the threshold
can be higher,
if the network is
pretty stable,
there is no loss then
the duplicates
threshold can
be pretty much smaller.
Here, I've shown
how we update
the suppression timer.
It has three phases
and how it is updated.
If the moving average
is above the threshold
and is increasing
which means
there are a lot of
duplicates in the network,
so it's increasing and
the moving average is not
decreasing and
is also able to
threshold then
we exponentially
increases the
suppression timer.
It increases here and
the suppression
timer increases
exponentially,
so it resists
at some point.
Now, the moving
average is still above
the threshold but if
the moving
average is still
threshold but it
is decreasing,
if that's the
condition then
we keep the suppression
timer as it is,
so it is a carryover of
the suppression time.
We don't decrease it
until we reach to a point
when the moving average
is below the threshold.
Then when moving
average comes
below the threshold
which means
it asumes that knowledge
has done a good
job in the past,
so that's why now
the suppression
timer is in a range,
so you start decreasing
it linearly.
Increases to
some point and
again, this thing happens.
The expectation is after
some period of time,
after running for a while,
the algorithm
will itself find
an operating range for
that particular
environment.
That's an expectation.
It's finding an
operating range.
That's the
algorithm on how
we address the
suppression time.
The suppression timer it's
a random between zero
and the suppression time.
The timer is the
one which will be
used before folding an
interest or data out.
The suppression
time is computed
regularly after we receive
the new duplicate account.
This is updated
regularly but
when the node decides
to forward something,
we compute the
suppression timer.
The suppression
timer will be
always correlated
with the duplicates
in the network.
But of course,
certain prefix.
I'll go to the
implementation
and experimental setup.
As I've said, it
is implemented in
the current NFD at face
in the link service.
For the experiment,
we use a
mini-NDN Wi-Fi and this
is the topology
that we use.
Here, the consumers
simultaneously fetch
615-kilobyte of file which
has 81 segments using
catchunks and putchunks
over the
multi-access link.
This is the
topology and then
these are some
of the constants
that we use in
the experiments.
The smoothing_factor
is this and there are
a bunch of other
constants that
we have used for the
experiments as well
as for the implementation.
This is our
preliminary evaluation
we are still working
on the evaluations.
But this is one
number that I would
like to share.
Here, this is the
average number of
received increased
data unsolicited,
interest with data
packet received.
How many of them are
received by a consumer?
In this experiment,
we have
this three consumers
and one producer.
The interest packet
without suppression,
there were 204 interests
packet was received.
Basically, they were
altogether 81 segments
but total number of
interests received
by a consumer which
means a consumer is also
receiving the interest
from its neighbors,
so this is the number
of data
the consumer received
without suppression.
From 145 of
those data were
unsolicited
because it only
expected roughly
81 segments.
The other data packets
were unsolicited here.
With suppression,
you can see
the interest packet
is substantially
reduced just to 90
which is you would
expect about 81-82
interest to go
out and then it
is reduced to
substantially
almost three times.
Not through number
2.5 times, I'll say.
Then also for the data,
it is also reduced
substantially and
then unsolicited
data is very less.
At the producer
side, all together,
producer without
suppression received
307 interests packets.
With suppression,
it just received
135 interest packets.
This is a very
substantial reduction
in the duplicate counts.
[NOISE] Here we can
see in this table,
the expected
number of packets
from the consumer
and producer.
We were using
the duplicate
threshold of 1.5,
so ideally you
would expect
246 of those interests in
data packets
combined which
is 1.5 is the threshold.
Up to 1.5 duplicate
is allowed,
so which means
you would expect
82 interests plus
82 data packets,
total number of
segments into
1.5 which is 246.
With suppression,
only 262 packets
were observed.
Total number of
interests in
data packet from
both consumer and
producer which is
135 interests packet
you can see it
here and 127 data packet
which was received
by the consumers.
Without suppression
it was pretty high,
307 interests packet was
received by the producers.
Total number of
packet is [NOISE]
307 plus 225 which
is the data packet.
You can see from
this table,
the reduction in the
duplicate traffic
is almost 50 percent.
That's why with
the suppression
model that we
have implemented,
we have come
up to this far
reducing
the large number of
duplicate packet.
Some of the challenges
that we're facing right
now is the fluctuation of
suppression time
and finding
optimal operating range.
Here in this experiment,
this was the same
experiment that I showed
earlier which
had 82 segments.
The suppression time
was fluctuating
from quite high
and then it
was coming back down
all the way to the
minimum value.
We're not expected
to come to
the very minimum value
but we expect it
to stay in some of
the operating range.
Then again, it goes up and
then again comes down
to the almost
minimum value.
If the suppression
time comes to this
low which is the
minimum value then
obviously the number
of duplicates
will start
increasing because
the node will not
have enough
suppression time
and all the nodes
will forward their
interests of data,
so that's
why the duplicate
account loss increase.
This is one of the
problems that we
are observing right now.
I also run another
experiment
with five megabytes
of file with
700 segments to see
how the behaviors
goes for the
longer period of
time and almost a
similar behavior
to observe.
It goes up and then comes
back down to the
very minimum
and then again goes up.
The operating range
is still not found,
so which means this is one
of the challenges that
we're facing right now.
This might be because
of several things,
the algorithm, it might
not be well tuned
or the parameters that
we are using right now.
I showed those constants
in the previous slides.
Some of them are
listed here,
so the smoothing_factor,
adative_decrease.
How you decrease the
suppression time
once the goal is reached,
what is the number
that you use?
Similarly,
the
multiplicative_increase
is also another number.
What is the factor
that you use
to increase the
suppression time?
These are the
parameters that
still requires tuning,
so these factors plus
the algorithm might be
affecting this not finding
optimal range but we
are working on it.
That's why these constants
need to be carefully
chosen and
based on the network
it might be different,
so you need to
properly tune them.
In conclusion,
in this work,
we designed and
implemented
an adaptive duplicate
suppression for
multicasting and a
multi-access NDN network.
We also performed
some experiments
to demonstrate
how our implementation
is working.
In future,
we want to work on
the challenges that I
showed in the
previous slide and
especially on tuning the
algorithm and
the constants.
We also want to perform
more experiments with
various scenarios and
network size
and conditions.
Also,
compare the other
metrics such as delays.
Delays will also be one
of the interesting
numbers to show,
because it will show how
the suppression
is affecting
the delay in the network,
like the content
fetching delay.
It might be a little
bit increasing
or decreasing or we
have to see that.
We're also looking at
the possibility of
using machine learning to
determine the suppression
time and also
tune the constants
that I showed earlier.
Some of those areas
we're actively looking in
the future for
our future work.
These are the references.
Thank you and please
let me know if you
have any questions.
>> Thank you,
sir. I appreciate
you ending on time.
There's a discussion
going on,
on Slack about
what happens
if you drop an interest.
You may join in and
answer the question.
This was the last
presentation for the panel,
so I think we've
reached the end.
Thank you to all the
presenters and Lotfi,
passing this on to you.
>> Thank you, Christos
and all the presenters.
This concludes the
NDN Com 2021 program.
I hope it was a good
learning experience
for everyone.
I think the banners were
great and for some
of the presentation
sessions,
I think we could
have done better
if we made sure
we had enough time for
Q&A and discussions.
Hopefully, we can improve
on this next time.
Also, it would be
good if we can
summarize the main
actionable items from
this meeting that we think
the community should
consider going forward.
We would reach out
to some of you,
in particular,
panel chairs
to see how much
can be done there.
One last thing on Slack,
there were questions
about the availability
of the video recordings
and the slides.
The recording should
be available on
the event page
in 1-2 weeks,
and the slides will
also be made available
once we confirm with
the presenters.
With that and on behalf
of NDN Com co-chairs,
thanks again to all
the presenters,
panelists and moderators
and session chairs
and everyone
have a good rest
of your day. Bye
>> Last one for
the audience,
I'd like to say
that really
appreciates your
great work Lotfi,
for making this
NDN Com such a
great success. Thank you.
>> You're welcome.
>> For all your co-chairs.
>> Great. Thank you
everyone, again.
See you-all in the
next round of NDN Com.