>> Welcome back everyone.
In this session, we have
a panel on NDN's accessibility.
This is more of an informal panel,
so we don't have slides,
we are going to go around,
talk about what it means to be accessible,
what are the challenges
and how we can solve this.
For the panelists, we
have Alex from Clemson,
James from Air Force Research Lab, Christos,
University of Memphis,
Matthias from Berlin,
and then make Beichuan from
University of Arizona.
Welcome to the panel. Maybe we
can go around and
introduce ourselves to the audience.
Alex, you want to go first?
>> Yeah, sure. I'm, Alex Feltus.
I'm a professor at Clemson University
in the Department of Genetics
and Biochemistry.
I'm not network engineer.
We study plants and animals.
I just had a lab meeting
where we were talking
about how bean plants fix nitrogen
from the air and how
bone wasting disease might
be occurring genetically,
and also, we talked about how we can estimate
Cloud resource usage if we're to
run our workflows in the same lab meeting.
We're using NDN to try to aggregate data,
make a data lake to be able
to access all the genomes that had
been sequenced for anybody
that does any real Biology,
a lot of people use these datasets now.
>> Beichuan.
>> Hi, can you hear me okay?
>> Yes, we can hear you.
>> Thanks. I'm doing several mic checks.
I'm James Lyke,
I'm with the Air Force
Research Laboratory and I
work in Space Vehicle Development.
I'm very interested in
networking in a global sense
or spacecraft play a role in
facilitating the network connectivity.
I also have an adjunct professor
at the University in Mexico,
that's actually where I'm sitting today.
I think the interest we have in NDN is
using it in some way to help
facilitate an improvement in connectivity.
I think in some sense it has
interesting features
that we wanted to exploit.
I'm interested in more pervasive uses
in Department of Defense,
but then we have
also experienced some significant barriers.
I think it's that ossification that we hear
about with Internet technologies,
Internet protocols,
and some of those barriers are very
difficult and so in
research trying to figure out ways
to make the benefits of
NDN more accessible, more understood. Thanks.
>> Thank you. Beichuan,
do you want to go next?
>> Yeah, my name's Beichuan Zhang.
I'm a Professor of
Neuroscience Department,
University of Arizona.
I am a network researcher.
I have been working on NDN for last decade.
I'm not really a real-world user
of NDN for this panel,
but I can talk about
my group experience of
developing some applications
and the accessibility issues we ran
into and effort we're
trying to solve those issues,
but still they solve a problem,
so also very interesting.
Let's hear what other people
on this panel will say about that.
>> Thank you. Christos.
>> I'm Christos Papadopoulos,
I'm a professor at the University of Memphis,
also in Computer Science and
my background is also
networking like Beichuan.
I have been with the NDN
team since the beginning.
I spent a couple of years at
the HS as a program manager,
and that is where I got exposed
to things such as legal cybersecurity,
which I found really interesting,
and my interest after
that is seeing how to apply NDN
into legal communication and more
broadly into
the transportation infrastructure. Thanks.
>> Thank you, Christos. Matthias.