>> Good morning
everyone and welcome to
day 2 of the Indian
community meeting,
the 2023 end year income.
Today's agenda has as
the first item Session
4 on forwarding
and applications.
And the session has
three remote speakers.
The first speaker
is Tian Song,
who was a professor at
Beijing Institute
of Technology.
Tian, are you ready?
If you're already,
you can start
[OVERLAPPING]
>> Yes, I'm ready.
>> Share your slides
and you can go ahead.
>> Thank you. I'm glad
to have this opportunity
to present our work
about the iStack it's
actually work of
from my group.
We have three very
important guys seen
this work is my
students can
only and another
faculty getting here.
So our work is about
an in-Kernel networking
stack for India.
So we have
another title for
this talk about
implementation of
data networking.
What do we have and
what do they need?
Then use what's the
Indian community
country have,
and what's the future
way Indian community in
need to support
the deployment of
engine network.
So let's have
a quick review
on current and
then forwarders.
Since forwarders is
the real worker to say
that Indian can actually
take out an
important role.
So let's go back 10
years ago we have
the first version
of Indians sim.
Is actually over
the Season X.
So from that time,
I write the source code
overseas and hikes
and know that
all the Indian
architecture
is something like
interests and
there's pathways
and the dumping
and the very important,
and very interesting.
And in 2014,
so we have the NFV and
involved in daemon.
So at that time, my group,
one of my students
and I was involved
in the development of
an act, the
forwarding part.
That's a
collaborative work
of five universities
and then we have
a new version of
an exam over fd,
and we have Indian Lite
and the DPDK and
other forwarders.
So that's the path
important forwarders
of the past 10 years.
So what we want
to get is general-purpose
forwarder.
So let's take the
FT as an example,
is a general-purpose
software package
forwarder is
implemented in
C ++ language
, is very successful.
That we can use
it to support
the architectural
research and it's used
on public NDN
project testbed and
then several
applications that
demonstrated based on NFD.
So let's talk
about how NFD
provides the narrative for
applications that means,
especially how
the FD support
multiple applications
running over it.
So there's a sentence
say that communication
between NFD
and the local
application can be
done where the
Unix-domain.
So what's that
Unix-domain sockets,
supposedly have
network packets
and we have
already kernels.
Then the kernel
provides sockets,
NFD is designed and
implemented over socket.
So how do we support
multiple applications?
Use Unix-domain sockets
is inter-processing
communication way.
That's an IPC in the
application layer.
Like TCP, IP protocols,
the operating systems
use Berkeley socket.
They use the socket
applications
, create a socket,
and the kernel
corresponding create a sock
and the packets are
distinguished by port.
So TCP/IP and to go
through the kernel and
the distinguish
using ports
and go to each
applications.
So that's TCP/IP works.
Actually is a
kernel things.
So let's look other
typical forwarders
like Indian Riot.
Actually, real
operating systems,
since the system is
a microorganism,
is no kernel user
space that stuff.
So the packets are
passing cross-layer
is used through IPC.
So the first forwarder
actually using
application layer IPC to
classify the packets
to each applications.
And the Indian
Lite is a little
different since
it's lighter version
of forwarder.
It can only support
one application
each forwarder.
That means if you run
one forwarder it can only
support the web
applications,
that's something
like you can use it
as a router forwarding
applications,
but it cannot support
multiple applications.
Now then we go
to NDN and DPDK.
Actually, DPDK, the pack
target of the DPDK is for
extremely high
performance and
it bypass the
kernel stack,
DPDK bypass for
high-performance.
And it's very suitable for
single-task equipment
like routers.
But if consider the
generative for
applications,
I think Indian DPDK is
a little difficult.
And then we have
YaNFD is similar.
The only difference is
the implementation
language, if called so.
So it also use
application layer way
to distinguish packets.
So let's discuss
this problem.
I think this question.
So all modern
operating system
actually implement
a version of
the Berkeley
socket interface,
and use this framework
to organize the packets
and the upper layer
applications.
Then why I've provide
another application
layer-level solution
imbedded into the kernel.
So I guess there may be
two packets, maybe speed.
So if we bypass
the kernel,
we can think that the new
version how to
higher performance.
But however, if
we use application-level
solution,
we also involve that
the overhead of
Unix-domain sockets.
Actually, it also can
film the complexity of
computing it cannot
maybe achieve that
high-speed unless
way bypass
the kernel totally
using DPDK.
And then maybe try
to think that NDN
is targeted for
a big story like I think
currently runs over
many protocols
like TCP/UDP/IP.
So you use current,
the socket mechanism,
and the using the
logic of phase
2 over that protocols.
Also, I have the
account over
Ethernet directly by using
the [inaudible]
have some way
of packets capturing.
So if we think
that Indian is
tagged for big star.
And that's okay.
If NDAs is designed as
a network protocol,
it should be run directly
on the link layer.
That should be the way
like network
protocol does.
So why we need
another forwarder.
So we seek
a general purpose
networking protocol stack
and it is expected to
be a three targets.
That's general
that is flexible.
That means many
applications has shared
this forwarder with
different purpose
using a same Canvas,
API or programming models.
And the second one is that
this networking forwarder
should be secure.
That means it
should be achieved
system-level
security since it
should be embedded
in the system.
>> The current kernel
stack like TCP,
IP kernel run as
kernel threads
that's protected by
the operating systems.
So there should be
another NDN forwarder
that should embed in
the kernel to gain
the OS protection.
And also, we try to
push NDN forwarder
kernel's reuse.
That means we should
integrate the folder
into the development
of operating system.
That means the
non-working parts should
be distributed along
with operating system.
That's long term evolution
with operating system,
that should be
integration.
So that's why we
consider that we
should take NDN,
this protocol into
operating system
, not over it.
So we proposed an
in-kernel NDN stack.
We try to design an
in-kernel NDN stack,
but we have to face the
following challenges.
The first one is that NDN
is entirely
based on names.
That means consider
the speed,
we should classify packets
with the variable and
unlimited last names.
While the TCP/IP use
IP is short addresses.
And we have to
use the names,
especially name prefix
to classify the packets,
to relate those packets
to each application
requirements.
So that's a flag complex
and also computing
consuming.
And the second one is that
NDN is a stateful
data plane.
If we embed it
into the kernel,
we have to face the
first performance issues
that a stateful data plane
is hard to achieve
line speed.
And also the stateful
data plane will keep
track of each
interests and
data packets that
state behavior.
And that state
behavior is very
leak from the
perspective of security.
So we have to gain
the kernel level isolation
for that security
requirements concern.
And also, we have
to consider to pull
the content store
as a memory
into the OS kernel,
or search the kernel.
But no matter what
kind of your design,
you have to inject
some memory into
the kernel design.
That may be a challenge
for the kernel,
that since kernel regards
the networking stack
should maintain
no memories,
no memory can
store that size.
And the third challenge
is the programming model.
Since the current TCP/IP
is okay to use
the session way
to organize this
programming.
But any user name
or continent
way to do that,
that's different.
So we consider to
solve the old above
the challenges and taken
into this kernel weight
proposed the iStack.
So what is iStack?
Let's go back to review
the hourglass
architecture first.
That's the beginning
of the NDN to say,
NDN is very good to
maybe correspond
to IP protocols.
Maybe 10 years
ago, I first to
know this graph and
then to know NDN
architecture.
And then let's go back to
the current NFD and
other forwarders.
So what they arrived.
The red line is
the separation
of the user space and
kernel space in an
operating systems.
And the current
that NFD forwarder,
and then maybe the
most important
forwarders we
have is running in
the user space,
actually over socket.
And some of forwaders can
over ethernet by using
packet capturing,
is bypass sockets and
directly over
the ethernet.
But it's not inside
the kernel way,
not go down but bypass
all over sockets.
That's what way
the current forwarders
have designed.
We say that these overlay
design over the socket.
No, I didn't say
overlay protocols,
is overlays sockets.
But iStack is different.
We design iStack
as incrinal stack,
that means the
iStack totally
run within the
kernel space.
And also is directly over
link layer and it
connect to the
upper layer,
we use the iSocket.
We define a socket
primitive programming
model to support
the application design and
all these from
the link layer
to the upper layer,
we use iStack totally.
We didn't use
any TCP/IP and
the iStack merged inside
the current berkeley
sulfated framework.
And it's also
compatible to
the current
socket framework.
So that's the brief
design of iStack.
So there are some novel
design philosophies.
We all know that
we have interface
to connect NDN layer
with other layers.
So we separate
the phase system
from one phase into
lower one and upper one.
And lower one to link
the link layer protocols,
and the upper one is to
support the
application socket.
And then we use
the Netlink sockets
to configure
our forwarding
information table,
and also we designed
all the passes to
make it workable and
compatible in the
kernel system.
So that's the
iStack design.
So this kernel one
is iStack is entirely
based on names.
So we didn't use anything
like a pass, no pass.
We use the name
prefix to distinguish
the packets and
connecting with
the applications.
We also provide
a socket-like
programming model.
That's another
story of our work.
So that's
programming model
for different
philosophy of how to
use the kernel using
content way, not
session way.
So we also have
another design choice
considered, like using
Maggie's writing to
support high-performance.
We catch data package
directly in kernel and
other kernels with several
here of the kitchen story.
And then also we designed
some open API for
events for the
general purpose to
make it practical
for real use.
>> One minute left.
>> So we have deployed
some prototypes
based on iStack.
So we implemented
in Linux kernel,
and we tested it,
iStack currently achieved
over 5 gigabits per
second report over
10 gigabit link without
any optimization.
We test it on
software router,
personal computer and
the Raspberry Pi,
that kind of hardware.
We also deployed
the iStack
as a Wi-Fi router,
and we designed
iGate gateway
to transfer the
NDN protocol and
IP protocol to
make it merged
as separate NDN
edges together.
That iGate is another
story of our group.
And they also have
this early work.
And also we deploy
some prototypes or
iStack using IoT device.
So we tried to give
a long-term evolution
support to the iStack.
And this year we tried to
launch the website and
the gateway
initial version
and we try to use
it for real products
in the next year.
So that's my
talk. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Tian.
Let's see. Monitoring
the stack,
I don't see questions
from stack,
any question from
the audience?
>> Very nice
talk. Thank you.
So is this a kernel
module that's
loaded dynamically or
how does [OVERLAPPING].
>> Yes, this kind of
kernel module
underloaded as
a network stack. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> And you mentioned
some prototypes,
did you done performance
tests and see
how it performs compared
to NFT and another
forwarders?
>> Actually, we done that,
but since it's
not a [NOISE]
>> Connection issue
looks like again and so
we'd probably have to
continue on the
Slack channel,
we've the general
question of in
Kernel versus bypass
the performance
comparisons,
whether he has done
any benchmarking
can be addressed on
the Slack channel.
So we can move to
the next remote speaker
for this second
presentation,
we're moving along Teng,
we can continue the
discussion online
and we're moving to
the second speaker
in this session.
Teng Liang on bringing
name data networking
to InternetLivestreaming,
Teng start sharing
your screen
while I introduce you.
>> Yes, can you here me?
>> Yeah, we can hear you,
so start sharing while
I introduce you,
Teng Liang is working in
banks Shang lab as an
assistant researcher,
he received his PhD from
the University of Arizona
under the supervision of
Beichuan Zhang and he has
been doing research in
the end since 2014.
Go ahead, Teng
you can start.
>> Thank you for
introduction.
Hi everyone my name
is Teng Liang,
today I'm going to
introduce our work,
bringing the data network
into Internetlive
streaming.
So what is the
biggest obstacle
to ICN or Indian
deployment?
One of which probably
is lacking our
applications
support actually
yesterday many people
do care about it and
discuss about it.
And one solution maybe is
to NDNize applications
which proposed in
ICN'18 and which means to
translate between
existing application
level protocols in NDN.
And why we're
going to do that,
because it only requires
minor development efforts,
but gaining significant
architectural benefits.
And in 2018, we built
mailSync which can
toll existing email
applications over NDN,
we also made designs
for chat applications.
And behind them are
IMAP protocols and
XMPP protocol,
which has the NDN.
And in 2020,
Chavush in University
of Arizona,
he builds this
iViSA which is
on-demand video
streaming over
NDN and he actually
translates a DASH and NDN.
Last year, we built
on top of his work,
we move one step further,
we just make
this on-demand
video into live streaming
and behind them
we translate
HLS and NDN and also
LL-HLS and NDN,
this refers to low
latency protocol.
So what is this
PCLive and NDNized
Internets Live
streaming architecture?
As you can see here,
this is existing
livestreaming producer
over IP and they
publish video streaming to
a server normally an
existing protocol
called RTMP.
And the video server
has a transcoder
which will
translate our RTMP
into HLS files,
there could be
other protocols,
so then the server
will distribute
to the files,
the videos, to the network
and all work
stuff from here.
We will translate
the HLS files
into NDN format and
published like
Ronnie thing or
NDN producer and publishes
it to an NDN network,
so here we will have
the Indian package and
we'll publish it to
our NDN network.
On the consumer side,
there's the existing
video player and we use
shocker player
that's Shaka was
used as created
by Google and
it will use HLS protocols
to retrieve data,
which is HLS request and
response and
basically it's
just a HTTP GET and
there's a response.
So the good
thing is when we
translate this into
NDN is very simple,
we just trusted
request response into
the NDN's interests
data format.
And to summarize it we can
see on the producer side,
there's data
translation what we
summarized and on
the customer side
there is communication
translation,
there are some very
common designs.
And also, as you can see,
we reused many
existing modules,
but we are able to run
it over NDN network,
that's what we mean, only
requires minor
development efforts.
And for the
evaluation part,
we actually have the
real-world deployment
that experiment were
built and little NDN
over a testbed as the
NDN testbed does,
we run NFDs over
Alibaba Cloud in
seven different cities
with UDP tunnels
connected and here's
the top project.
We have the PC
live producer
connected to the Shenzhen
node to published
the video.
And because it's very
similar to the
IP architecture,
we used many modules,
we compare it with
IP live streaming.
So in the IP architecture,
we can support 21 clients
because way the PCLive
outgoing bandwidth is
roughly about 50 Mbps
and for NDN we have
different clients connect
to different nodes
and we can support
83 clients,
this does not even reach
the theoretical limit and
we didn't even mention to
test how fast or
how many more
clients NDN can
support but just to show,
there's some benefits
like in every ocation,
we didn't even mentioned
other benefits
like affording
or security.
So this is what we
meant we can gain
some architectural
benefits by doing
this, so what's next?
We're also studied
low-latency HLS.
>> And also we analyze
a little bit why
everything seems
very simple,
but actually it is
a receiver driven
protocol to achieve
adaptive bitrate
video streaming.
And how does it
actually work?
So to summarize,
step 1, they will
periodically poll
the playlist.
And step 2, if
the previous
tell me there
are new items,
it has their names, you
will retrieve them.
This is the reason
why this transformation
is very simple.
And low latency was not
the primary goal in
the first place.
To re-throw the CAD file
extensions on top of
HLS to make it
low latency.
And that's what
we are interested
in to see if we can
endianness them easily.
To analyze it,
so we summarize
the extensions
into two different
categories.
And the first one they're
targeting is BLock
Playlist Reload,
basically means they
will hold on
the request for
the prettiest article they
expected previously
is generated,
then you send back.
And the second one
basically means that
we will hold the
requests for
the expected video chunks
article they
are generated.
And the third one is still
provides the
Delta updates.
To analyze them on
the consumer side,
we just need to add
conditions to request.
The field is called
interests parameters.
We just say you don't
need to send back data,
would drop them if
there's no data
generated because
we expect
them degenerative soon.
On the producer side,
they will hold other
requests and wait
until the data
is generated
and send back directory.
So the key is
the word hold on
the interest until the
data is generated,
which actually saves
a time of pulling.
And one constraints,
this will leave
some states
on the path in
the networking.
But because this
is live streaming,
so those states won't stay
long so that's why
we can actually
use this strategy.
And there are two
other extensions.
That's our
application specific.
Why? Is they actually
generates smaller
video chunks.
And the other
one is they have
provided the
orientation reports.
And to internalize
them is very simple.
We actually have smaller
application layer unit
with naming changes.
And the second
one does not
even need to
change anything.
And for this, we also
do more evaluation.
We have the
similar structure.
And on the right side
there is a publisher push
the video using RTMP to
a video transporter,
will use GPAC,
this open source
framework,
because it
supports LL HLS.
And the changes
were made that way,
didn't change all
of the extensions.
Where only for
the extension to
hold on the interest until
upcoming data is ready.
And for the video size,
segment size from four
second to 0.56 second.
That's essential four,
and the proper size is set
to three videos elements.
And the result is
the point of capture
to playback latency
decreases from 20,
about 27 seconds
to 3.5 seconds.
There are still rules if
we tune the parameters.
So that's about work.
The last, this is
from Van's paper.
He made the observation.
I've read similar
arguments in other papers,
basically seeing
applications,
retrieved data,
but today's network,
just create tunnels.
There's gap. An NDN design
should fill the gap.
If this is true,
actually many modern
application
level protocols,
they actually should
be easily translated
or supported by NDN
because they retrieved,
and NDN also does it.
And also, isn't
it our work a good
proof of this argument?
So that's the end of
my presentation.
Thank you.
>> Thank you very much.
There are a couple of
questions from Slack.
One is, did you
quantify the
computational cost of
signing plus
verification and
its effect on latency?
>> Actually, we
didn't do that yet.
We do have plans,
but because one reason
is that the
content right now,
is not that's
very sensitive.
We do not have anything
to protect that,
at least for the
current stage.
So we didn't evaluate the
sign-in part for now.
When we have a dummy key
to do some fake signing,
just the current state
of the whole purpose is to
demonstrate the thing is
immunization
approach can work.
In future work we did that
for the signing as
well as for the
encryption.
>> Okay. I think by doing
the ionization
versus rewriting
the application
as an NDN Native,
you're losing anything
from NDN advantages
[OVERLAPPING] in terms of
adaptive forwarding
security performance-wise,
do you lose anything by
doing the translation
versus rewriting native
Indian application?
>> Yeah, that's a
very good question.
At least for the
live streaming,
I haven't observed any
sacrifice too far.
But maybe in other
application programs
because one thing
is we only did
the translation for the
communication part,
that means there are
some logics were still
follow more than the
application logics.
If they're
designed perfect,
we don't sacrifice
anything.
But if they are
not designed well,
maybe there are
something we cannot get.
But so far for this
specific case,
I didn't find anything.
>> Another question
from Slack.
Why is NDN HTTP
live streaming slower
than pure HLS?
I don't know
whether that was
in your presentation.
Did you notice
that it's slower?
>> Which one
is for, sorry?
>> NDN HLS versus
non-NDN HLS?
>> NDN HLS. Is
this slower?
[OVERLAPPING]
>> Maybe on Slack,
why isn't the NHLS or
slower than pure HLS?
I don't know whether
that was in your table.
It was lower speed.
>> You can mean the
throughput or which one?
>> Yeah, throughput,
reading from
the Slack channel
in your table.
[OVERLAPPING]
>> So for this one,
maybe there's some I
didn't experience
very accurately.
This throughput
doesn't mean
the whole throughput.
This means the
bottlenecked throughput.
For the IP, the
bottleneck is,
happens at the server.
So everyone retrieved
from the server.
And the server called
choline throughput has
only about 50 mbps limit.
So we need to roughly
reach out that we
cannot add new clients
because it reaches
throughput.
This throughput 33 mbps,
it happens on
the Edge Node.
Different clients
like each
node we connect to
about seven or eight
clients to each node
and because of the
built-in multicast
and an in-network
question,
they will not aggregate
you that the server.
So the server side,
there's only one
string outgoing,
there's no bottleneck.
But on different nodes,
there will be
the bottleneck.
And what we'll observe
is their bottleneck,
the maximum is 33
mb per [inaudible].
So that actually
shows the NDN,
we can achieve,
serve more kinds
with smaller
bottlenecks, throughput.
>> Okay, Thanks.
>> Do you use NFD to
support the video
or transfer?
>> Yeah, right
now, we use NFD,
we run NFD on
different nodes,
we connected the
producer to the one NFD.
>> So is the 33
megabits per
second bottleneck due to
NFDs performance
bottleneck
or something else?
>> I don't think this
is NFDs bottleneck.
On the nodes, we
rinse the clouds,
virtual machines
are clouds.
This may not be
the bottleneck,
we may add more clients
to support that,
but we just
didn't do that.
The bottleneck of NFD is
just during one test,
we add 83 clients
and we observed
the maximum
from one node is 33.
>> So if you add
more clients,
the edge node throughput
will be higher than 33?
>> For some reason, if
we add more clients,
their video quality,
some of them will
decrease very badly,
we didn't find why,
so to make a fair
comparison at this number,
at every client, they have
very good video quality
during the testing.
If we add more the
quality decreases,
but we didn't know why.
Is it because of NFD?
Or just because
some other reasons.
I cannot conclude,
it's because of
NFD, that's why.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you Teng.
There're a couple
of more on Slack,
you can go and
answer those,
and we move to
the next speaker,
Mohammed Elbadry.
Thanks Teng.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very
much. Next speaker,
Mohammed Elbadry, and
you start sharing
your screen.
The next talk on, towards
first data centric medium
access control,
multi-rate control.
Mohammed is a fifth year
PhD student in
Stony Brook,
under a professor
Ye supervision,
is main research
focus area is
developing a wireless
MAC for ICN.
He has developed systems
on edge devices like
raspberry *** to be easily
usable by the
research community.
Mohammed are you ready?
>> Yes, thank
you very much.
Can you hear me okay?
>> Yeah, go ahead, please.
>> I'll start.
Hi everyone,
thanks for letting me
present the Indian
community today.
So I'm about to introduce
a multicast rate
control design,
and this work is
ongoing right now,
and I want to
introduce what we've
done and what the
big picture is.
So right now we're
trying to make ICN,
we're trying to see
how ICN and can
be more of an enabling
technology on edge.
So imagine you have an
edge computing nodes
that has wireless dongle,
and that has
multiple sensors.
So imagine a video camera,
lidar, infrared camera,
and a couple of
IMU sensors,
accelerometer,
magnetometer
and other sensors.
And wants to
share that data,
over wireless to
multiple nodes,
so node 1,2,3,4 are
interested in the data.
They're all interested
in video stream,
for example, that could be
live or just a video file.
For the content
to be played
real-time by nodes 1,2,3,
and 4, week during
the transmission,
we need the
following criteria.
We need the loss
rate to be under
20% and the goodput to be
above 5 Mbps or
else there's going to be
a buffering duration,
it's like you're
watching YouTube video,
and it's just
going to keep
buffering over
and over again.
So the edge computing
node, for example,
selects a random
data was 54 Mbps,
and all nodes are happy,
everyone is
receiving data,
last rate is on 20 Mbps.
And the goodput
is about 5 Mbps,
so all nodes are happy.
The medium changes,
node 1 is unhappy
because the loss
rate increases,
let's say it goes
above to 35 Mbps.
So the computing node to
accommodate that
loss rate increase,
will decrease its
data rate to 36 Mbps,
and by decreasing
data rate,
that increase wireless
transmission resilience,
so that basically node
1 can receive the data,
and everyone is
happy for now.
But imagine
another scenario
where basically
node 2 medium
that's so much worse
that for it to be
good on loss rate,
so it can achieve
under 20% loss rate,
it needs 3 Mbps data rate
from edge computing nodes.
Basically that's
not going to
work too well
because essentially
that can impact node 1,3
and 4 because they
need minimum of
goodput of 5 Mbps
to be able to
continue playing
the video live.
So essentially what
should happen as
the computing
node abandons
node number 2 and say,
you're basically
requirements to
satisfy you while
satisfying everyone else,
it's too much, and we're
not going to be able to
continue
transmitting to you.
So what I just
explained is,
that scenario is
a big picture
of what we're
trying to do.
Essentially multi cast
rate control
communication,
where you have multiple
nodes interested in
the same data
over wireless,
and each of them
has different needs
and application has
certain requirements
for loss rate
and goodput to
perform properly.
So how does
existing wireless
technology do it,
and what exists right now?
Existing wireless
technology
is only a unicast,
meaning one receiver,
one transmitter.
So as you can see
on the right side,
there is node
1 and node 2.
The way it works
is that the
transmitter sends
a data frame,
say at 54 Mbps,
receiver sends an
acknowledgment
and you keep doing,
and if no ACK is received,
essentially if you send
the data frame and
doesn't get through
acknowledged,
the node 1 sends the
thing data frame again,
at lower data rate
and see if it gets
acknowledged.
And based on that,
an algorithm
based on history
decides if it
should stick to
the data rate
or attempt to
increase the data
rate or lower it.
So if 24 Mbps
is gaining knowledge
every time,
that algorithm
could try to
transmit at a
higher data rate,
to see if we can
perform well as
well, to increase
the goodput.
Couple of notes
to note about
the scenario and
how it works,
there is an
exploratory phase,
the costs multiple
initial packets,
so basically this start,
usually low
conservative and
keep going up until
packets are getting
lost and then they go down
and go up again and
so forth until good
data rate is reached.
It's an address space
station structure,
so basically for
this to happen,
node 1 keeps station
structure inside
the kernel,
and MAC address
keeps success rate,
the size of the packets,
or low information
to adjust the data rate.
And address-based
communication is
established for long term,
so what that means is that
you know who
the station is,
you know the MAC
address, and you
communicate for
a long time,
so imagine pretty much
how it works with
your laptop or
any edge device or
anything connected
over Wi-Fi,
you connect to an
access point and you
mean for tens of
minutes to hours.
So now the access point
and your computer have
pretty much
hours or minutes
to figure out what the
optimal data rate is.
If we would apply this
instead of being
address-based to
make content-based
really control,
how would it work?
Though the challenges
that we faced
was content-based
rate control,
are the following:
data packets are too
short to adapt to
data rate based on,
by the time the
optimal rate
is found for a
data packet,
the data packet
may be complete,
so as we said earlier,
it takes about ten to 15
packets or could take
even more than
20 data frames
to find the
optimal data rate,
that's enough data
frame transmission
that a whole data
packet could be gone,
by the time you
find the optimal
data rate for that packet.
The other problem
is that we need
an alternative
feedback mechanism
because all the
existing mechanism
is only for unicast
one-to-one.
Meanwhile, ICN
supports multi cast,
which is one-to-many,
so we need an aggregate
mechanism that
allows consumer
with the most need and
can be saved, go first.
When I say be saved,
as in the first example
we just demonstrating
the first slide,
node 2, needed three Mbps,
but that will degrade
everyone's performance,
so we just
dropping node 2.
We have an existing system
that we developed
called vMac,
and part of it is a DACK,
a developed multi cast
feedback mechanism,
but the issue with
that system or
using that protocol as is,
it's basically
the worst-performing
consumer report.
That's not exactly what
we're trying to do here,
we're trying to do the
worst-performing consumer
that can be saved
through reports,
so we have to modify
that system as well.
And also we need a
faster conversion
to the optimal data rate,
given the edge needs
and loose communication,
by content-based
communication, adjusting
data rate needs to
operate much quicker.
>> So this is
where we introduce
our multicast
control design
to solve these problems.
We designed the
highest and maintain
current entry adjustments.
We call it a stream,
which is a group of
data packets or
cheer the set of
consumers locally
and temporarily.
And that can
be for example
a file that contain
multiple data packets.
So a string can
be the farming.
So imagine a video file
that's 100 megabytes,
that'll have multiple data
ICMP packets will
use this file name,
the stream name locally
and temporarily
to just transmit
the data and adjust
the data rate for
the whole string
instead of for
each data packet,
figure out the
optimal database.
The other thing
we tried to
do is basically
distributed,
loosely coordinated
backoff feedback.
We call it our dad.
We're basically
knows who's optimal
feedback information
representing all nodes,
report feedback on
behalf of all consumers.
Because if you
have 4-5 consumers
and every frame
transmitted,
you get five
acknowledgment that
was basically cost
too much overhead,
its transmission is not
going to work well.
And the last thing
that I want to talk
more about them
folks to talk about
introduced as
multi-dimensional
rate control
adjustment procedure.
We've done a lot of
empirical experiments
and extensive data
collection to
figure out how we
can actually get
the data rates selection
to work faster.
So that way we can
actually get there faster.
So we started looking at
how does transmission
rate change,
how does Wi-Fi
retrenchment
retransmission
change over time?
So there are a few
parameters that Wi-Fi
changes that we have
to choose from.
So there's a
digital modulation,
which are changes
in amplitude and
frequency to K
analog signals.
So the different kinds of
modulation we
have is BPSK,
QPSK, QAM16, 64 and 256.
The other option
is coding rate.
We're only a portion
of the best change
with every word slot.
There is hardcoding,
3/4, 5/6.
There's guard
interval and it's
intended to avoid signal
loss from multipath.
Essentially it's
400 nanoseconds
or 800 nanoseconds,
and that's the
space between
each sample and other end,
the Wi-Fi wireless
transmission.
Bandwidth, it's basically
the capacity of the link
to transmit over
the channel.
There is 20 mhz,
408-16-0480
plus 1800s of space
in between them.
And their spatial stream,
essentially
spatial stream as
the transmission
technique used in
MIMO wireless
communication
to transmit independent,
separately coded data
signals amagine,
essentially it's
where exactly it's
two different streams
at the same time.
There's one, two
spatial streams,
and as such, they're up
to three or four as well.
So what that corresponds
to is this big table.
I found it everywhere.
You can find it to 11 AC,
very high transmission
rate table.
And you can see basically
are five dimensions
of options.
We have the modulation.
So you can see over
here under the circle,
these are different
modulations.
You have coding grades.
These are also options.
You have the guard
interval for
100 and 800 nanoseconds.
You have the bandwidth,
any other spatial stream.
And that corresponds
to all of
these possible options
of the iterates to
choose from that
basically based on
the environment
and based on the
consumer's you're
sending through,
there's an optimal choice
among these choices that
corresponds to the
best performance
in terms of loss rate
aims throughputs.
So we end up with 212
options that we have
to select in pretty
much quarter of
a millisecond
because we're
transmitting a
lot of frames
back-to-back and
we have to decide
for each frame basis
how data-rich for that
train, pretty much.
So we started asking
these questions,
which is, how does
changing each parameter
affect loss rate?
And basically we started
just with that question
and we set up
an experiment,
set up Raspberry Pi's
is 802.11 ac dongles.
And we use the costume
mode V-max module,
clean slate kernel module
that we built that
has no beacon or
any transmission,
just the data frames.
And then we send
data frames
for each data rate
back-to-back.
So we basically
transmitted
all the possible
data rates
that you saw over here,
back-to-back, same
frame size in
the same environment
so we can see
how it performs over time.
And this is one of
the sample of
outcomes that we got.
We have a lot of data
extensively collected.
But you can see the
x-axis is data rate,
the y-axis is
the loss rate.
And as you can see,
dairy does not
correlate with
lawsuit as you go the
higher data rate,
it doesn't always
mean you're
going to have
higher loss rate.
As you can see,
around 100 Mbps
is higher data rate,
higher loss rate than 200
Mbps certain data
rate combination.
Well, we also
found is that
some high data rates have
lower loss rate than
other of low data rate.
And if you can see
that line highlighted,
we can actually see
that it's just a
very small subset of
all the choices are
usable in that
environment.
The rest of the data
rates are actually
not good for the
environment.
They're not
helping at all.
So we start asking
more questions.
If data rate does not
correlate the loss rate,
which parameter actually
impacts loss rate.
And we started doing
more analysis.
And what we have
found so far is that
the painless
and short guard
interval actually did not
impact loss rate to
any collective
environment.
Just FYI for
data collection,
we've done 10 locations
that have current date,
one transmitter
and four receivers
24 hours of experiments
to research labs five
homes and three
corporate officers.
And so we have these
two is the actual
apartments.
And we have roughly
about 100,000 packets
transmitted in each
of these environments
over the span of 24 hours.
A lot of traces that
we've collected.
So what we ended up doing
after doing some
analysis further
is that we found
the cross dimensional
candidate set.
So basically we
were able to rank
loss rate impact
from highs to lows.
And we found a modulation
has the highest
impact on loss rate
and then spatial
stream and then
coding on guard
interval and bandwidth.
So what that means is
that if you change
the guard interval to
be shorter and change
your coding to
be 5/6 instead of 1/2,
you're increasing
the data rate
without actually
increasing the loss rate.
You're getting
essentially free
data rates speed.
Changing the modulation
is very risky.
So essentially we ended up
from 200 something to
70 something data
rates we ended up with
20 only option that are
just the ladder
of up and down.
And that enabled us,
if we go further,
is that we basically
simple up and down
exploration process
quicker conversion
in optimal data
rate candidates.
And also we now
prevent getting stuck
in local maximum.
So if you can see if
you're testing up and
down and just all
the data results.
If you go up and
down and go to
the 100 Mbps options,
you're searching as
the data loss rate
is increasing,
let me now go higher
any data rate.
It should be worse.
Meanwhile, do not
really worse.
You just dropped
together. So based
on these results and
things we have tried,
we have tried different
frame sizes from
200 bytes to 6,000 bytes.
And usually a frame
size is 1,400 bytes.
That's usually data frame
by 802.11 standard,
we have tried different
distances up to
their maximum
limit line of
sight and not
line of sight.
We've also tried
multiple frames
back-to-back and
single frames
per data rate,
got similar
results, only 2%,
pretty much standard
deviation and loss rate.
We also have tried
different network
interface cards.
We experimented
with a 802.11
dongles 802.1 ac.
Very much the same
results again.
So right now part of
our ongoing work,
it's finalizing aggregate
feedback protocol
to enable the
consumer with
highest needs that
can be saved without
impacting other
consumers go first,
implemented new
clean slate system
on 802.11 ac.
We have a new
kernel module from
scratch that lemonades,
TCPIP stack,
all that stuff
and just uses on
content-base.
We have either integration
hugs for NFD as well,
that we're integrating
right now.
And we're originating
more results in
different environments and
cooperating system
with V-MAC.
So in conclusion,
we just covered
the multicast rate
control problem
in data centric paradigm.
We introduce a new
design that relies on
content or
just free control
leveraging stream.
And we showed our results
for in-depth analysis for
rotatory Panthers
impact on
loss rate. Thank you.
>> Thank you very much.
Any questions from
the audience?
Otherwise I
was going to ask
a quick question.
>> I just asked
you in person.
I don't feel there's
enough information
about your test set up.
You mentioned about
the frame size
doesn't make
much difference.
Is that it just
a one stream,
or it's actually multiple
competing streams,
because that's
going to have
interference and
other streams today.
>> So what we
actually did,
the transmitter
was one stream
transmitting frames
back-to-back,
but it was
environments that
had already ongoing
transmission.
So that's why we tested
in different environments.
We tested in
research labs,
homes and corporate
officers that are active.
So that way there
was interference,
there was a
multi-pass loss
and all of these cases,
but we did not
artificially
create interference.
>> And in different
frame sizes,
we tried different
because different
frame sizes
have different
medium time.
So we wanted to see if it
will cause different loss.
If it takes longer, but
it didn't affect the
loss rate that much.
>> Mohammed, you
expect the loss
to increase with
the rate. Right?
>> That's correct.
>> In short, you're
saying the local maxima.
Did you see that from
experimentation?
What's your intuition if
it's not monotonically
increasing?
>> The reason behind
it is that when we
increase the data rate,
we're not increasing
one ladder,
is that it's actually
five dimensions.
And the intuition behind
is that I can't believe
that all of these
are linearly
increasing with data rate,
because each of
these impact
lost data rate
differently.
But we didn't know
if data rate correlates
linearly as loss rate.
So we started
actually testing each
of these parameter
individually.
So we found out which ones
actually impact loss rate,
and which ones don't
impact the loss rate.
And just to also
address this,
we only tested
this statically.
Then that affects the
channel coherence time.
When we test this
in mobility,
I believe that the results
will be different,
but right now
we're only tested
for static environment.
>> All right.
Thanks. We can
continue in Slack if there
are more questions.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much.
And we are on time to
start the Panel 2,
on named data metaverse,
which will be chaired
by the Dirk Kutscher,
who's a professor at
Hong Kong University of
Science and Technology,
he is remote.
And four panelists.
Jeff Burke from UCLA
Remark, he's local.
And the three remote
panelists that
Dirk will introduce.
Dirk, are you ready?
>> Yes. Thank
you very much
Luffy. Can you
see my slides?
>> Yes, we do. Go ahead.
>> Right. Thank
you. Welcome to
the panel session
on data metaverse.
Unfortunately I
cannot be with
you in Rockwood today.
But anyway, great to be
discussing with you.
Thanks also to NIST
for organizing this event,
also for the very
good preparation and
hybrid infrastructure
works really well.
So named data metaverse.
So I'm actually currently
at this location here.
In this metaverse
and knock-up,
I have to say,
was my office,
it's a bit darker
at the moment.
It's midnight.
So metaverse is an
interesting topic,
and you can look
at it from different
perspectives.
And I think that's what
we're going to do today.
So there's was a
really nice blog
posting by Benedict Evans
on ways to think
about metaverse.
And so what he laid out
there was there're
two perspectives.
So one is the rather
broad perspective
on conceiving
metaverse as
data technology
that changes everything,
the way we work, the way
we consume media
and so on.
So may be similar to
the information
superhighway.
So vague idea,
with lots of
potential that will
change everything.
Of course, it's
quite inspiring.
The other way to
think about it
is maybe a bit narrower.
That's maybe what the
networking people
in the room would
normally use.
And we'd say, you
know there's a bunch
of technologies,
there is some
progress in hardware.
And if you combine this,
we have the next
evolutionary step
in the way we work with
the web, so to speak.
And metaverse would
be the evolution
of what we currently
consider as the web.
And there's probably
a healthy middle
ground here,
but you probably have
thought about this,
because it's a
very hyped term,
very broad, and
people understand
different things when
they use the term.
And in fact, when you
look at applications,
you could probably make
a nice taxonomy of
different types
of applications.
So like virtual
meeting systems,
this 3D avatars
or something.
Pokeman Go virtual
reality mobile games.
Maybe they say a
bit more ambitious.
Hyper-Reality vision
by Keiichi Matsuda
is a bit more futuristic.
But also all the
gaming aspect in
metaverse are
probably also
of relevance and also
interesting to consider
in this context.
And I didn't mention
other things
like digital
twins and so on
that also often
included in this.
In networking perspective,
so that's where most of
the people in the
room are coming from.
So there are some
interesting aspects.
So we are blending,
for example,
interactive real-time
with video-on-demand,
and was rather strict
latency requirements.
We're doing this
not only for 2D
but also for 3D content.
There could be
other ways how we
use the network,
so that could
be potentially
significantly more
upstream data
than downstream
data volume.
So if she consider new
video technologies.
And we have what
we always try to
achieve with IP
multicast in the past.
So we've
potentially larger
user groups with also
really diverse endpoint
and creativity
characteristics.
So this raises the
bar a little bit for
the technology stack that
we used to work with.
And that alone provides
interesting challenges
and also good potential
for innovation.
And then when
you're coming from
maybe ICN or
NDN background,
you could say, okay,
there's actually
really good potential
for our technology.
So we could now
for example employ
multi-pass forwarding
strategies
or implicit
multi-destination delivery,
maybe some better
replication strategies.
Caching, we could
optimize caching.
>> Some people
in our community
have been thinking
about how
to integrate computing
in NDN systems,
maybe leverage the vector
name data access approach
also for maybe
addressing functions
or services.
So I think many people
would agree that
there is also
really interesting
optimization potential
by the fact that you have
a bit more visibility,
bit more leverage on
how you use the
network resources.
And you can treat
these resources in
a bit more general way
include caching
and computing.
And so there's lots
of interesting things
that will be intuitively
could identify and could
probably also work on.
But then there are also
additional
potential elements.
So for example for
metaverse applications
often have
to also do it with
creating things.
Now if the
question is, who
owns these things?
How do you maybe
do transcoding or
transformation or
insertion in a secure way.
Maybe verifiability
and corresponding
trust infrastructures.
So when you talk
about assets
that people own,
would like to transfer or
things that
people could use.
So the question is, how do
you model this
transaction,
how do you financialize
these things?
And another
question is also,
if you would use data,
or produce content, and
you get compensated.
If you share,
produce efficient
infrastructure,
can you get
compensated for that?
So this decentralized
distributed
communication and
computing story.
And maybe depending on
where you come from,
you may have different
perspectives
on the technology stack.
So in terms of what
features should be in
this technology stack and
how would you actually
fluctuate it?
How would you
separate it into
different maybe stacks
or technology areas?
So what we are all
familiar with,
it's the current
overlay approach where
we can assume a
relatively simple
Internet forwarding.
So in order to
achieve many of
the features that we need
for continuous
evolution but
also for live
media streaming.
We need increasingly
extensive CDN networks.
We are seeing now
data related
concepts in the,
not overlap in the
overlay [LAUGHTER].
So things like media
over QUIC for example,
it's quite
interesting to see
what's going on there.
But we also know like from
an ICN and the
N perspective,
that these things cannot
say provide the
same level of,
say, network optimization
of foreboding optimization
than compared to a
packet level ICN system.
So in NDN we
would say, Okay,
we assume some underlay,
maybe at least underlay,
a two underlay.
But in general, we have
a more powerful
forwarding layer
that can do more
useful things,
date for forwarding
strategies,
hashing, and so on.
And so we build network on
the approach
of accessing named
data securely,
which is the core of
basically of all
these benefits
that we can achieve.
We had bit of
interesting discussion
yesterday in the
other panel.
And so I think one of
the interesting aspects is
really the fact that
you can work differently
with the network and
get better performance and
better scalability
for example,
mighty destination
distribution
and all of it.
We also sometimes discuss
application support,
like the fact that maybe
this named data approach
will also be nicer for
applications to use or
you can also
build nicer APIs
and application
oriented services.
And then there's the
other perspective.
So when you maybe
come from the time of
blockchain content
fabric perspective,
you would probably say,
Yeah, we assume some
Internet productivity.
And on top of that,
we design our
decentralized
infrastructure that
provides content
discovery,
access to content.
Interesting in some form
in the whole distribution,
but also things like
transactions and
asset management.
And so this is often
considered to be like
one system and then you
would be able to build
applications on
top of that.
I know this is a very
rough comparison
here and you can,
but it's also not
quite correct
because if you
dig a little bit,
you can also bisect
these texts in
different ways,
but I think
just to give us
some intuition it's all
about different ways
how to proceed.
So for the panel today,
so we thought it
would be nice to
discuss a little bit
what the different
types of
metaverse systems
actually need [NOISE].
So you can do
this in two ways
where you can look
at the existing
systems today.
But maybe we can also be a
bit more creative
and think.
So what, how could
distance look like?
So assuming maybe
knowing little
bit the technology that
we have at our hands.
Named data seems
to be useful.
So we see this in
even a legacy overlayer
systems today,
but question is
on which layer?
You don't have to
restrict yourself
to one layer.
But what are good ways
to structure the
functionalities?
Maybe there is
some relationship
between named data,
your data oriented
approaches in
the application, layer
application space.
And the named data
approach that we
typically use in
the network as NDN.
And the third maybe
high-level topic
is a little bit
maybe looking
into the future.
So I think the discussion
today will also
point to some
interesting needs
or interesting features.
And one question could be,
how can we support
applications better?
So is there something
the NDN could do,
or we should develop
maybe something that
NDN is missing,
or how we should
evolve it?
In general,
what are the research
opportunities?
So maybe more
specifically,
what we could get
out of this from
an NDN perspective is,
are there any
architectural
or security-related
or performance-related
issues
in Metaverse systems today
that need to be addressed?
Is there any communication
patterns that we can
identify that NDN
could support?
And so how can
the data-oriented
model and
decentralized trust be
helpful for better
metaverse systems and
which layer would actually
be able to support,
this was NDN?
And as I mentioned,
so what are the
gaps and challenges
and so on in NDN research?
And I'm super
happy that we have
a really nice composition
today from
people from really
different backgrounds
and what they've
experienced
in networking
distributed systems.
And contingency question.
So let me introduce
Paulo Mendes.
Paulo is currently
an expert in
Network Architectures
and Protocols
at AIRBUS research
in Munich,
and also an Associated
Researcher at Munich.
So he will talk
a bit more about
his background
in a second.
But the NDN
people probably
know Paulo from previous
ICN and the end work.
And I'm happy to have
Michelle Munson
and Todd Hodes
in independent today.
They are both from
Eluvio and has
previously founded
Aspera and
developed the
FASP bulk-data
or data transfer protocol.
And he's the Co-Creator
of Eluvio's Cotton
Fabric Particle.
And Todd is the
Principal Architect
at Eluvio and he
previously built
Location Labs
and has a background in
distributed systems.
And then finally we have
Jeff Burke from UCLA,
The School of Theater,
Film and Television,
where he is Professor
and Associate
Dean for Research
on the anthology.
And he's also the
Co-Director of
the UCLA Center
for Research and
Engineering, Media
and performance.
While those of you
who work with NDN for
some time surely
know Jeff,
he's been a long
time researcher
and contributor to
the technology.
And so next,
I would invite
our panelists
to tell us a little
bit more about
their background and
maybe their connection
to this metaverse
public in general.
And let's start
with Paulo.
>> Good afternoon. I hope
you can hear me well.
That's always the
first question to
ask in this
remote situation.
So as Duke already
presented a
little of myself,
so I'm at AIRBUS
central assertion
technology in
Munich since before
the pandemic, 2019.
Just arrived and
the pandemic also
arrived some
months later on.
Before that, I worked
in different places.
I created some research
centers in Portugal.
I was also professor
in University
in Portugal and also
long time ago or also in
the industry where I
was researcher assistant
at NTT Docomo,
the Japanese
Telecom operator.
At the time that
we were creating
former in Europe
for the 3G network.
So I know Duke,
Jeff and others from
the NDM community.
I'm very pleased
to be here in
the NDM com to contribute
to this topic.
And I may say a little
about what is my
correlation with
metaverse because
let's say
association with
this event is more
from the NDM side
at metaverse.
Metaverse is
something that
started one-and-a-half
years ago.
Within the context of
AIRBUS where we started,
I only did a study
about what does it
mean metaverse for us?
Like Duke said,
there are lots
of different
definitions and
people have different
ways to look at it.
What does it
mean for AIRBUS?
What can we
exploit from it?
And actually, how can
we contribute to it?
And that's more or less,
let's say my
motivation towards
the topic of metaverse
and actually to be here.
Not sure if I should
explain a little
what my opinion
about metaverse is and
provide some insights now?
Or just to go around
and allow the
others to present.
Duke how does it go?
>> So we have a more
technical presentation
option later.
Maybe you can say like
like one or two sentence,
what's the relationship of
your work to metaverse.
>> So like I said,
being within
the context of
AIRBUS doing some
work on the context
of NDM that was like
the main topic.
And that's why I also
liked the invitation
because it brings the
two topics together.
On the metaverse I'm
leading a studying
within AIRBUS.
And it's a
high-level study.
So it is not
technological jargon.
Is more related with
this first picture
that Duke presented.
The beautiful
future world.
What does it
mean? It's going
to be completely
different.
And we are trying to
answer some questions.
What does it mean?
For instance, we
got the conclusion
that the metaverse is
not the Web3 only.
That was very
good conclusion.
That is not only
NVIDIA Omniverse.
Also some of my
colleagues in
several business units are
using NVIDIA Omniverse to
create the 3D render
models for the
production lines, etc.
Is not only about
virtual reality and
augmented reality,
in my opinion.
And most
important, it will
not change or will not
replace real life.
That's something
that I try to
tell people not to be
afraid of the multiverse
because you're not
going to disappear.
It's not like the
matrix where you
disappear
completely and you
just live in
the metaverse.
That's not exactly
what happened.
And what I've tried to
do also in this
study to figure out,
and that's a
learning process,
is that the
metaverse for us is
not only a set
or one 3D space,
three-dimensional space,
or that's the
first challenge.
The interconnection
between
three different 3D spaces.
Is also the connection
with the physical world,
with real-world
in real-time.
By the connection of
virtual presence
like avatars with
the real systems like
cyber-physical systems or
robotic systems
for instance.
This is more or
less what we're
doing in this
high-level definition.
And maybe towards
the panel,
I can go into
more technical
issues because now
we're getting more
into what is our,
let's say, vision in
the short term
and long term.
And actually technically,
what good can we exploit
on the short-term?
Short-term means in
the next five years.
And long-term
what should be
our positioning
even technically.
I think that we
can take it during
the panel discussion.
>> Thanks Paulo.
By the way,
to those of us who
are joining remotely,
I invite you to turn on
your camera as well.
So let's move on. So Jeff
is actually onsite
[inaudible].
>> Hi. So Jeff
Burke from UCLA.
I'll just give a quick
introduction of
my background.
So I teach at UCLA and
my focus is on essentially
the impact of emerging
technologies on
storytelling and
also vice versa.
The impact of the needs
of the creative sector
and artists in
the long-term on
fundamental technologies.
What that has
involved has been
research in
different types
of fundamental
technologies.
So I've been involved in
the NBN research project
since 2010.
I guess since the
original proposal.
And then also at
the same time,
working on part of
experimental productions,
from performances to
recorded media to
interactive
projects that are
exploring a mix
of technology,
opportunity and
the storytelling
challenges that exist.
So it's integrated with
our training
programs at UCLA.
That includes
most recently
shared augmented
reality experiences
in the context of
live performance.
So last year we did
a live performance set
in the world of the
Amazon Studios series,
The Man in the High Castle
that was looking at
mobile AR based audience
experience of a
live performance.
And we've done other types
of experiments
like that that are
scaling up in
sophistication
in terms of their use
of extended reality.
Also very interested
in the relationship
between named data
networking and
alternative strategies
for networking
and the future of
content creation
and experience.
So I have just a
screenshot up here
of a project a few
years ago called
touch NDN that was
looking at taking
a hierarchical naming that
exists in real
time graphics.
So in this case,
a platform
called Touch
Designer that was
built by the
folks that did
the Houdini 3D
graphics platform.
And looking at how to
have NDN communication of
media integrated
into this real-time
platform.
And what some of
the benefits and
challenges were.
I think just to briefly
explain my interest in
the metaverse and how it
connects to this panel.
I think that sits in
two different
places that relates
very much to Paulos.
>> One is in the
relationship between
the physical
world and shared
extended reality
applications and
what some of the
technical challenges are.
I think the notion
of a digital twin
has been helpful
in reminding,
I think that each
of the applications
that were discussed
yesterday,
so whether it was
vehicular networking,
mobile health,
energy generation.
All of those
are very likely
from an end-user
perspective to have
representations in
3D shared worlds
in the near
future and have
maybe close coupling with
some of the data and
actuation that's
handled in
other parts of
those networks.
And so I think it's
a broad concern
for the community that
we're going to see
those types of systems
integrated with chaired
XR experiences soon.
And then, I guess the
second interest that
I have is really the
trajectory away from
traditional production and
post-production processes
that we're focused
on 2D video
captured optically
towards really
real-time 3D graphics
is a fundamental way
for processing
and presenting
future of entertainment
experiences.
And those connect
very closely,
I think to fundamental
technologies and
experiences that exist
in the metaverse.
So I'll leave it
at that and then
look forward to
the discussion.
>> Thank you,
Jeff. And I'm
really happy that
we have Michelle,
taught in the panel
today as well.
And I'd like to
invite them to
introduce themselves
and their work
at interview.
>> Hi Dirk, I'll
start. Michelle here.
Thank you-all very much
for including us in this.
I think first
and foremost,
this is a really
big topic area.
And as Paul has said,
it interconnects
everything about
the history of
TCPIP networks
and optimization now all
the way up through what
people are trying to do
in the modern
content industry.
And I thought maybe
I'll try to tell you
a little bit about
my own background and
how we arrived at
creating the content
fabric protocol,
which is the decentralised
blockchain and
content native
protocol approach
that Dirk referred to.
After grad school, I
was fortunate to
get exposed to
some of the application
layer networking problems
that were emerging
at that time.
And I ended up,
after working with some
folks at UC Berkeley,
that's how I met Todd,
couple of start-ups,
some getting involved in
the areas of transport
optimization.
And I started a company
ultimately and a protocol
called a spirit fast.
And this was years ago
for unicast based,
reliable bulk
data transport.
I'm sure Bon saw me when
I built that up into a
functioning both
protocol stack
and also application
layer set of tools.
And that grew
across media and
entertainment quite a
lot for many years.
And during that process,
we ended up being
exposed to a lot of
the overall contents
supply chain.
I don't know how
better to put it on
and toward the later
stages of that.
And it was
specifically being
integrated into content
delivery networks,
classic major CDNs
and has a tooling and
application stack to get
large data into
public Clouds
and around public Clouds.
And so the reason
I'm going into all this is
because in that process,
Chevron and I had this
consistent exposure
to what you would call
a web of problems.
And those problems were
both at the
application layer
and then I would
say also at
the interface
to the network
and also to the storage.
The kind of content
that Jeff's
talking about
that exists now,
it's not only very heavy,
but typically
it's composed.
And the same base
content is recomposed
in many ways.
And then the more
traditional way
of storing and
processing that and
then distributing it to
the consumer is
very multistage.
And then finally,
if you take
a really Indian level
approach to the problem,
there's a huge amount
of duplication in
the bytes that go through
those composed versions
over the Internet.
And all of this together,
we had this sense
that there might be
a more content
native approach
to create a
distribution protocol.
And the fabric
is just that,
it has many
properties that
are derived from some of
the philosophies you
all are talking about.
And I'll try to
get into that,
the more technical parts.
We started the protocol
implementation in 2018,
and it's taken us
a good 3-4 years
just to get it to a point
of functioning at scale.
We do now, since 2019,
have a pretty
large-scale network
that runs the protocol.
It's a full-stack
blockchain as well,
which I'll get into.
And I think
the most interesting
part about this to
today's panel is that
the fabric network is
both as a
blockchain and also
just as an application
layer network is now
being used to support
many Web 3 Metaverse
experiences.
One of the most interesting
recently has been
an interactive AR/VR model
for releasing movies,
which we've done with
Warner Brothers Studios.
And this is, as Jeff said,
I think the tip of
what's possible in terms
of bringing interactive
content to the consumer.
One of the things that I
want to talk about
as we get into this,
as you ask for the
motivations of
problem space is
what we can do as
a integrated
networking and
technology community
to really help to
advance the
architecture beyond
what's known as
so-called public Clouds.
One of the great
challenges to really
getting the deepest
adoption in this area,
is the fact that
the public clouds
have become so dominant.
And in terms of
content production as
well as distribution.
And as long as that's
the only paradigm
that people know and
understand it makes
it difficult to push
forward at really
large scale
and to unlock the
possibilities.
Fortunately, I
think there's
huge good timing in
terms of the interests
from the market.
But definitely the
large majority
of media workflows
that Jeff would be
talking about that we
would work on
would have more
traditionally
been locked into
what you think of as
a classic public
cloud storage and
distribution through
a more classic CDN.
So I want to
turn it over to my
colleague Todd,
who joined us at Alivio
here just in 2023,
taught as a PhD
from Cal Berkeley.
But most importantly, I've
known him for a
very long time.
He's quite an expert in
distributed systems and as
this platform has really
started to scale,
we have many
application layer needs
that Todd is leading out
and I think he'll be
a fantastic addition to
the conversation.
Turn it to you Todd.
>> Great thanks,
appreciate that.
Thanks for the
invitation to the panel.
It's a great opportunity
to talk to everyone.
There's two main things
that I've done in
my past that are
relevant here and one
is each relate to
the metaverse and to
name data networking.
So back in the
early 2000s,
we were starting to work
on content centric
networking,
which came more of
the named data space.
That was also
the environment
which has all the
papers quote,
was the multicast
environment
we talked about
protocols for
application level
framing and
soft-state and receiver
driven policies
and whatnot.
Two of the things we were
working on back then and
the papers at the
time called them
simply service
discovery protocols.
They were really
about naming
the data elements such
that they had two
interesting properties.
One was the local name
would resolve differently.
So the example would be
the light switch or
the video camera
in the room you're in.
You can name it as
a named data element
instead of a what?
An endpoint and IP
endpoint and find it.
So that's the
service discovery of
the named piece and then
extending that to
the wide area.
How do you actually allow
these names to
propagate wider?
And some papers that
were interesting.
Learning if it became
what is now routed
differently in
the name data
networking stack.
The way the protocols
have evolved is
different now,
but some of the same stuff
was coming up at
the time and then
the second piece
is interesting.
After doing that
work early,
I took a foray into
mobile computing,
which we're
building things,
such as local
social networks
for location-based
networking.
And so you get into the
Metaverse elements,
which is you're
inserting the user into
the application because
it's location-based.
And so various things
are built by location labs
before eventually
being carrier
focused applications.
From there then
joining Alivio,
where I'm working
on authorization
and application
services on
top of the content fabric.
So as introduction,
I'll just leave it
there and we can get
more into those
topics, thanks.
Great. Thanks very much,
Michelle and Todd.
It's really good to
have you on the panel.
So I could imagine
that there will be
quite some
interesting questions
in your content fabric
protocol and so on.
So we definitely have
time later to talk
more about this.
Certainly interesting, I
read the white paper today
and I found quite
interesting,
synergies overlap.
So I think it's
an actually quite
interesting setting.
So I'm also monitoring
the lecture.
And so don't hesitate
to post your
questions there.
I will try to [inaudible]
this a little bit,
and as we go,
I will then read
out a few questions
and then we can
discuss this more, great.
>> We initially prepared
a few topics that
we would like
to talk about.
This should not be
limiting the discussion.
So if there are
other aspects
that we identify,
I think I'm able to manage
it and we can also
talk about this.
So let's use this
as a starting point
and see how it goes.
We only heard a
little bit about
the different perspectives
and connections
to metaverse.
But let's talk
a little bit
more about what is so
interesting about it or
what are the
interesting aspects
from your perspective?
And let's see what
we can probably get.
Paulo, you started
a little bit,
but maybe talk more
about what's
interesting from
your and from
Airbus perspective.
>> Sure. During my
previous intervention,
I gave a little hint,
what will be for
the Metaverse.
This statement that is
there is not
Airbus statement,
just my [inaudible] idea
about what Metaverse is,
because internally
there are
still lots of
discussion about it.
Like I said, I like
to emphasize again,
I think what the
Metaverse is not.
First thing that
people look at,
at least my
colleagues when they
look at lots of things.
[inaudible] you're also
doing the same thing
or doing 3D modelling
of production
lines to help
the design of
aircraft, etc.
Where there is
a certain number of
people cooperating,
like a social network.
But for work like
LinkedIn where
people [inaudible]
writing a certain
specific task,
like looking at the engine
to see if it
works properly.
If it's been built
according to the plans and
if there's something
that is missing.
This is what people
are already doing not
exactly what I'm looking
at towards the
next ten years.
That for me is looking
more for the visual point
of view that we need
to start interacting
and bringing
all these 3D
worlds together.
But this is one of
the first things
that people are
complaining is
that when they
create their
3D modelling for a
specific purpose,
Metaverse application,
that application does not
talk with other
application.
You can use NDVI
Omniverse and to create
your 3D modelling
and to do
all your interactions
with all avatars.
But people, for instance,
in our production line,
people from the design
can use this tool,
but people from production
or testing use
another tool.
They don't talk to each
other. So there is
no way currently
to transfer,
transport
information back or
forward between
the design phase
and the testing and
production phase
because they
are not connected first.
Second, because if
they were connected,
we already discover there
are some data semantics
that actually needs to be
translated in real time.
Something that may need
some kind of a neat.
So this is more from what
we call the industrial
Metaverse purposes.
On the other hand,
there is also the,
let's say, the
customer experience.
For us the customer
are the airliners,
but we talk about
the B2B model,
the customer of
the customer,
that is the passengers.
What will be the impact of
the Metaverse for
these passengers?
The first application
that people
look or think about is
to make airline traveling
a little less boring.
Where you can embark
in a parallel
traveling while you're
traveling and then
you can get out of
this metallic tube
where you are in
for hours and have
a pleasant voyage.
That could be
[inaudible] We
did some experiments
with aerographical
environments, etc.
That's very good,
but you have
the problem of bandwidth
getting off the aircraft.
So that's the first
problem to look at.
The second one is
when we want to build
a 3D model is in real-time
because other
avatars are present.
These normally is
done on the Cloud,
and the Cloud is
really far away.
So this does not work
properly and
the handling delays,
for instance,
for handling headsets,
because of the head
movement and the delay,
actually that's
a big problem.
So there are lots
of constraints,
very simple constraints
that are endangering,
actually bringing
the Metaverse
inside the aircraft.
But for me, what
Metaverse is all
about that for me
is like the next
generation of Internet.
The Internet is a
network of networks.
Internetverse will
have a network of
three-dimensional spaces
connected to the
physical world.
So this is exactly what
we were looking at.
And from the data
point of view,
I think it will be
really interesting to
highlight that,
in my opinion,
on the Metaverse
will not handle
the only multimedia
data that
we normally use or
consume on the Internet,
audio, video, and text,
but other kind of
data is also needed,
like ampathic data,
temperature,
temperature came from
the internet of
things, of course.
But other things
like how do you
transfer of
digital assets.
Then we go to
discussion about
NFTs blockchain, etc.
But as other things,
let's say complex need
to be transferred
like emotions.
If you really want to
replicate in
a virtual world your
physical world,
it's very important that
you understand
the other person.
And there are some
aspects like the problem
of [inaudible]
People don't
like to talk with avatars,
psychological is
the impairment.
So we need
really to create
a virtual world that is as
realistic as possible,
including, for
instance, having delays
there not fake delays.
So all of these are very I
think might be a challenge
for the next 15 years.
I'm not going to
talk for now about
what Indian can
do about this.
But just from a
Airbus point of view,
what we are
looking currently,
it's like in a two-log
step progress.
One, like I said,
in the next
maybe five years
where you can
actually exploit
existing tools as
these applications.
I was not aware about
the contents
fabric protocol.
I will read the white
paper very carefully
over the weekend for sure.
But we are trying to
figure out how can we
improve the use of these
three-dimensional spaces,
like the sense
of immersion,
the real-time interactive
in this single
environment.
But on long term,
we need to understand
how, for instance,
someone in the virtual
environment can
control a physical
equipment like a robot.
Currently, we can do
remote control of robots
over the internet,
but it's not
very immersive.
We lack lots
of information
from what the robot is.
We have video,
we have sound,
but we don't have the
three-dimensional view
of what the robot is.
If the robot is outdoors,
we don't have the idea
of the wind, for instance,
that may be very
important if I
maneuvering a long
arm, robotic arm.
So all this kind of
information I'm missing,
and we need to include it
on the Metaverse since
they are not present
on the internet.
[inaudible] that
is the problem
of scalability.
We are playing with
single virtual worlds
in very simple
application.
In the future, we need to
interact thousands
of virtual worlds,
my family virtual world,
my work virtual world,
my friends, other
virtual worlds.
How can we do that,
if each virtual world
is like a completely
protocol stay?
So if we need to
standardize it.
There are lots
of needs for
standardizing how
disinformation
is transported.
What kind of information?
Like I said, there are
some pieces of
data that are
actually not, let's
say, captured.
We don't have
a way like we
do with voice to know
how to format voice
and to transport it.
We don't have that
for other kinds
of data that are needed.
That I think that's it
from Airbus point of view,
I can give you a hint
what we are already
doing and what we
are looking at.
Currently, we are
already looking
at what we call
industrial metaphors,
where we have
digital twins.
The famous Digital Twin,
for instance, of
aircraft construction.
If you see we have
the manufacturer
facility of the a350 is
already completely
modeled on
the virtual world that
is used for people
to interact,
to solve problems
related with the
construction.
We are also using the,
I'm not sure if
I should call
it currently the
Metaverse but
virtual reality
experience for people
to collaborate.
We are trying to
interact with
some physical devices and
we are a little worried
about scalability of this.
If we are looking more at
the business part of
handling customers.
That's a very
important issue.
>> Thanks Paulo.
We can talk
a bit more of the
challenges in a bit.
But what I heard
from you so far is
that so you're looking at
different use cases like
passenger entertainment,
but also production
due to twin distance
and basically
virtual meetings.
For the four-vector, the
in-flight entertainment,
let's say.
What I heard is that
you're interested in
these challenging
requirements regarding
bandwidth and low latency,
especially in an even more
challenged network
environment
where connectivity
is maybe not so easy
to achieve. That correct?
>> Yeah, that's correct.
That for us is
mainly impairment.
So for us Metaverse is
not just a flying
experience,
it's a door-to-door
experience
where flight design is
just a small
step in the way.
But yes. People start
to think about the mobile
Internet long time ago,
that people said,
we should have
the same experience
door-to-door,
even when we are inside
cars or outside cars,
for the Metaverse should
be the same thing.
And inside the aircraft is
difficult to access
Internet properly,
so the Metaverse
is like them,
will be ten
times difficult.
So that connectivity,
a very simple
connectivity problem
is one of
the first one that
needs to be solved.
>> Okay.
>> So let's have a
bit of a discussion.
So one perspective
from this it's
largely industrial
airplane production
but also consumer,
the end perspective.
What do other
people think?
What are
additional special
properties or
interesting properties?
>> I wrote down
a few points
as Paulo was talking,
which I think built on
what he was saying.
I think this whole
problem space of
interoperability and
availability everywhere
comes down to
content composition,
which implies many
other things.
But underneath that,
what I mean by content
composition is that it
becomes possible in
a scalable and large-scale
interoperable way
to be able to
create interactive
content derivatives
and to do that in the
network, basically.
This also implies in
the applications.
We are day-to-day
involved in a form of
what would be
considered Web 3 or
blockchain-based
metaverse all the time.
And one of the most
fundamental properties,
I think to get
this to really
scale for today's
Internet is ownership.
And what I mean
by ownership
is that the
composition, of course,
needs to relate to
the user or the owner
that's participating.
And one of the points
that Paulo made,
which is so true and
it's just so far
from the vision of
what's painted is that
so much of what's
been done with
metaverses and AR,
VR experiences is
completely siloed.
It's not only built on
a centralized
architecture,
it's an entirely
traditional stack,
and what is done in one
environment isn't in
any way orderbly
ownable or re-usable,
experienceable by
the owning user
anywhere else.
There are some
small attempts,
frankly, on the
commercial side,
from vendors to have
digital twins that
are portable,
but that's not built in
a way that you would
consider actually
something you could
architect upon.
So that brings me
to my third point,
which is latency
and performance.
Paulo said this too.
The way the content
has been handled in
more traditional
streaming in
the last 20 years
is just way
too unperforming for
what needs to happen.
And what I think for us,
we're a networking
community.
I got a little one
here. Thank you.
One of the missing
pieces and
the discussion is not
just the throughput
over the network,
the way we treat
the network,
but the interaction
with the IO.
And one of the
huge problems
of the way most of
the real-time
content flows work
in cloud CDN space,
if you want to
call it that,
is the stop off points
between file IO,
transport over
the network,
generation, transcoding
and output.
And then also the
nature of the IO.
If you really
get down to it,
maybe this is
because I spent
years with high-speed
file transfer.
The biggest problem of all
is the IO architecture
and especially as we get
into cloud-based
storage systems,
those are just
not conducive
to large forum content,
high-throughput IO
for many reasons
and that no matter how
good we get the
network portion,
without addressing that
directly into
the protocol,
you're stuck with
a certain latency
performance envelope.
The next point I
wrote down was
metadata and
Paulo said this,
this is spot on that
compositionality
needs to have
data along with it to be
able to, again,
manifest experience.
Because what
people think of as
metaverse application
goes straight
up to the end user.
And one of the core
principles that we
really believe
in and think
needs to be part of
the application protocol,
full stack is the
metadata about
the content is inherently
part of what it is.
And that metadata can then
be composed upon in
that first point.
Next is user experience.
And I want to stress this,
Paulo said it too.
I really want to speak to
this in the
overall context,
not just the
performance and
availability of
the environment,
but ownership.
One of the great downfalls
in crypto and blockchain
into this is
most traditional
blockchain is terrible
user experience,
meaning that, first
of all, it's
very immature.
We all know
what that means
in Internet systems,
it just takes
awhile for all the
pieces and parts to
work well enough.
But there's a bigger,
more fundamental
point which
is if you talk to the
blockchain community,
same group like this
but over in the
blockchain community,
there would be no
thought whatsoever to
the needs of the content.
The blockchain community
thinks exclusively
about codifying
ownership onto a chain,
having a way to sign for
that on behalf
of the user,
but there's no
native connection
back to the
content itself,
its provenance,
its version, etc.
And we feel those
two things are
inherently linked
in order to
build these new
experiences.
And then my last
point is cost.
The most limiting factor
of all the choices of
the last 20 years of
CDNs and clouds for
large firm interactive
content is
it is incredibly expensive
to invest in and produce.
I want to give
you all a fact
from just last week,
I spoke at the Hollywood
Post Alliance.
I guess they
changed their name
HPA Tech Retreat,
right after us and our
talk on this topic
was the Lord of
the Rings on Amazon
production panel.
And that panel
was all cloud,
all virtual
production utilizing
what is considered
the state of the art.
Of course, it's an
Amazon-created work
so it was able to
utilize all the
Amazon cloud in full.
But the end point of
the presentation,
someone asked, well,
how much did this cost?
And the person
leading this,
the executive director in
charge of all
the technology,
literally admitted
that the cost
was out of range for
anything practically.
So one last thing
I want to say
that goes back to
the roots of Indian.
Again, because I'm quite
commercially
minded these days.
I don't know how directly
relevant this is,
but the original papers on
content native
routing in design.
In the first
talk I heard on
this from Van Jacobson,
one of the most
important principles
was to suck the
redundant graphic off of
the back plane
of the Internet.
And if you do that
through the full stack,
it starts to
really pull in
the resource usage at a
truly scalable level,
not just over the network,
but in the storage and in
the compute it's
used and whatnot
and I think that's
a great opportunity
for sustainability in
this and to take
the cost way down.
My thoughts.
>> Thanks, [inaudible]
many good points.
Is there any
immediate reaction?
So let's make this more
into a discussion.
>> I'll make a
quick comment that
the WDV experienced
actually embeds
AR objects into the sale
of their Lord of the
Rings experience.
And what's wonderful about
that is first of all,
it's encrypted such that
you don't have
issues with people.
The ownership question
is handled again,
blockchain people
care a lot
about that and just
wonderful being
that networking
needs to deal
with that too,
your data needs to be
routable even if
it's encrypted.
The second piece that's
needed about that is,
is once you own
that content,
you can incorporate it
anywhere you
want if that's
an open AR standard object
you can just
get to use it.
So it's very
important that
these elements are getting
used not only the community
but commercially.
>> Maybe add to that also,
one of the things
Todd and I
deal with on a daily basis
is decentralized ownership
for real I mean,
right now we're
deep in involved in
on-chain contracts
that allow for
provenance, ownership
in payments,
splits between
parties that own in
compositional content
in these environments
and doing that well,
I really want to call
this to the
community because it
brings out the full
interdisciplinary nature
of this problem space.
Doing that well, in a way
that really the blockchain
world you would
say it's truly
on-chain and also
doesn't leave exposed
the opportunities for,
again, centralized
intermediaries to
control the
economics of that.
Doing that well is very
important and very
closely tied to this
and the reason I want to
call that out
as I think it's
fantastic that
this community
is taking this topic
on and we hope that those
of you who are experts in,
not just the
networking area,
but interested in
these related problems
will work on them
because there
needs to be more rigor
in the approaches for this
because there are huge
economic implications
to what Todd just said.
Jeff works with a lot of
the most creative IP,
and these will
be the new means
of ownership and
monetization.
And we have an
opportunity to
really make this much
better and much
more democratic
for the user and
the creator,
that in the best sense
of the internet.
But it's only going to
happen if those
approaches are really
rigorous and we don't
redo what we've been
doing with data ownership
for the last many years.
>> Let's see how we can
make this rigorous.
So we talked a little
bit already about
the second item here so
some requirements and
gaps and some ideas
so just let's see
whether there's
anything else that we
like to talk about.
As I took some notes and
good points that you
raised so far that I
hope to some of those
we can come back later.
So for now I would say,
let's move a
little bit forward
because I think we
touched on many
of these things already.
Let's talk a little bit
about the named data,
say aspect and potential
and we mentioned it
like superficially
here and there,
but I think I would like
to get more to the point.
So what role
does it actually
play in maybe
different layers of
the system and what is the
potential and to build
better systems
in the future.
So in the perspective of
the question also we have
this fundamental
interests data protocol
but what can we
actually do with it,
or what should we
be doing with it?
What type of interaction
maybe useful?
And maybe we can
come back to
this decentralized
control for
real requirement
or suggestion
that you brought
up earlier.
So Paulo do we have
additional ideas on
these questions,
on Named Data
and Metaverse?
>> Yeah maybe. I think
during the discussion to
know, like you said,
there was some
glimpse about
how something like names,
that system could help
and I think that the
painting is conceptual,
the metaverse is
not about host,
is not about servers,
is about data objects
or programs
computing elements.
So by itself,
conceptually,
metaverse is really
align with the
ICM general and named
data network
in particular.
From the conceptual
point of view,
the question is, like,
I think you mentioned
their case what
do we do with it?
We use a traditional way,
we have a protocol
stacks within
MDN somewhere
in layer 3 or above
the transport layer,
whatever you want to
do it and then we
have several sets of
metaverse
applications using
a traditional SOC
plays or API that
will be the
traditional way.
Not sure if that's
exactly what
we want to do.
I can just using
this picture tell you
a little what we
are looking at.
I give you two examples.
One, for instance,
could be
leveraging the MDN.
I think it's more
or less with
what Michelle
and Todd said,
maybe we find this
loop before is
leveraged in the MDN for
the distributed control of
the metaverse like to
support distribution
of ledgers and
because currently
this is very
poorly done so
blockchain as
discussive protocols
that don't
work very properly, etc.
Maybe you could
use the exploit,
the native
in-network catching
and multicast of the
MDN actually to do
a better service in
distributing
these ledgers and
to keep them updated.
And that's something that
the MDN was built for,
not for the ledgers
but for data objects
and that could be quite
interesting to have.
And that will be a
central piece for
the metaverse because we
need to control ownership,
we need control assets
that actually needs
to be transported
from three-dimensional
world to
another three-dimensional
world where
people want to move
and roam between them.
The other aspect
that is more
correlated with
the picture or
the slide is
something that I
mentioned before about
our Airbus scenario.
I think IT after some
RFCs that mission
they talked about
limited to it.
That's what Airbus
leads for we have
the aeronautics to mind,
the satellite one.
All of them are not
core networks
on the internet
and all of them specific
properties and problems.
And one of them is
constrained resources.
I can put a nice server
inside the aircraft.
No problem about that,
but the server will be
very fast connected.
I cannot put the same
server inside
the satellite,
will be much constraint
the power that will be
somehow nicely
connected if
we have free-space optical
links to the ground, etc.
So there is some
nitrogenase scenarios
that return figure
out what to use them.
And what the picture
tried to illustrate is
that what we're looking
at is a scenario that
is not homogeneous,
will not have a
metaverse application.
Let's say a
three-dimensional
world being processed on
the cloud with everything,
the rendering of the
3D world itself,
the creation
of the avatars
in real time or not,
the inclusion
of autonomous
avatars in the future.
All of these will not
happen in our opinion,
in a centralized
environment.
Actually because may occur
over what I have here,
these Cloud to
seem continue.
Because we may
have the Cloud,
the high capacity
Cloud to be used to
render three-dimensional
worlds of a factory,
of a party, of a company.
But then maybe
you towards more
to where the action
really happens.
If we look at
the interaction with
the physical world,
we may need to do
computational and
data gathering
in other places.
In the case of the
aircraft point of view,
maybe the passenger
inside the aircraft
will have access
to the metaverse,
while lots of processing
that needs to be
done in short
periods of time.
It may have
actually happened
inside the
aircraft itself.
While other processing may
happen in the Cloud,
like the adaptation
of the three-dimensional
space.
So how do I connect
all of these elements?
MDN chemically a role
diet or the
leveraging MDN.
What I imply
with this slide,
leveraging their MDN to
distribution of services.
Maybe I've talked
about microservices.
And just last
but not least,
Microsoft is very
well aligned with
blockchain
things like Lucy
talks about
smart contracts.
That's a very
nice alignment.
So there are lots
of things that
I think alignment,
we just need to figure
out where do we start
and maybe people in
the audience already
start to look at it.
Technically, I would like
to really do
hear about that.
>> Maybe let's hear
a bit more
application ideas
on name data for
the Metaverse,
and then we can
discuss this together.
So Jeff has some
ideas from it.
>> Yeah, it looks
like there's
a typo in this slide.
Can you go to
the next one?
It might make sense
to start with that.
So in thinking about
this a little bit and
listening to the
other panelists,
something that is
interesting from
the production
standpoint is
the idea of the
metaverses,
or let's say
just the feature
of environment for
content generation
as being
essentially a persistent
shared world.
But if you really
think about what
that means,
it's also a shift from
an environment of
content production
where most of
our content was offline.
So if you're
shooting a film,
you have a large
amount of footage,
you have all the
things that you've
done during the
production process,
all the assets and so on.
And then at some point,
you boil it down to
something that's
distributed and you never
see those original
assets again,
or at least not
in a traditional,
let's say, filmmaking
point of view.
And the same is true
to some extent in
3D graphics and other
things as well.
So we're shifting
from that type of
environment to a
world where yes,
maybe it's in
cheaper storage
or it's further away,
but you essentially
have the opportunity
to access and reuse
content and elements
from throughout
the production process
from other productions.
And I think for
larger content companies
that are looking at
the idea of content
emerging from a
consistent universe,
or consistent world,
they are able to draw
from assets, of course,
across that universe
and reuse them and
that has a really
interesting set
of analogies
in the idea of thinking
of making content
within a metaverse way of
thinking which is if I
can access any type of
named content if I have
an ability to verify
my ability to use it,
whether it's ownership or
license or contract,
however you want
to look at it,
I can access and reuse
those elements
at any point.
And this changes
the way that we
think about
production models.
So the idea of an
iterative production
of something like
an augmented
reality experience
looks a lot maybe like
software production
where we're
starting with
stand-in assets,
developing interactions,
changing out the names
that we're using
to access final assets
and plug those
things in and so on.
And so I think this idea
of content creation
within a network where
everything is named
and accessible,
takes on a very
different set of
authorial and creative
strategies that
you need first and
also has a lot of
interesting opportunities.
So this slide was
related to this idea
of what are the
opportunities
specifically for named
data networking and
thinking about
the metaverse,
not just as some shared
end-user experience,
but the environment
in which we
might be authoring
content and creating.
So one person's metaverse
behind the scenes
business application
is another person's
content experience
as an end-user with a
flip of the switch.
And most of the elements
that make up 3D graphics,
the analysis of 2D images,
the interoperable
content formats that
people are considering
for shared 3D worlds,
all use hierarchical
name data
in one form or another,
whether it's a
scene graph that
describes a 3D
environment.
We're seeing graph
that's generated by
analysis of a 2D
scene and then
using new machine learning
techniques to manipulate
those 2D images.
There's many opportunities
I think for us to look
at how content is
already named or
will be named soon,
and how that allows
a very granular way
of accessing and
manipulating
content and allows
the persistence
of elements from
previous versions,
and the intermixing
of versions.
I think this actually
comes up a little bit
in the Alivio white paper,
moving from Version 1 to
Version 2 or
creating updates,
but also the idea
that content
is composable,
and we are often
thinking of how to
compose that content
based on hierarchical
namespaces that map very
well into a named data way
of thinking about
these objects.
And I guess to make
one connection to
something that
Michelle said,
the removal of
the IO steps or
the simplification
of how content moves
from one stage of
a creative process
to another,
has an economic impact,
of course, but
it also has a
creative impact.
As soon as you are able to
name and access
individual elements
as a developer and
user creator of content
in a way that's
much more flexible,
I think you get
a completely different
strategy for
authoring and
creating experiences
than how we think
about it right now,
which is author the thing,
render it, store
it, retrieve
it, manipulate it,
and then lose the
manipulation or
access to it and
having to deal
with different systems
at each stage.
Do go back one slide
and I'll finish
up quickly just
with this thought.
Sorry for whatever
happened in
the transition of
the slides here.
But there were five
things down here at
the bottom summarizing
the types of
things that at
least for me and
thinking both
about NDN and
the ways that
it can support
future types of
creative experiences,
that we have to deal
with that are not
really too prominent in
the community right now,
are real-time interaction,
which I think
we alluded to
already in terms of the
end-user experience.
Spatial organization
of content is
a great research
opportunity
for figuring
out better ways
to think about
whether it's
spatial naming things in
the real world or
spatial naming
something that's in
a 3D virtual world.
Managing shared
views that are
different of individual
experiences.
Again, I think alluding to
some things that
other folks
said and then
ownership and
actually different
types of identity.
My identity within,
and my ability to access,
pay for, manipulate,
or use my ownership
of some object,
is not going to be one
singular identity.
Of course, it's
going to be built
on different types
of roles and identity
across different systems.
So these are all
things that I
think are really
interesting
research
opportunities from
a content creation
and named data
networking standpoint.
So sorry for the ramble,
but hopefully helpful.
>> Thanks, Jeff. And
sorry about the slides.
I'm not sure what happened
probably here
something on my side.
>> I want to challenge
you a little bit on
this hierarchical
naming idea.
Of course, many
people would agree
that from a patient
perspective,
it's how you structure
your maybe objects,
and many people do that.
And solution in the chat
also supports you and
I think that's a chat.
The metric namespace sets
the foundation to
realize that model.
On the other hand,
some people could ask,
we understand that
it's useful to have
this structured
namespace in
the application space
and maybe also think
about transformation
and probability and so on.
But what does it have
to do with the network?
What do you gain by
applying this directly to
the network layer
communication?
>> So Derrick, I wanted
to say something
about this.
And my answer, of course,
comes from the perspective
of the content
fabric protocol,
but to take it from
that point of view.
It was our sense
that content
native addressability for
composition was
intrinsically important.
And what I mean by
that is that given
a basic structure
that's able to,
let's say compose output,
which in our view is
both binary data as
well as metadata,
as well as self-operating
code, if you will.
Given that you ought to be
able to address that
in a generalizable
way in a network,
and that really inherits
directly from the idea
of content native
routing principles,
which I think are really
the progenitor of
data networking,
if you will.
Now, in that model though,
the addressability
really comes from
a more generic notion
of the bytes themselves,
the hash, if you will.
And the routeability layer
is based exclusively
upon a namespace derived
from the content hashes.
Where I'm going
with this is above
that at the application
layer, there is,
in practical
terms, is one of
the most fundamental
features
of the fabric protocol.
Above that is the need for
the application to
be able to create
its own graph
structures on
top of that lowest
layer of routing logic,
which it works off of
the hash at the parts.
And that graph structure
needs to, number 1,
to Jeff's point, be
independent of the
specific application.
So the specific namespace.
The second thing about it
is that graph structure
needs to be able
to, if you will,
overlay logically
on top of
the underlying
routing so that it's
possible for if you will,
application namespace,
or hierarchy to be
able to then be
resolved directly
to the parts.
And the content
fabric protocol takes
a specific approach
to this through
the management of metadata
and the ability
to create links
between content
objects based
on how that metadata
works in the protocol.
The reason I'm
saying all this
because I think it's
a design primitive.
The design primitive
ought to be that.
Number 1, there is a
requirement,
like Jeff said,
that applications be able
to address content through
a naming structure that is
under the control
of the application
and is directly addressable
to the content.
And at the same time,
the lower routing
layer is able
to distribute
and also route
and locate content
in a means that is
independent of that
particular namespace.
The details of this,
I'm sure guys want to
know what am I really
talking about.
If you have a
moment, please take
a look at our protocol
white paper button.
But I think
those are really
the important design
paradigms here to
both make this
highly scalable
and generalizable.
And at the same
time support
the application
needs that are so
wide ranging and need
an architecture
that allows
the applications
to in fact
reuse the content
just as Jeff said.
>> And if I could
maybe add one thing.
Michelle said, I think
something important,
which is that I
don't know that you
have to necessarily
represent all of
that detail of
the namespace in the name
that's on the network.
There's some
decisions about what
gets presented to
the application.
What is interesting to
me in NDN is
the ability to
tie elements
of the name, to
trust relationships.
And to also imagine
inner operating
with something
like an IoT environment.
Maybe not directly,
but using some of
those same
principles where
in an IoT environment,
maybe you are deciding to
have a hierarchy
that is very much
used for local
communication
and maybe some forwarding
within a smaller
environment
and uses essentially
the same structure,
but with different
decisions about which
named components are
used for forwarding at
the network level
than you might
with content,
but at least
it's consistent
across this sphere
of applications.
And so I think that I
didn't mean to
suggest that
interoperability
necessarily
means that every name
in some application
level hierarchy
is represented or
used on the network.
But there is a
design space
that remains to
be explored about
which components
are exposed and
which components are left
at the application layer.
I think the
exciting thing from
an application point
of view is the more
the semantic
names are used
to access
decomposed content,
you can be more granular
about how you
access and use
components and think more
creative in how
they're fetched,
presented, and so on.
>> Good discussion.
Jeff, I'm not
sure if you have seen
Dave's question in
the Slack channel.
>> No, I don't
have it here.
>> So Dave was asking.
So it seems that the
remixing for
production should
be bi-directional
or invertible.
That means go forward
to the final mix or
backwards to
have the links
back to the raw footage,
which brings in a pretty
strong requirement or
opportunity for
explicit creation
and storage of
provenance data.
In ICN-NDN, we
don't seem to
have much research
or experience
was provenance
tracking pro
for NDNs dynamic content.
Michelle talked about
this earlier as well,
so Dave was asking
whether we have any
thoughts on this.
>> And just a couple
of notes and I'm
curious to hear the
communities opinion.
We did make the
content fabric
protocol natively
consider content
provenance both
in the encryption model
and the authorization.
And I mentioned
briefly that
the protocol is,
it's bipartite.
It is both the
content protocol
which will be
very, I think,
familiar and graspable
to this community.
And it is also a
blockchain protocol.
At the same time
implemented in
today's main network as
a for stack Ethereum
base blockchain.
But the main part of
that second aspect
is that the idea is
that to achieve the target
ends that we've all
been talking about,
you need to have
native provenance
in the content that
allows for
explicit transfer
of ownership when
a derivative of
core content
is created for someone
to experience,
to access, to view.
A couple of key
points about that is,
it's interesting, again,
it's worth reading
that paper to get all
the nuances to this.
But what that means is
that no content
exists that
isn't effectively
encrypted based
on ownership.
That's been
codified through
blockchain identity in
blockchain consensus,
and also no versions
of content evolve without
recording version
hashes in
a scalable way to the
protocol blockchain.
And then on the
other side of that,
no reading access to
content or derivatives
happens without
blockchain authorization.
When you get into
practical terms that
authorization can
also go into data,
which can be also part of
the content
objects in this
attested to on chain way.
So the policy itself
becomes tamper-proof.
So you start to
create this pipeline,
if you will,
of true ownership and
versioning control
that is intrinsically
backed by blockchain
semantics.
This is, I think,
a really important
idea because,
to what Jeff said,
the applications of
this are really around
digital IP, digital
intellectual property.
And going back to my
original comments,
if the ultimate goal of
this better the
Internet economy
and users of the internet,
the real driver here
is to have a means of
harnessing a
decentralized
approach that's more
efficient and that's owner
controlled, right guys.
And I don't want
to get too deep into
the blockchain side.
I realized that's not
these communities focus,
but I think it's a
very important partner
in this whole conversation
to really get to where
everybody is trying to go.
It's also interesting for
the computer
scientists here,
it's a whole
another dimension,
the security
aspects of this are
very well tied to the
name data principles.
And I think many people
and researchers,
grad students in this
conference would
enjoy getting into
that space as well.
But that's the way
we think about it.
That's how the fabric
protocol works.
It's also the
commercial drive.
As Todd said, everything
we're doing every
day is about somebody's
creative IP.
Some of it very big,
some of it independent,
that is going to
get distributed and
owned by somebody
else on his new way.
>> That's great. Thanks.
>> So I would like
to use the rest of
the time to give
people a chance
to understand your
system better, Michelle.
So there are a
couple of questions
in this lecture already.
Maybe to start this off.
So it says something like
a one-minute summary
that you could give
to describe the
key properties
so that we're all
on the same page,
maybe differentiated
against other systems.
So that's like
one question.
What's the difference
to life or to IPFS?
Something that makes
some people know.
And then I like to
call some questions,
and then we'll
discuss this further.
>> Since I'm the
oldest person
in the mix between
Todd and I in this,
I'll give very short.
And I do think it's
worth a read of the paper.
The biggest difference
from everything else,
biting off pieces of this,
is the fabric
protocol does
attempt to take on
the whole problem,
and by the whole problem,
I mean what we've been
talking about here,
the idea that
you would create
an application layer
protocol intended
to run on top of not
just IP, but TCPIP.
That would be natively
suited for
compositional content,
storage, and self
serving in a
net-scale network.
That implies also
decentralized in
native ownership through
the content's life cycle.
And then the protocols
number one
design principle
comes from this space,
which is that you would
design the protocol to
be based on
content-native routing,
and addressability.
Then, as far as the most,
I think visual metaphor
for folks is to think of
a pipeline for all output
in a decentralized network
that serves rich content.
That pipeline is
compositional in the sense
that both the raw
bytes as well as
the data metadata that
would then be under
the control of
software also stored in
the network
operate together
to generate the output,
whether it's streaming
or static data.
And as you all know,
there's doing that
as a pipeline in
a infinitely scalable
Internet environment
with predictable latency
implies many things,
but the protocols
architecture then is
built for really
those n states.
The lowest layer for
content routing and how
these parts exist
in a network
and are found which
will be the most,
I think, native to
what everyone here
thinks about.
The content
object structure,
which is the referential
structure that
guides that.
And then there is an
interesting in
network design and
implementation that uses
LOVM as operating on.
The best way to
put it so that
objects can operate on
themselves through
the protocol stack
to do things like
real-time transcoding.
So that's extensible.
And then, to
just point the,
I suppose the top layer
of if you think of
the protocol stack,
is the way that
those functions are
addressable, their
URL addressable.
And the fabric protocol
knows how to resolve
those URL names to
this pipeline functioning
in a decentralized way.
Now, of course, there
are many questions
about how do you
get that to work,
that ever-growing
scale, ever number,
larger number of objects.
How do you guarantee that
the latency and
performance
is going to be consistent?
How do you make
sure that the way
the metadata interacts as
part of the
objects is truly,
fully extensible
without limit?
Then, on the
ownership side,
how do you ensure that
the authorization
and the encryption
of content,
and the blockchain
control,
is generalizable
and scalable?
Those are all the
hard problems
the fabric attempts
to address.
So I hope that's helpful.
I would say first step,
read the paper,
and then please
feel free to
interact with us.
We would love to
collaborate on applications
and can answer more
and tell you some of
the things that are
unsolved problems
that we're still
working on.
>> Let's take my
view at least one
question from [inaudible]
because there
are some good ones just
on the transcoding
that you mentioned.
So a question
by Dave about
the just-in-time
transcoding.
The question is, the proxy
re-encryption
capability is quite
cool but what leads
the content owners to
trust you are
transcoding code?
And it was on.
[OVERLAPPING] Any
on-demand transcoding
since they don't
trust anybody.
>> It's all supposed
to be trustless.
It's a great question
and that all
gets into the trust model.
The nodes themselves,
which run
the whole stack or
active participants
in the blockchain.
And that principle
is fundamental to
the trust model
and also to
the data provenance and to
the economics of it all.
And to be specific each of
the nodes has a
blockchain address,
and conducts its
trusted operations
authorized based on
its blockchain
address and contracts
for what the nodes
are permitted to do.
So your point is correct.
The nodes are trusted in
those operations
and they do
that trust under
the authentication
of their Blockchain
identity.
And then the
operations that they
do are authorized based
on the contracts that
the base contracts that
support the content.
Finally, those of you
who are into blockchain
know there are
really complicated
questions about
true decentralization
in this.
And I can tell you
from a practical
standpoint,
you have to launch
these things in
a centralized manner as
in centralized naught
and architecture,
but no ownership
to get them going.
And it's a real
practical thing
to grow the node,
providing ecosystem to be
sufficiently decentralized
and governance to back
the architectural
assumptions.
This is a real thing.
That's why I said in
my opening comments.
If you really want
to dig in on this,
we need to have lots
of participation.
Otherwise, we're going
to be stuck with
the clouds that we've
had for 20 years.
>> This is a really
good discussion.
I think we could go on
for quite some time.
Unfortunately, we have
to take a break now.
So you have some
additional questions
on this lecture
if you have time,
it'll be great
if you can have
a look and answer them.
For now, let me compute
this a little bit.
So I think that
was a really
cool pennant,
really interesting.
And I think we barely
scratched the surface
about like in
deeper problems
or some interesting
challenges.
I think we got some
really good ideas
and also quite
good understanding
what DFP system tries
to do is quite
interesting for the
Indian community,
I think to see
what is all needed
from a commercial content
distribution perspective,
that was really cool.
And I think there
are also some good
connections between,
like the thoughts
that we heard from
Jeff and Paolo
about interesting
opportunities.
So the way that
we could also
conceive certain systems
in a different way.
And I wanted to
thank you very
much for this very
dense but super
interesting.
I hope people find it
useful and enjoy
your break.
And hope to see
you again soon.