>> It's 1:30 and we
should probably start
our first
afternoon session
which is focused on
ndn security and will be
chaired by Christos
Papadopoulos.
I have the first
presentation up.
Christos is a professor
at the University
of Memphis
in the Computer
Science Department.
Before that he was with
Colorado State
University and
the University of
Southern California.
Recently he
spent two years
as Program Manager at
the Department of
Homeland Security
between 2018 and 2020.
Go ahead, Christos.
>> Thank you, Loppy.
Let me give everyone
a chance to sit
down after dinner.
Hope everybody enjoyed it
through where your
staff know that.
So this is the
security session
and gives me
great pleasure
to welcome Eric
who's been a
long time UCLA
and NVA member.
But he's promised that
he's seen for something
completely different.
So Eric, I'm not
going to read
your entire bio.
But he's an
assistant professor
at George Mason
University,
coming up for
tenure pretty soon.
And he focuses on
Internet cybersecurity,
objects security,
and large-scale
Internet measurements.
I can attest to that.
I've seen him work
on these things.
So, Eric.
>> Thanks, Christos.
Hey, everyone.
So like you might
see in the title
of this talk,
this will be a little bit
different than some of
the subjects we've been
talking about today.
But I can tell
you a few things.
One, I think it'll head in
the direction that you
all might find
interesting.
Two is, I usually like to
give talks very
conversationally.
I don't have the luxury
of a long enough
time slot for that.
But I will say that I have
very thick skin and
if you have something
interesting to say
whether you think I
like it or not, I'd
love to hear it.
So please save up
some good questions
and consider this
discussion topic.
So anyway, I'm going to
talk a little bit about
knowing the road ahead.
Lessons that we've
learned and can learn and
should learn from
IP DDoS in
today's Internet.
So DDoS attacks
are perennial,
but are they inevitable?
It's perhaps one of
the oldest sicknesses
that still plagues
the Internet today,
distributed denial
of service.
The first nominal
attack of a botnet and
volumetric fashion
against the
Internet was over
21 years ago and it was
from something called
the Trin botnet.
Then if you flash
forward to 2015,
there were programs
that were started
to be formed
that said, hey,
one day we got
to worry because
these attacks are getting
bigger and bigger.
They might get to
be one terabit.
Then in 2016, less
than a year later,
Krebs On Security online
got blasted off the
Internet by what was
then the nominally biggest
internet DDoS
attack ever seen,
it was somewhere
north of 665 gigabit.
Then later that year,
a service provider
named OVH got
taken to town at by
1.1 terabit attack that
was launched by
CCT cameras.
And then later that year,
Dyn got knocked off the
face of the Internet
by another massive
DDoS attack that's
even bigger,
1.2 terabit by
the Mirai botnet.
And the volumes of
these attacks have just
grown and the
tools that Ms.
Greens had come up with,
clever ways to work
around what people
expected have also
just blurred.
Nevertheless,
the entire time,
researchers and community
members have
been fighting.
So as attacks
have grown so
too have our research
efforts to address them.
More and more
research put in,
the graphic doesn't quite
show all the lines
there at least.
So you can see that
this is a plot,
it's actually
a scatter plot
of research publications
year after year in
DDoS-related fields
like either DDos papers
or something related to
network security
adjacent to DDos.
It's just poured in
year after year and
billions of dollars
have been poured
into the problem
year over year.
But attack volumes
have kept up,
and actually in
many cases have
exceeded what we've been
doing to try and
mitigate this problem.
So the talk that
I'm giving out.
So we conducted
a large-scale
architectural analysis
of the research
literature,
the literature in general
of what people have been
doing and what has
fundamentally enabled
DDos attacks.
In order to try and see
why are we chasing
our tail here?
How can we break
the cycle?
And what I'd like
to say is that I
think what we've
done is we've found a
very compelling
path forward.
So let me give you an
outline at the top.
So our evaluation
was over about
25,000 DDoS-related
papers from
the past 30
some odd years.
I'm going to talk
a little bit about
our observations
of the basic
attack surface that DDoS
exploits which I realize
is not something that's
specifically
relevant to NDN
unless you listen
to the whole talk.
So keep with me.
Then I'll talk a
little bit about
the basic architectural
advantages of
NDN in this
cybersecurity setting.
So real quick,
any questions?
I'm used to stopping
for questions,
I can't help myself.
Cool. So real quick,
I want to make
sure we're all
on the same page.
So probably everyone here
has some sense
of what DDoS is.
So if you do bear with
me and if you don't,
don't worry, I'll just
go through it real quick.
So imagine we've got
a content provider
up in the top
left-hand corner.
I've got a little
goofy transit
core of ISPs that
forward packets in
the middle Internet.
Let's say we have
three edge networks.
We have an access network
with some home users,
a laptop, and some phones.
We have an ICS network
or a bunch of IoT devices
or something and maybe
down at the bottom we've
got a wireless carrier.
So a DDoS attack
is there's a
service provider,
they are offering
a service.
So a miscreant
can compromise
an endpoint and
start sending
a lot of attack traffic.
And then she can
invite all of
our friends or just
commission her to
singular botnet to blast
a whole bunch of traffic
all over the place.
And a DDoS attack really,
there's a lot of
ways in which
people suffer from that.
But one primary way from
a volumetric DDoS attack
is those networks towards
the aggregation
point become
oversubscribed
and traffic just
can't get through
and they're swamped.
So as a side effect of
that if someone
actually wants to
transact with the service
they probably can't
because at that point
the pipes are awful.
So this problem, the
volumetric DDoS problem
is a problem that
happens in the aggregate
and it's an
inter-domain problem.
Lots of packet love
gets sent from lots of
edge networks and
maybe not even in
massive quantities
until they
all start to aggregate.
They act like tributaries.
Those tributaries
start to come
together as they
are converging on
the victim or the endpoint
then they become
torrents or they
become rivers.
They become too much
for someone to handle.
And so one just
side comment is
the actual size of
DDoS attacks are
oftentimes not
known or knowable
because when network
links are swamped,
packets get dropped which
means if you measure
how much attack traffic is
being serviced
at the victim,
that doesn't
include everything
got dropped on the way.
In other words, those are
usually underestimates.
So this is a problem
I'm a big fan of.
Go ahead, Alex.
You might have to
use the microphone
because they're
folks online.
>> This is just going to
cause me to speak even
faster as I run out of
time but it's all good.
>> I just wonder if
the volumetric attacks
of the prominent ones and
the low rate attacks
are no longer
an issue or there is
still a big [inaudible]?
>> That's a fair
question. I don't have
to repeat it because
you use the microphone.
Thank You.
No. The volumetric
attacks garner
the most attention
because insecurity,
if it bleeds, it leads.
So people hear about it on
the cover of New York
Times or something
like that.
Whereas the low and slow,
those can actually be
way more pernicious is
where APT [inaudible]
other stuff.
And it just doesn't
get as much headlines.
Also, if it's
a big bridge,
people try not to
divulge any more
than they have to.
But a big sledgehammer
volumetric attack
usually leads
to headlines.
So this is admittedly
just one of
the security
problems we face,
but it is just one.
So anyway, this is a
proverb I really like.
I overused the
heck out of it,
but to know the
road ahead,
ask those coming back.
So if DDos is a plague
for today's Internet,
then can its symptoms,
can its nature, can
our responses to it?
Can it teach us
something about
the architecture
for tomorrow,
what we do and don't need,
what does and doesn't fit.
And that was one of
the main motivations for
the architectural
study we did.
I say architectural
because
we've looked at the
actual architecture.
A lot of what we read in
the literature was
treating symptoms,
but we wanted to understand
what was going on
underneath from
the architectural
perspective.
So like I said, we
called about
25,000 papers,
RFCs, patents,
anything that
seemed like it was
related to this field.
We went back about 30
plus years and we made
a very close inspection of
about 260 of those.
And so what we looked at
was what was discovered
through all this work.
What was rediscovered
And what meant was
deployment success.
So in a sense, we looked
at this as like
requirements gathering.
If you've ever done
software engineering,
you know one of
the steps is
requirements analysis.
We looked at this
as a clear and
present problem for
a very long time.
And we said, Well,
what are the
requirements of
remediation and what are
the basic requirements
to launch
it? So what we found.
The DDos, does
a huge space of
different types of TTPs
it can vary widely in
form and function.
But there are
just a very few basic
vulnerabilities
in the IP layer that
fundamentally enable it.
And moreover,
what we saw in
looking across this
massive corpus of
community
literature was that
there's certain
design patterns were
repeated over and over
again as people
would do a proposal.
A lot of times they'd
be doing a lot of
the same things over
and over again.
Further, we
actually looked
at what's actually
deployed,
what's actually
being used?
And what we found is
that misaligning.
Who pays for something,
who has to commit
to upgrading
something and who's going
to benefit from that?
Is a good way to
make sure that
what you're doing isn't
going to get deployed.
So I'm going to
go quickly through
this because
I would rather you read
our work than me try
to summarize it too much,
but I'll tell you
a bit about it.
So we took this
big giant corpus
of literature
and we broke it
down into certain
categories.
Though some of the
approaches that
we studied were
preventative.
They tried to prevent
DDos attack traffic
from entering the network.
Some of them
were focused on
detection when traffic
is being sent.
It's not trivial to be
able to determine what
the difference is in
good traffic and
attack traffic is.
Some approaches focused
on actually doing that.
Then the flip side
of that is some approaches
focus just on mitigation.
They focused on
like look someone
else is going to
actually classify
the packets.
Once that happens,
how do we
separate wheat from chaff?
And then finally, some
of the approaches where
holistic they did
mitigation and detection.
So rather than give
you that corpus,
I'll just go over
it real quick and
have a bunch of
footnotes for you.
So some of the preventative
ones were simple.
They use filtering,
things like
BCP 38 and 84,
ingress and
egress filtering.
And some of them
proposed put state into
router's the IP has got
stateless forwarding
but some of them
said like but one
way to fight DDos,
is add state to
IP let's put it
in the routers.
Some others said, that's
a really good idea.
I thought of it,
but I'm going to put
it in the packet.
Some others, there
was a large section
of literature called
capabilities.
And what capabilities
did is they basically
said we should do some
admission control.
You shouldn't be
allowed to send
traffic unless you've
been granted permission.
So they use an RTS
authorization model
and even one of
them started using
an overlay to
implement this.
And there's lots of other
stuff in our paper,
but lots of other
works that we
covered but a lot of them
reuse these
design patterns,
state filtering,
state RTS.
Detection classification
systems broke
down into three
categories.
Basically, they
said you can
do detection at
the victim's side,
you can do detection
somewhere in the middle,
or you could do detection
at all the sources.
And they all have
their various
pros and cons.
If you do it at
the victim's side,
it's a lot easier to
tell what's
attack traffic,
what's not because
you're getting hit
with a sledgehammer,
but at that point it
might be too late.
Although you are highly
incentivized to
put a solution
like that in
your own network
because you're
getting clobbered.
And flip side the
distributed models say,
if we work as a community,
this is really great,
but nobody in the transit
core really benefits from
deploying this and also
you don't get
really good signal.
It's not always clear
what is and isn't
a DDos attack until
it really converges.
And that's even more so
if you do it
near the source.
Although if you do
due detection
at the source,
you can stop the DDos
before they even happen.
And then mitigation only.
For those of you that
are familiar
with networking,
there's black holing,
It's a tried and
true mechanism.
There's also
something called
mitigation as a
service where you can
pay a third party to go
off and take all
of your traffic
and scrub away
what's attack and
then returned to you
the service operator,
what's actually
legitimate traffic.
This one has some
benefits, for example,
you have a clear
relationship with someone,
it's probably for money,
no changes needed
the infrastructure,
etc and so forth.
And then one more
thing I'll just cover
from our literature
survey was that
a lot of approaches
actually proposed that
you could build
filters and
distribute them
through the networks.
Some of them said you
should distribute
those filters directly
in line using BGP.
Others said you should
build an overlay
so you can
distribute
filters so you as
a victim or
being attacked,
you should be able to
tell the Internet this
is the traffic you
should block for me.
That's this slide
in a nutshell.
Okay.
That's all the DDos
school I want
to talk about.
Unless you have
questions I'm
happy to talk
about details.
But what are the lessons
we learned from that?
So these proposals
repeatedly
asked for changes
to the routing
infrastructure.
They asked to have
state added the
stateless IP.
They asked to
have filtering
as a capacity that
you can request.
They asked to have
admission control
and outflow parody.
Looking at what has
and has not been
deployed is
a real sad or
interesting tale
depends which side of
the coin you're on.
Solutions that require
changes to the
infrastructure
of those solutions
, we didn't see
any diploy.
Of the solutions that
require deployment
by non impacted parties
in other words,
you do the work because
I'm going to
benefit from it.
We saw basically none
of those got deployed.
And solutions that align
the deployment costs
with incentives,
the ones that said,
you pay you benefit.
Well, we saw
Maas providers and
Anycast solutions.
So what the take-home
from that is,
Maas providers
are really what
protects us on the
Internet today from DDos.
Now, their whole
proposition is,
we're a network to absorb
the attack traffic,
which means we have to
be at least as big as
that attack traffic.
We have to absorb it.
So these attacks
are growing.
So a Maas providers
road is, I've grow too.
In the words of
one operator
who I agreed not
to ever name.
Their response to how they
keep up with this
is they said,
our job, we look at
our proposition is always
be ten times bigger.
And then he said
some other stuff I'm
not going to read.
So the costs and
incentives are
aligned and there's no
infrastructure
upgrades required.
This is what works
for us today.
Now, a distributed
attack probably would
indicate a distributed
defense but
those proposals have not
really found purchase yet.
So going forward,
today's butcher's bill
makes for
tomorrow's feast.
So I suspect I'm
preaching to the choir
that previous
work has said
NDN is inherently
DDos resistant.
Nevertheless, there are
some angles of attack
against NDM that could be
used to exploit it
for a DDos attack.
Lessons from the IP
DDos literature.
Flow parody,
really important.
In network state,
Fine-grained in network
control filters,
policy intent,
very important.
Backpressure mechanisms,
Inherent admission
control,
very important and more.
>> This is clear
motivation
for what needs to
be done if you
want to produce a
solution to address
the outstanding issues
the NDN may face
if it inter-domain
capacity
when someone try
to attack it.
I think what I
probably should have
led off with this,
if you start off
with something like
a DDoS resistant
architecture,
that should be
cold comfort
to you if that's where
you're going to stop.
Because that's what
people started off with,
with any number of
different networking
approaches
until miscreants found
a really clever
way to attack.
The attacks will come.
They absolutely will come,
and they will work
around whatever
you've left from before.
This will always
be an arms race.
The benefit is, if
you look at what's
happened in the past,
it can help you for what
comes in the future.
I'm reasonably
closed on time,
but I got a
question though, so
maybe that gives me grads.
In our work, what I
think we saw is that
the DDoS threat,
the DDoS problem in
today's IP Internet,
is a clarion call
for an architecture
like NDN.
I will not read
ahead of my slides.
So one of our
main findings
was that misaligning
deployment costs
with benefits is
a non-starter for at
least these types
of solutions.
And this is where NDN
really stands out.
I think this is probably
my main take-home.
NDN's general purpose is
what makes it
such a standout.
The true benefit of
NDN is that, yes,
it is inherently
DDoS resistant,
and yes, it can be
enhanced to be
even more robust.
But it's also all
these other things
that we're hearing about
today and tomorrow.
Said simply, when
people propose
a DDoS remediation
approach that
requires a
forklift upgrade
throughout the Internet,
we could argue about
whether that's
a good idea or a bad idea.
But if you do
it and you get
just a DDoS
defense solution,
then that's a
big outlay for
a very singular problem.
And that's why
NDN stands out.
It is this set of
things it's better at.
Among them is this massive
multi-billion-dollar-a-year
problem
that faces the Internet,
in addition to
everything else.
So here where you
too roll into
NDN saying that DDoS
is a big part
of the story.
It would then be
followed with
everything else
it's good at too.
So the dire state
of DDoS is like
a clear motivation for
everything else that we
need with the NDN as well.
And for those that
are wondering,
our paper is currently
under submission.
So with that, I
have it pretty
close on time [APPLAUSE].
>> Any questions for him?
>> What's the overhead for
those mitigation as
a service providers?
>> They're overhead.
I don't know what
you mean exactly.
Maybe I'll just
describe it.
>> Are you forwarding
the traffic
to them and then
they're clearing it,
and then forwarding
it back to you?
Is that the [OVERLAPPING].
>> For different
approaches, but the
most common is
what they'll do is
they will announce
your BGP IP prefix.
They will basically
route hijack you,
all traffic will
go to them,
and then they'll form
a tunnel to the
real service,
a GRE tunnel or something,
and send you the traffic
after they've
scrubbed it clean.
>> Does that
incorporate any delay?
>> It does.
[OVERLAPPING] The
principle motivation
for that though is,
if you are going to
succumb or go under
because of an attack,
they'll keep you out.
>> And I think
that there's
one detail that's
important,
that is, they can watch
your traffic because they
got your decryption key.
>> If you have HTTPS,
it doesn't work unless
you [OVERLAPPING].
>> So think about
your essence of doing
end-to-end security,
think it again.
>> It's true, that's true.
There's a fulsome set
of discussions
that happen in
back-offices
or places like
the IETF that are
very entertaining.
But I will say also that
lots of folks escrow
their keys to
CDNs as well.
And that's not exactly
what we're talking about,
but I will say
it unfortunately
becomes silent common
practice when you say,
this isn't DDoS,
so I have a CDN,
I just want really
low response times,
but you're going
to have to have
a copy of my private key.
So looking at what
works for CDNs might
actually also be,
I'm a big fan of
using what we've
got to get to where
we want to go.
So being aware of what
people are doing
and how it's
a poor substitute for
an architectural
approach is,
I think an important
perspective [APPLAUSE]
>> Alex, you're
coming up next.
You may like [inaudible],
which of course
is not needed.
So all I'm going
to say is Alex is
an Assistant Professor of
Florida International
University,
and he has given
us a lot of blood,
sweat, and tears about
NDN over a very long time.
Thank you, Alex.
So welcome, Alex.
>> Thank you.
This work again,
let's say it's a
preliminary work.
I guess it's a little
bit intersected with
the leaners done
in Memphis.
But again, the objective
for this work is
kind of apply the
schema approach
for the access
control policies.
And before kind of go to
the little bit of details
of that approach,
just a reminder, that
what we're dealing
with NDN is
data-centric security.
And a lot of work
that we did so far
was focused on
authenticity part.
So if each packet
is signed,
keys are signed and
forming a chain.
And from that we can use
the schema to do
the automation
of the sign-in process,
verification process.
But the same thing
technically applies
for the
confidentiality part.
So that each packet
can be encrypted,
meaning that they have
the data-centric
encryption in this sense.
This one, I just wanted to
emphasize this
slide a little bit
more because this
is what creates
a really big difference
from the today
access control
solutions and,
potentially have different
properties of how
the data is being secured
in the first place.
So instead of dealing
with always some kind of
server that
restricts access at
the right moment
that you do
in the request
to the data,
like I put in the picture.
We're potentially
dealing with
the security that is
embedded in the data.
I'm not saying that
the first approach
cannot be
implemented in NDN.
You can always implement
this type of
facility where you
have basically a server
that always
protects the data.
And when somebody's
requesting data,
it provides some
authentication credentials,
then the data being
encrypted for
that specific person or
a data session encrypted
for that person.
Again, this is all that's
possible and maybe
for some approaches,
it's still needed
to be implemented.
But we also
want to explore
the other approach
where the data
itself has the properties.
And security properties.
So it's going to be placed
anywhere and whoever
has access to
this data can
effectively get it
and then decrypt it.
And who doesn't have
access to the data,
okay, that's where
comes the implication.
You still can get the data
like encrypted version,
but you should
not be able to
access, you can
decrypt it,
at least in principle,
without using all those
fancy decryption
hacking mechanism
that takes other years.
I'm not going to there.
So with this
data-centric security,
the question is, how
to define this policy?
Who sets this policy?
Easy question,
whoever owns
the data or logically owns
the data should
define the policy,
but rather how this
policy looks like?
How's it enforces?
And then other question
that I'm not going to
answer in this talk at all
is about long-term
security.
The question about
the data itself.
I want to
emphasize because
there were some
conversation
on Slack about this point.
The fact that a lot of
times in NDN we're
talking about
the data that
been produced
and stays in the network
for a long period of time.
Whether it's true
or not true,
this assumption
that this data
exists forever,
or is the data a
femoral in some sense,
it's a big question.
And the work for
the data-centric
security and
name based access control,
it's more for constantly
produce data and with
usability of this data,
having a limited
time span basically.
Because this simplifies
problems significantly.
You don't deal with
the thing like,
what happened to the
data in one year.
Like how can I change
access to the past data?
So those are really
hard problems and,
I don't know,
maybe the first
solution where you have
a gateway for that
long term data would be
a preferable solution
to that one.
>> [inaudible]
time limit network
magnitude is?
Is it seconds,
is it minutes,
is it hours? [inaudible]
>> I don't even have the
answer to that question.
Again, because if
I give the answer,
somebody can come up with
a very counterexample
of what would happen if
I hack you in five minutes
so I could change access
in two seconds for
some of the data?
It's hard to give
specific timeline.
But in this case,
the focus of
this work is on
schema so I just
keep introducing
this concept.
So as I already mentioned,
for the name-based
access control,
this is the approach we
have explored already
and hopefully many
of you are familiar.
We have the concept of
the access manager
who defines
the policy and how the
policy looks like.
It's actually
effectively using
the key encryption key
and key decryption key.
So with the key
encryption key,
this defines some kind
of a granularity
of the control,
like everything that falls
under a single
encryption key,
you can control it
as a single unit.
And there are
some crypto keys,
the different
ones underneath
but still you can control.
For the decryption
key, basically,
if you give access to
someone by encrypting
this decryption key
using his public key,
for example, then he will
get access to
the whole granularity
of the data.
So the enforcement
actually at
the data production stage,
kind of because
you encrypt
data as soon as
you're producing
and maybe for the
long-term stuff
you have to
re-encrypt the data.
But again, that's much,
much longer story.
And again, I can bring up
the concept of granularity
because this are
things that we introduced
as part of an index
access control,
but didn't really go into
much detail of how it's
supposed to be doing.
So for example,
each data packet,
it's not necessarily that
the data packet will
belong to so-called
single granularity,
on the flip side,
is that there's
only one way to control
access to a single
data packet.
Maybe this data
packet belongs to
the dataset of the
course data that is
access to more open
and the same time this
data packet
also belongs to
the more restricted
access of data.
So you want to have
different abilities
to do the same stuff.
Again, in principle with
the [inaudible] X
control is possible,
but there are
some implications
that I mentioned
in a minute.
For the flip
side, the KDK,
again is for the few
ways of how to deal with
the KDK distribution when
played with the
attribute-based encryption.
Again, in all cases,
there are some
implications of that.
And if I give a little
bit more on, again,
granularity, I'm
just basically
restating myself.
But in this, for this one,
I just want to
get more specific
what I mean with
granularity.
And in this work
we try to leverage
the naming.
So if the data has a name,
it has a hierarchical name
if the data still has
hierarchical names,
so we can actually
leverage this
for the defining
granularity.
And it doesn't mean you
have this granular for
every single level
of hierarchy.
This basically
just defines
what kind of datasets
you want to control.
But if by the
schema operations,
there's only one set
that being controlled,
then there will be
one granularity.
If there could be
multiple ways you want
to control this data,
then it's somehow will
create multiple
granularities.
There are some, a
little bit of details.
I probably not going to
go to the highlights,
but effectively the access
manager producer
that produce data,
consumer that
consumes data.
In this one I
want to highlight
is the actual enforcement
building blocks
on the ground,
how things are
actually working.
So whenever
something follows
the specific granularity
it means that
the encryption key for
the specific data or
specific small subset
is being encrypted by
the key key for
this granularity.
So in this case,
I showed that
this specific key,
at a single data
packet of network,
a few data packs that
were encrypted by
this symmetric key subject
to three granularities
at the same time,
meaning that you
can control them
independently.
So either give access to
everybody using
the one or give
access to very
restricted amount
of people on
the flip side.
For the KDK, the
picture is similar,
but there's a few
complications.
So because there's
multiple granularities,
granularity you have
multiple parties
that you can
grant access to.
And that's the end
of the sentence.
And the reason I'm
bringing this names here
is just to highlight
a complexity of how
many things needs to
happen in order to
grant permissions.
So you have to generate
the key key for
appropriate things.
You have to potentially
create multiple key keys.
You have to inform
the data producer
that which
specific datasets
needs to be signed
by which specific,
I'm simplifying
the picture,
but what kind of
encryption key you're
supposed to use.
And on the flip side,
for the consumer side,
and this is the problem
that we actually face
before is I can
get the data,
data indicates which
symmetric key was used.
But then I don't
necessarily know
which policy it falls
under and whether I
have access to
this policy.
So the way we can
and this is kind of
highlight my
current state of
affairs is the fact
that we did it for
cheating in a
[inaudible] X control
for the consumption part,
we just assume there's
a single granularity for
a single piece of data.
So if we ask for
the prefix of CK,
it will give you
a data packet
that has CK encrypted
by the specific
policy and we
just assume that
only one exists.
And then by somehow magic,
just extract from
this policy,
you can convert this
key key into the KDK
and append my own key
and assume that I will
ever have access
to this policy.
If I get the data packet
back, I have access.
If I don't have
data packet
back, I don't have access.
But it's a little
bit of complicated.
And if you have
multiple policies
and multiple keys
that you own,
is the question what
is the process to
actually determine
whether you have
access and under which
policy you may
have access to.
So what I'm saying is
the motivation work
for the SEANAC,
I forgot what it
even stands for.
Somewhere access
controls somewhere
like a schema encryption.
But essentially we had
a long conversation of
how exactly to realize
this stuff and invented
Versec inspired
schema policy.
>> Schemas which
end up to be
separate schemas one
for the encryption
and one for the actual
access control.
This work is still
preliminary,
so we defined, we
did a few examples.
And this is just
one example
of this granularity.
If you look at
this picture,
you may see that
it resembles
the same format that
was defined but their SEC,
but for specifically
the encryption.
So there is a
publication that
defines how it should be
encrypted, what locations.
But again, the
objective of
the whole thing is not
the schema itself,
but rather use the schema
that is more like a
human readable, human
interpretable
specification.
I'm not saying that it's
very easily interpretable
specification,
but it's concise
representation to
define how I want to
control the data.
Because you may
define that I want
this publications
be encrypted
by this and this.
The other one be
encrypted by different
granularities.
But at the end,
I need to look for
the encryption part.
It needs to know how
many granularity
should exist.
And given a data packet,
which granularity
I should use.
The end result
is some form
of rules that needs to be
given to the data producer
of how to deal with the
key encryption keys.
Like produce the data,
I create the
symmetric key,
how many times I encrypt
the symmetric key into
to protect this datasets?
And this is the schema is
supposed to give us,
and this is the
preliminary way
of doing the process.
And I had actually
highlighted this
to any device
published under
this bedroom
camera will know.
And this name is
basically saying
that it only controlled
by the single granularity.
So there is no point
of creating anything
else and there'll be
just one key,
encryption key.
For the other one
for the thermostat,
there are actually two
paths of the control.
Basically the same data
can be controlled
in two places,
by two parties, by
two ways to control.
So for
the key encryption,
that's the objective.
So we want to know
how many keys should
exist in the first place.
For key decryption,
it's what we have
encrypting per
individual user.
How do you get
this users is also
the question and how
to get the keys,
how to verify the keys.
So it's the
problematic part.
So we try to hear,
again, preliminary.
Try to define concept of
role-based access
control granting.
So you can just write
a schema that says,
so in my home, I'm owner.
Maybe define
some set of keys
that belong to
the owner and
say this data
should be accessed
by the owner,
this data should not
be accessed by the owner.
And that's all that schema
defines, which
then converted,
first of all to the set of
the key decryption
keys that can be
pre-created or
automatically created
as the time goes,
published and so that's
one part of the key
decryption key.
Can be used by the
access manager
to predefine the access
control policies.
Those keys should
be pre-created.
On the flip side, it
also can be used by
the consumers to actually
know whether they have
access to the data,
and know how to
actually decrypt,
what is the path for
the data decryption.
So I think I highlighted
this in this example.
Again, what is
preliminary?
That's probably
all the results.
I show you two
more examples
that are probably not
going to go in detail,
but just to highlight
that we are planning
to use this
for the hydro project
or assesment.
So this is what we
wanted to talk
a long time,
but we keep postponing.
But we already defined
encryption schema for
the hydrophilic
sensitive data,
nonetheless
sensitive data.
And on the flip side for
the key decryption keys.
As I said, this is
totally preliminary work.
What we really
want to show
is for
the evolution part that
we haven't yet done,
is how easy is to actually
define those policies and
what is the result
of the policies.
So for example
instead of someone
needed to create
a bunch of
those key decryption
keys say by manually,
you just define a policy
or redefine the policy
and automatically
things have been created
and publish it
in repositories.
So set of the key
encryption keys that
potential rotates every
hour or every day.
And same for the
decryption keys.
As soon as a
person's public key
is discovered or if
somebody sends it
new keys being
published into
repository and
that entity is
given access.
So that's the basic
stuff that we working,
but there are tons
of other questions.
So for example, is
this policy is
public or not?
This depends on
the environment,
but also
maybe something needs
to be protected.
But maybe you don't
want to disclose
the complete schema
to everybody
who potentially can be
in this environment,
but only extract parts
that are relevant to
a specific entity and only
give the parser
to the entity.
We want to explore
not just granularity
based on the hierarchy,
but also some
additional things for
example time, geographical
coordination.
So this is the different
types of defining
the granularity that
not necessarily
directly related to
the name of the data,
but some metadata
of the data.
And there's some
many other issues
including the one
that the timing
issue that was mentioned.
I don't know how
long I went,
but I think it
was 20 minutes.
>> The first one
question [inaudible]
>> Are you sure the
microphone is on?
>> There you go.
>> Should be green light.
>> That works. So
Kathy is asking,
so is the idea
a single key containing
all the attributes?
>> Single key.
I have to process
this question.
I'm not capturing
it honestly.
>> Okay. So you
can answer it.
>> I will try to
process it and
maybe ask clarification
question,
what do you mean
by the attributes.
>> Yes Eric.
>> So I just had a
real quick question.
Just maybe more like
future work thing.
So security postures
are really hard to
encode just in general and
go into our back is not.
Now, have you thought
about like looking at
a user study or
looking at how
people have
actually wanted
to configure their homes?
NDN aside, just to see
how you would
model that and see
how easy it is to
make a schema or
what assistance
people would
actually need for
that because,
home users are not
always the most
cutting edge?
>> We haven't
looked. We've tried
to go with from
the home example.
Because one
side is simple.
On the flip side, it
can be fairly complex.
But yeah, like we did
not yet have looked in
detail in
existence stuff,
but then we should.
>> I think in the
interest of time,
we'll take other questions
offline. Thank you, Alex.
[APPLAUSE] So we're going
to go to the next talk.
>> Very good. Come on.
So Tianyuan Yu is
a PhD student.
>> Yeah.
>> You need to plug
in [OVERLAPPING].
>> Use the slides
[OVERLAPPING]
>> Something.
[inaudible] Yeah.
[OVERLAPPING].
>> Yeah.
>> So Tianyuan
is a PhD student
at UCLA, working
with Lixia,
and his interests are
in security bootstrapping,
certificate management,
and access control.
And he's going to
talk to us about
security bootstrapping
for Hydra.
>> Thanks, Alex for
giving that talk about
access control and this
talk we're going
to talk about
something happens before
the access control,
that is before getting
the encryption key
and decryption key,
how you get the name?
How to get a certificate?
Things like that and the
trust policy, the
trust schema.
And this work is
done by the Hydra
team and especially I
want to thank Alex for
his valuable comments to
making this package work.
For people who don't
know Hydra yet.
This is a federated
file storage project.
We have organizations
that contribute to file
servers into
some authority
file storage
like the demo shows,
and they share data
with each other.
And the users running
apps side down let's say
their laptops or
personal computers
and try to
upload the
individual files
or download
individual files.
And we have a Hydra,
say Network
Operating Center
actually manage the Hydra
apps on the user side.
On the server side,
especially where
I'm managing
the trust
relations and the
user-written
in red access.
And this Hydra app and
the Hydra NOC make
a trusted domain for
the Hydra application.
Which means the
Hydra NOC is
really a domain controller
of this application.
Now the question
is, how to make
the system work and how
to make the system
work securely.
And in order to enable
the Hydra application
as to clearly communicate,
we need some pieces
to be configured.
First, we need a trust
anchor because you
know who should be the
source of the trust,
which should be the Hydra
NOC self-signed
certificate
because it's really
the domain controller.
And so you know
this is the source of
the entire domain.
Then as a user application
or your server
application,
you need to get a
name, a Hydra name
and that name should
get certified.
So that name also
need to follow specific
naming conventions.
That should be
a Hydra name.
Say I can have
a name /hydra/node
to represent,
this is a server node
in the Hydra
application and I can
like derive
folder-named components
by the last naming
conventions.
And if we have such
naming conventions,
the Hydra NOC operator can
easily manage the
trust relations
within the domain to
say who can access,
for this organization can
access this type of data,
things like that, and
also we need a
trust schema.
So we know
each applications
they are aware of,
the security policies
and they know
how to validate the
application data,
the current performance
class policies to
say this key is
allowed to sign
this type of data,
and that key is not
allowed to do so.
And we need 1, 2, 3, 4,
four pieces need
to configuring to
the application
before they
can communicate securely.
And among the four pieces,
there are some
relatively simple ones
like the trust anchor
and trust schema,
because they
are relatively
stable because
trust anchor as a
student certificates
not very
frequently updated,
also the trust.
So we started from
installing trust anchor
and trust schema.
The Hydra solution is
that we embbed that
the trust anchor and
the trust schema into
the application package.
And we utilize
the existing
authentication process
of this software
distribution.
Then we have a Hydra
application running on
the remote host and we
have the Hydra NOC,
as the trust
domain controller.
We know that there's
a certificate authority,
for example, GitHub,
and the domain controller,
which is a Hydra NOC
can publish of course,
the human operator can
publish some code on
GitHub and of course,
that is based on
the assumption that
domain controller trust
the certificate authority,
which certifies a GitHub,
I think that is
the research.
Then, on the other hand,
on the application side,
if the application
owner also trust that
particular certificate
authorities,
then the domain controller
or publish code on
GitHub and share
that specific
GitHub repository,
the GitHub link then
the applications that you
can download
with the code.
And here's the beauty of
an occlusion during code
downloading process,
because you need to
authenticate the
remote party.
First to say
that it's really
a GitHub and you also
will authenticate
that specific link
and you get the code.
Once you get the
code, you have
the trust anchor and
trust schema in slot.
But notice that this
trust schema is,
I would say those
initial trust
schema only used
for validating
data packages
during the
pushing process.
And a more complete word
in trust schema
needs to be
fetched through
normal Interests-Data
exchanges
offered at bootstrapping,
expressing
interest, ask for
the latest data package of
the trust schema then
install the latest
trust schema.
For the trust schema
installed here,
it's only for
bootstrapping purpose.
After we have
the trust anchor
and trust schema,
we still need to resolve
the name and certificate.
But before we
can have a name,
there are
some prerequisites
for obtaining it.
Say, if you're the
domain controller,
you want to say give
names to well, everyone.
So the first thing is
that you need to
authenticate the
remote party,
which is, in our case,
if you're server
application,
we need to know what
is our DNS name.
And if you have a
choice certificate,
we need to validate
your TLS
certificate to say,
you are really the owner
of that particular
device name.
For user application,
we're assuming you
control email address.
We can verify
your identity or
authenticate you by
verifying that
email address.
And authentication
and itself is
not enough because we'll
still want to have
some membership
control not everyone can
get Hydra name from
the domain controller.
So the NOC still needs
to know if you are
an allowed user or
an allowed server
in a cyberspace.
Say for the Hydra
user we have
a list of names.
If you are on that list,
well you're lucky
you can get a name.
Also for the user side,
we perform
membership control
over a list of
email addresses.
Still, we will check
if that email address
is in the list.
And after we do
the authentication
and authorization,
we still need to assign
Hydra names to ease
the schema writing.
I said, for server
name we say
/hydra/node representing
this is really
a server node?
And for the divided thing
as naming convention
and for the user we do
/hydra/user followed
by the email
naming convention,
similar thing.
But with this, we can
actually ease
the trust schema
writing to make
the policy maker.
Yeah, have a simple life?
>> And now we can talk
about how we
actually do that.
So here I will show a
very abstract dataflow.
Now, not very precise,
things as they
have changed,
but it will give
an overall idea
of how the protocol works.
So first, suppose I'm
a server application and
I want to ask the NOC,
please authenticate me and
give me a hypername.
I first ask the
NOC to say,
this is my TLS
certificate,
and I'm walking
by and toss
the certificate chain to
your digital certificate.
The Hydra NOC after
receiving it,
will verify it.
But even though the NOC
verifies that certificate,
it still need
to know that if
I'm the owner of
the certificate,
so it will send me
back a message to say,
please use this
certificate's private
key to sign a message to
prove that you own
the certificate.
As I signed the
message with
a signature and the NOC
can verify the
signature to say,
you are really the owner
of the certificate,
then you are
authenticated now.
Then I will perform
at least the check
to see if you
are welcome to
the Hydra system.
After that, the Hydra
NOC can give me
a name assignment by
converting the
previous name
into a Hydra name.
On the user side,
we do the similar thing,
but the difference is
that because we send
the email address to
the Hydra NOC and the
Hydra NOC will also
send a verification code
to my email address
out-of-band of course,
and ask me to
enter that email
verification code,
and echo that back
to the Hydra NOC.
I send the code back and
the NOC can know that
the remote party,
at least the
user in front of
the screen is
indeed that user
who control the
email address.
The Hydra NOC say, I
have authenticate to you
and let me check
if your email address
is in the list.
If so, I can give you
a name, assignment by
converting an email
address into Hydra name.
Well, after a
name assignment,
we say we have four
pieces class anchor,
class schema, name,
and certificate.
Then finally we come
to the certificate stuff.
And here is the certificate
issuance logic.
In general, there's
a certificate issuer
and there's a
certificate requester.
Usually, the
certificate requester
has a name assignment
and the issurer needs
to ask a requester
to prove that it
does own the name,
and if that the
challenge is to proceed,
issuer can certify has
requested the name.
Specific to this
difficult sororities
are doing this
in a different,
well, in a variety
of manners
and say this plus encrypt.
They only ask a requester
to prove that say,
if you can prove
that you can control
the corresponding
records by
making a text record,
or you can serve STB,
our chapter on
radar domain.
I can certify you
because last name
favorite foster,
trust worthiness and trust
that the operating system,
if the HTTP requests
can catch you there,
that means you indeed
control the domain.
So I can certify you.
And this challenge
is proof of possession.
They asked requester to
prove that they have
the possession of the
name or of the domain.
And in Hydra, we do
the similar approach.
That is, we are asked
for possession,
but we do a very
different way.
That is, we directly
use knock assignment,
name assignment as a
proof of possession.
Instead of asking you
whether you can fetch
that the HTTP object.
This proof of possession
is designed for
Hydra apps,
proving it is a
legit owner for
for a Hydra name.
If it end specifically,
this proof of
possession is a knock
and scientists the
packet in certificate,
the format, the gears
of possession packets.
We have the name following
this naming convention,
and it's certainly faster.
Hydra public key
with the court
also will have the
superior than a signature.
And if let them
prove that they own
the public key
are certified
in this proposition,
that means they own the
corresponding name.
For the name waste,
we apply the following
naming convention.
Will always have the first
component to be a keyword.
That means authenticate,
that means this is
marking this is a proof of
possession
data packet that's a
normal certificate.
Then followed
by the keyword
we have assigned the name.
And then in
this case it is
Hydra load you up.
So when the knock
were turned,
the name assignment is
your actual return this
proof all possession.
And the application can
further use this
for all possession.
Running the incentive
protocol to get to
a final certificate from
this exhibit issuer.
If we're putting
the workflow
together with our
Hydra package,
when the running the
Hydra package first.
The first thing we will do
is that we're going
to generate 22 and
then it is after
the Hydra,
because we want
to separate
the keys that is used
for different purposes.
They will have two keys.
One is only for
authentication and
authorization purpose.
That means that key is
used to assign the proof
of position a second.
And then Italy,
which is the slash
Hydra slash
certain signer,
that key is only
used for certificate
issuance.
Then I have a hustler
application
running on a host.
I have a TLS certificate,
I own the private key.
And because I installed
the package key top.
So I have the precedent
initial trust
schema configured.
I run a protocol to
prove I own that has
the private key and
the controller.
The controller,
which is an OK.
We'll check if my thing as
name is in that list and
return me of possession.
And there's proof of
possession already
says name
assignment because
this is encoded
in your name.
And then I will run
the protocol to say,
here is my prove
of possession.
And I can prove that
indeed on the public,
corresponding private
key of this possession,
then in turn
will return me
certificate with
the same name
presented in
their possession.
So we can see by
this approach,
the name assignment apart,
actually get
out of that and
the answer is only done
by the name authentication
and the assignment
department.
We have a Python
implementation,
although a
pretty enumerate
for the Hydra project,
and this is available
as a package as well.
We still have protocol
specification and
basic examples include and
we are still working
on the documentation.
>> When we actually
use this package,
the first thing
we will do is
that we need to
configure the NOC
because authentication
cannot start from
the scratch.
Authentication
always start from
some shared
trust relations.
We all say first,
here's the identity,
here's the name of the
domain that is /hydra.
Then I need to configure
the authentication and
the authorization.
For user, I
have a waitlist
, alice@cs.ucla.edu
and bob.
Those two are
allowed users.
Then for the server
because we are trying
to verify TL certificate,
we need to give
my definition
of trust anchors,
just to be configurable
to say I have a
different set
of trust anchors.
Then we can give a
waitlist to say,
here's the domain
names allowed
and we also need
to keep the validility
period of possession,
because the proof of
possession is used for
name assignment purpose,
it should not be forever.
In using this package,
we need to increment
the name assignment
function.
But actually implementing
within conversion rule,
say giving a
string converting
into NDN name in
our context that
is into a hydra
name and loading
the name of
assignment function in
controller runtime.
Then we have controller,
we call the function or
the assignment, and with
the specific name
assignment function
to the authentication
type user
and will know a server
name assignment
into a server type
authentication.
The final point
I want to make
here is that when
we do this project,
we actually
found that what
really makes the
hydra bootstrapping
different is that usually
assigning names
for entities
requires one being aware
of what domain naming
conventions you
will need to
have and actually
in many works,
we have seen the
domain controller
or the controller directly
signs certificate with
the name assignment.
In hydra we're
actually decouple
the naming formal
certification
and this approach actually
enable certificate
issuers be
agnostic to the
naming conventions
and focusing on the
certificate itself.
Like a certificate
management
revocation,
things like that.
That could to be
a lesson even for
us. Thank you.
[APPLAUSE].
>> Any questions?
>> I'm not sure if
it's a question,
but I'm just going
to say something and
then maybe you can
comment on it.
I wasn't sure I understood
what you're
proposing here.
You're talking about
bundling the code
with the trust anchor.
It's green here.
You're talking about
bundling code with
[LAUGHTER] okay
Sorry about that.
You're talking
about bundling
the code with the
trust and code,
you're talking
about basing
your trust on some PKI.
Isn't that a
centralized solution?
And then you talk about
the email addresses,
which is also existing
infrastructure,
maybe not so centralized,
but good luck.
That's a different topic.
What exactly are
you proposing here?
I don't know if I
have a question.
I'm very confused.
That's it.
>> I'm not actually
proposing a thing.
Just explain this is
what we did for
our application.
The key point is
that the application
and the domain controller,
they need to attribute
a neutral authentication.
And only point is that
for any authentication,
there's no free launch,
you need to have a
shared trust relations
in advance otherwise you
cannot authenticate.
You have to have
the shared trust
relations in
any case and using
GitHub is only one way.
>> Why did you
pick that one way?
[LAUGHTER] I'm
not referring
to GitHub as
literally GitHub,
I hope we're both
talking about
a central party that
is distributing code
and effectively.
[BACKGROUND]
>> I have changed
the slides.
>> I think the
slides are here.
>> I don't think
so. That's not it.
>> You didn't
send them out?
>> I did.
>> That's not it. He's
going to handle it.
While we're
switching slides,
Doran, is that the
proper pronunciation?
>> Yeah.
>> He's a first-year
PhD student
at UCLA working with Lisa.
He got his bachelor's from
Texas at Austin and the
master's from Cuba.
And he spent some time
in industry working
on Cloud security.
Because I have time to go
to the whole introduction.
When he's not
doing his PhD,
he supports
security startups
in the Web3 ecosystem,
so pretty busy
guy. Almost there?
>> Maybe, maybe not.
>> Ready?
>> I think it's
very [inaudible].
This is your very
best, it's here.
>> [inaudible]
>> Go ahead.
>> Let's see. Let's put
everything in
here not needed.
Cool. Meet a
puppy [LAUGHTER].
We'll go ahead and
get this going in a
second and I'll try and
get us back on time.
Well, I don't just
have to work.
There we go. Much better.
>> [inaudible]
>> Sure thing, no
problem. I hope
you all enjoyed
the little break.
So first easy question,
how many people here
have heard of NDN?
Cool. So a quarter
of the room.
How many people have
heard of Defined-Trust
Transport?
The same quarter, nice.
So essentially today
I'm just going
to give a quick
overview of what
Defined-Trust Transport
is which is
information-centric and
yet inspired
transport protocol
based off the work
of Kathie Nichols.
But different I'm going to
start with the sources.
Essentially. I'm
just going to
be summarizing the points
made in the IETF draft
submitted in 2022,
and if anyone wants to
get more hands-on with
everything there's a
GitHub link at the top.
There's Define-Trust
Communications toolkit;
that's interesting to use
, available on GitHub.
So Defined-trust
Transport essentially
it's many
broadcast-friendly,
brokeless publish suscrbe
transport protocol for
limited domains
especially good for
OT and IoT network
communications.
It allows for security
through easy management,
through scaling
up and very
expressed native rule sets
of who can say
what to which.
First we have a figure
of how the
Defined-trust Transport
actually sits
in the system.
It sits underneath
the application
either on top of
whatever system provided
transport that's provided,
or it can act as the
transport layer itself.
The application
communicates
with Defined-Trust
Transport
with the information
it wants
to convey and the
interests that it wants,
and to that it sends
it to the network
where different nodes
on the network will
add the information
on the interests to
its local sink
collections.
So first dataflow
and DeftT,
it uses the
SyncPs protocol
to synchronize knowledge
amongst nodes.
Every node has a
sunc collection of
what it has seen and
what it knows is
on the network,
and it keeps all
this information
and rather come
back to beig
what invertible
bloom lookup
table with digest
of the titles of
the publications
that have been
on the network.
So all communication
occurs via
two Protocol Data Units,
the cStates and the cAdd.
So the cState and
cAdds you all
might know as
the NDN interests packets
or something
similar to that.
It was inspired
by NDN TLV,
and then cStates contain
the IBLT with
the publication
knowledge of
what every node
knows on the network
and then cAdds contain
the application data that
actually wants to be
broadcast to other nodes.
It approaches the
dissemination
of information on
the network as
a set conciliation
problem overseeing PS in
which case cStates
are broadcast
periodically or
when the current
state is obsolete.
So this obsolution either
happens at timeout
or whenever
a neighboring node
sends its cState
out and the
local node sees,
oh, there's information on
the network that I don't
know in which case
my set is obsolete.
So there's
three kinds of cases
that can happen.
Either the transmitter has
the larger lookup table
than the receiver in
which case the
receiver sees,
oh, there's something
on the network that
I don't have
in which case,
the receiver is
out of date.
It sends its own cState
back to the transmitter,
and then the
transmitter replies
with the cAdd with
the missing data.
The second case is
the transmitter has
a smaller IBLT
than the receiver,
in which case the
transmitter is out of date.
The receiver sees
this and sends
the cAdd with the missing
data in response.
Then finally, transmitter
and receiver has
the same set of
information in
which case it acts
almost as an
acknowledgment of,
hey, the nodes are synced
up and everything is good.
Trust domains in DeftT
define the domain in
which the DeftT
can communicate.
Especially for OT,
this has a big advantage
over current protocols.
So in traditional Internet
of course you have
end-to-end encryption
with third-party CAs.
This doesn't
make sense for
operational environments.
For example we had things
about automotive
networking.
It doesn't make
sense when you have
a very explicitly
defined network
with known entities and
known communication.
So now you can
take it up to
traditional IoT
protocols which
does have end-to-end
encryption with
locally sign certificates
and protected
hardware trust
enclaves which is
really good against men
in the middle of attacks,
but it's still vulnerable
to insider attacks.
So one thing that's
really important
that DeftT and the trust
domains deep to mitigate
the threat to application
level attacks.
So in this case,
we have the DeftT
trust domain,
which defines
the domain of
the Defined-Trust Network.
It's defined by a
common trust anchor and
assigning chain
which allows for
less complication with
per device configuration.
Whenever you have
a new device
enrolled on the network,
all it needs to do is have
a certain identity package
with the trust rules
which means that
essentially whenever
you need to
add a new node to
the network all you
need to do is configure
the note itself.
There's no broker
to configure
or no peer notes to
configure either,
and then it also has
less misplaced reliance
on physical network
security to
actually secure
the data being
transferred across
the network.
How are we doing on
time? So DeftT has
a very explicit
trust schema in
which case it provides
rules for who can
say what to which.
It is made available
to every identity
in the DeftT or
rather every entity in
the DeftT has to have
this trust schema
to communicate.
So rather than just
relying on, hey,
this node should only be
able to say one
thing which makes it
vulnerable to
attacks where
a certain node
is hijacked,
this trust schemas says,
these nodes can only say
these things to these
kinds of people.
So it doesn't matter if
a node gets hijacked or
the network and start
sending out garbage.
That trust schema
prevents the node
from even sending
that out in
the first place even
if it is hijacked.
It uses a domain
specific language to
actually
expressively define
the trust rules
on the network,
and the toolkit comes with
the compiler that
actually checks
the soundness of the
proposed trust schema,
compiles it into
a signed binary,
and then packages it in
with every node
on the network.
So the binary is
used at each node
to both validate
the incoming packages and
validate and build the
outgoing publications.
Quite we have the
device enrollment
which makes it
much easier for
network administrators
to control
and administrate
their networks.
In this case again there's
no brokerage to be
configured and you
don't need to
do anything to
the neighboring peers
or anything like that.
There's an identity
bundle that is installed
out-of-band for
participation in
the Define-Trust Network,
which means that all
you need to do is build
the trust bundle and then
install it in a
secure fashion.
So this trust bundle has
the trust anchor
certificate
in the trusts schema
which explicitly
defines all the roles
and who has those
roles on the network.
And then the
membership identity of
the specific
node which has
the secret signing key,
the public certificate,
and all the
certificates in
the signing chain.
And then key
configuration,
installation and
update is left
to the administrators of
the network to do as they
see fit hopefully in
a secure fashion.
So define trust
security in
action. We're
almost through.
In this case, we have
pre-publication signing
instead of session-based,
which is especially
good in OT networks,
especially where you
have nodes that needs to
run on low-power or
low bandwidth
and hibernate.
So rather than TCPIP where
you have session-based
security,
this has almost
packet based
security where nodes
can hibernate,
join the network without
any deviation from
the protocol.
The certificate changes of
every publication
is validated.
System trust policies are
applied via the
trust schema
through the different
parts in the figure.
So essentially the
trust requirements
are at the top.
Do we have a pointer?
I hope they got
it, do they?
So out-of-band
the trust requirements
that need to
be, I appreciate you.
So essentially
out-of-band the
site policy and
the standard
conformance rules
are all put into
the trust schema
and compiled
upon enrollment
and that's put
into the trust schema
on the device.
The trust schema
is used by
the publication
validator and
builder to verify
everything that's going in
and everything going out.
And then lastly,
especially
for the ease of
development,
there's a shim
that actually
acts as a liaison
between all the
DeftT components
and the device specific or
the application
specific code.
>> For the last
two things,
we're going to
have examples.
So a commissioning
example would be
to create the
trust schema,
compile it into the
compact binary,
put it into the
identity bundle,
make the certificates, and
then install it into
the actual note.
And all you have to
do is repeat this
for every node
on the network.
And so finally, just an
overview of the security
that this is
particularly good for.
It protects against
all the data
is secured by the
trust schema.
It's protected by the NDN
validator and
prevents against
all application
level threats
that could be posed
to the network.
It has a validated
to protect against
corruption,
denial of service, and
information leakage
is reliant on local
network security.
The SyncTS
protocol provides
resiliency against
dropped PDUs,
especially with
the peer-to-peer
publish-subscribe
architecture.
The DeftT's trust
management engine
and the validator
protects against
spoofing of messages and
then replay attacks
are built into
the cAdd and cState
architecture as cAdd
can only respond to
a specific cState.
So if you have
someone doing
replay attacks of
different nodes
on the network,
they'll just be
dropped and ignored.
So in conclusion, this was
a much quicker than
expected overview
of secure brokerless
Pub/Sub for
operational technology
and IoT networks through
defined trust
transport with
a resilient set
reconciliation algorithm,
and that provides
a highly risk expressive
security framework for
well-defined operational
technology environments.
And we're back on track.
>> Great. Thank you.
>> Great. Any questions?
>> Questions.
[APPLAUSE] Put
this in the Slack,
but there's some
relationship here with
the DCT work that
was described
in the ICN 2019 paper.
Could you elaborate on
is this adding to that?
Is DCT a building
block part of this?
Kathleen says it's
an evolution.
[LAUGHTER]
>> Thanks Kathleen.
>> Thank you.
>> So it's describing
the work done there.
>> Any other questions?
>> Thank you. [APPLAUSE]
>> Randy?
Now we're going to
hear from Randy,
who is this current
CTO of Oprah networks.
Do I need to read
the whole thing?
>> No. [LAUGHTER]
>> Not what I'm
standing on here.
Not firm ground usually
when I'm up here.
Not a trivial problem.
Yes, so that's a phrase
I've been using all day
with operant team is,
this stuff is tricky.
It's not as easy
as it sounds,
then you get
interested in you
can't let go of
these problems.
But anyway, I'm here in
a somewhat odd
role in that,
I'm presenting
a presentation
around the use of
Trusted Platform
Modules with
the defined
trust transport
that Saran just reviewed.
And this was prepared
by operants principal
scientist Roger
Youngerman,
but he has personal
commitment this week,
so I get to present.
So that gives me one
level of deniability.
But even better is I'm
here as a user
of this stuff.
So I can bring you guys
problems and you can't
complain that I don
t know the answer.
So this is much
better than
being a peer
of this group.
I'm going to talk
about what we use it
for and then I'm going to
talk about how we solve
the specific problem
that's related to
trying to use
Indian type technology
in real-world
applications.
I would be happy
if someone
came up to me
afterwards and said,
you did all that
wrong because then
we could fix it but I
thought it was good
to expose what we're
doing in the sense of
no security by obscurity.
Here's how we
were implementing
the secure storage of
private keys because
that's fundamental.
To talk a little
about what we
do for those that
don't know me,
we're all about
energy right now,
so energy takes
many forms.
What I'm going to
talk about today is
particularly relevant
to utility natural.
So we have a
representative
here from
Constellation Energy,
who's one of our
major investors,
and we haven't
deployed systems now
running in Indian
interest data transport,
controlling 25
large-scale power plants
over most of
the East Coast.
And so we're controlling
a significant chunk of
the energy in the US,
electrical energy
through Indian,
which is not probably
widely known,
not that we're hiding it,
but I think it's
cool and speaks
to the progress that's
been made in Indian.
So what are the attributes
of an energy application?
Well, there's a bunch
of different users,
so there's people that
have utility systems.
There's all the way
down to homeowners.
There's people
who aggregate
energy at the
intermediates.
These things go over
complicated networks
with Cloud services,
all kinds of transports.
And eventually
they get down to
the distributed assets
that are out in the field.
So thinking back to
this morning in
the conversation
over the reasons that
there's barriers
to adoption.
I believe we found
a good application
which needs a couple of
the key requirements,
which is one, they really
care about cybersecurity.
Utilities are
serious about this.
Secondarily, it's
a limited domain.
So in the context of
the stuff that Tran
was talking about,
Kathy Nichols work,
undefined trust transport,
it is a very
restricted domain and
I think it was
Ivan maybe or
Kathy that said that the,
or maybe Lisa,
internet was
designed to deliver
everything,
everywhere and that's
the exact opposite of what
a utility [LAUGHTER]
network wants to do.
So there's quite a bit of
distinguishers
from what we're
doing to the
general problem
of Internet forwarding.
So what does that lead to?
Well, there's a lot of
drivers drive in our
business forward,
which is existing
utility networks
have relied
a lot on least private
fiber networks
to connect sites.
Works fine if you have a
500 megawatt utility-scale
generation site.
But what happens
when you have
a 10 megawatt solar
site on a Walmart roof?
It's not practical
to have leased lines
to every single thing.
A lot of the utility
protocols are so
old that they're
completely insecure.
The MP3 mod bus,
there just aren't concepts
of security there,
so there's an
opportunity to provide
security for
the first time
to the existing protocols.
Similar to the
conversation
around the
automotive buses.
A lot of network security
now is pointing to points
and they get a
bunch of firewalls.
You've got a whole
bunch of IT people.
I think Adam, you said
it takes four weeks
to change a firewall
rule in constitution?
Yes. So I think we
have multiple firewalls in
our system with NDM,
we don't have to
reconfigure them
each time we
add a new site
because we're
not using the
point-to-point protocol
security as much.
So a lot of valuables.
And then the
final thing is
renewables are coming
everywhere and
it's just huge.
I'm from California. So I
just see it every day.
But as I come out
to the East
Coast now all of
a sudden when I'm landing,
I see solar everywhere.
And so this is just
going to happen.
And you can't physically
control things once
they get small enough.
Most of the solar sites
in the world are unmanned.
There's nobody there.
This might be a fence,
but it's not going
to stop anybody.
And so security takes
a whole new look
for utilities.
I just spent like what,
10 minutes talking
about this slides.
But what we're doing,
the tightest of
previous talk is we're
using Kathy's defined
trusted shrank,
publish-subscribe
thing and we're
just in the process
of replacing
our first-generation of
interest data
exchange protocol
with a Pub/Sub version.
And what it's going
to do is give
all the access
control stuff
that define trust brings,
which is really
relevant to
a lot of the
previous talks
about how do you control
who can say what to who?
And so, just to give
a conceptual diagram,
we're going to be taking
different sources,
a complex mesh of
interconnections in a
whole bunch of sites.
So it's going to get
big and it's going
to get complicated,
but with the defined
trust thing,
the network can
be complicated,
but trust
relationships can be
maintained and distinct
from the network
connections.
>> So this was something I
put out here because
we're coming to
NIST floppy and I thought
I should do
something with NIST,
but also so I could
get someone else's
opinion about this.
What I'm going
to talk about is
secure storage
of private keys
and gateways so that
how we can make
these field gateways
very secure.
And as I was reading,
I was thinking
this is relevant
to like multi-factor
authentication.
So in a human
login situation,
you have the things
we're all used to.
You log in, so you
have a password,
something you know, you
get a text message
on your phone,
which is something
you have and maybe
you touched the
fingerprint
sensor or use your face,
which is something you are
and now you have
access to a system.
And this says the
more the better,
but for the purposes
of these particular
guidelines,
two factors is
adequate for
the highest security then.
So in our gateways that we
deploy at these
field sites,
we're using two
distinct authentication
methods.
One is the
administrator logins to
these devices
which are strictly
controlled and then,
of course, we're
going to use
a TPM controlling
a private key.
The trust transport uses
to identify that node.
And the combination
of those
two provides, in my
mind, a multi-factor
approach, but that
may be wrong.
So I put it out here
to think about
it a little bit.
But this is where
we're headed with it,
which is for
these unattended
distributed devices,
we have password,
something you
know, we have TPMs,
which are hardware on
that device, uniquely
identify it.
And so what I wanted
to describe a little
bit was how we have to
add access to the TPMs
to the Indian codebase
because that's
not something
that the academic
community
provides because these are
real-world
physical devices.
So when you look at TPMs,
there's a whole lot
of different ways
that they work and, well,
Roger, in fact, put
a bunch of things
in here that we
can use the
resources later
if you want to look back
and think about it.
But basically there are
different levels of
security depending
on where you
store the private key
once you encrypt them.
And so they can
be stored internally
on these chips,
they can be encrypted
and put on disks.
Assigning can be
internal to the chip,
so it's a little more
resistant to hacking.
So there's
different levels of
security depending on
how you implement it.
And then the TPMs
themselves take
different forms.
So the word TPM
doesn't imply
necessarily a
specific physical
implementation.
People talk about
software TPMs.
They're not really
even a thing,
they're literally
just simulators of
physical TPMs that are
completely insecure.
And yet we find
people using
them like they
were really TPMs.
And you go up this
chain and you can get
higher up, that's level.
We're working with
discrete TPMs,
so on board devices
that are tamper
resistant and
are reasonably
inexpensive in the
few dollar range.
So that's where Operant
chose then to implement.
This is probably redundant
to the previous
description,
but I wanted to show
that we are going to use
the trust schemas that
VerSec provides to
control access.
Initially, it
will be a very
simple name based system,
like we'll say this
master control center
can talk to this site,
but no other site can
talk to that site.
Really simple
restrictions over
time as we learn how
to use these
trust schemas,
I'm hoping we
learn all kinds of
useful application
related things
like third-party access to
limited datasets
and things.
All these things
are necessary in
the industry and we're
evolving towards them.
This is just an
indicative diagram
to show that in order to
have a defined
trust system,
you need a trust anchor,
which is what
Tehran brought up,
which is a common
trust anchor,
very simple in a utility
network because
they want that,
they want one
corporate route
of trust and everything
to flow down from that.
So in our case,
we would have
different roles as
defined in the protocol.
And each one would
be associated with
a TPM private key that
is then represented
with a certificate that
fits into the trust
schema and all that goes
together in an
identity bundle and
the full signing chain is
the identity
of the device.
And then every
publication, as mentioned,
is validated as it's
received and as it's sent.
So it's like a belt and
suspenders kind
of approach
to security, I
like it a lot.
The certificate
chain is validated,
how far up and down the
chain this variable
with time,
so you can have
different levels of
persistence of keys
and certificates.
But all of this
is built into
the transport
levels so that
Operant only has to
know how to use it.
We only have to
know how to define
the identities
and the keys.
We don't have to build
the infrastructure.
And that's proving
to be good.
When our software
developers
take the DeftT codebase
and they look at it,
they go like,
this makes sense.
We can just use this.
And I think that
experience is
what people were
asking for this morning
and I think we're
getting closer.
So I want to be
encouraged in that.
In the interest
of time, I'm
probably going to
skip through this,
but maybe just mention
that we're doing a lot of
packet level
decrypting and
validation and so we
have to have
keys in memory,
so we don't want to have
the long term
keys in memory.
So we spin up
instances keys and we
keep ephemeral
keys and we trace
them back in
a user-defined method
so you can set
a period where you
want keys to be valid
so you can set a
security level effect.
Final thing I
want to mention
is something we're
interested in
pursuing and likely to
is that now that we
have this gateway with
the DeftT protocol
running on a Linux box,
we're realizing
our real
vulnerabilities as DOS.
We ran a security scan
on the latest Ubuntu
and I think there were
500 and something
NIST vulnerabilities
identified on the box.
Not all real,
but too many to be
comfortable with.
What I think the best way
forward is and
what we'd like to
investigate is running
the basic transport
and a monitor
system within
a trusted execution
environment processor so
that we can take
the basic security,
isolate the rich
environment from
the outside world and
provide all the security,
but without the OS threats
that otherwise become
predominantly a thing.
So that's our
conclusion overall,
is we're super happy with
the defined-trust thing.
We believe the TPMs are
an essential
part of securing
the hardware devices.
And we think that adding
a trusted execution
environment
at the end would create
a really good
overall product for
these energy
and critical infrastructure
kinds of things.
And I guess
that concludes.
Questions? [APPLAUSE]
>> Saw activity on Slack
that you might want to
take a look at too.
>> Okay.
>> Any questions? Yeah.
>> I just like
to understand,
because we talked
about earlier the
benefits and costs
alignment has come up,
so could you say
a little about your
business model?
You-all are selling
this as a service to
the utilities.
Is that correct?
>> Yes. So let me speak
to that a little bit.
>> And the trust
relationships
involved there.
>> A couple of
things I can say,
one of which is operant
formed out of my
own interests
in the renewable energy
space and it was
a technology push company
for the first
three years or so.
And we were
funded by the DOE
and Leashes group helped
us to define
some early
understandings of
what we could do.
At that point, it
became clear that
that's not how you build
a product company.
You don't start with
the technology.
That's silly and everybody
knows that but me.
But now we've managed
to evolve to the
state where we're
actually asking these
business questions.
We got two gentlemen in
the back there
that are trying to
avoid my eye that
are both new to
the company.
Mike Hertzberg, who's
our board member
is here to understand
enterprise business
models and how would you
position this
product so that you
can sell it to a
giant customer,
but you can also sell to
a small solar developer.
We don't actually know,
but he's qualified
to find out.
And then we
have Gei Foster
who's here to
figure out how to
productize something
so that a customer
sees the benefits,
not the technology.
So we're actually asking
those questions Kim,
but we don't know
the answers yet.
Feel free to tell
me if you know.
>> I don't know.
>> But I think those are
the right questions.
Exactly. Did I deflect
that sufficiently?
[LAUGHTER] Any
other questions?
>> Other questions?
Thank you, Andy.
>> Thank you. [APPLAUSE]
>> 03:40, I think we
can go back to
our next session
which is focused
on NDN applications and
would be chaired by
Susmit Shannigrahi.
Susmit received his PhD in
Computer Science from
Colorado State
University in
2018 and is currently
an assistant professor of
Computer Science
at Tennessee Tech,
where he runs the next
generation networking at.
Susmit, go ahead please.
>> Thank you. Here's
our next presenter.
Saurab is a PhD student
at the University
of Memphis.
He received his
Master's in 2020.
His research
interest involves
information centric
networking,
specimen Indian and
distributed computing.
He is also involved
in various
Indian research,
such as security,
IFT routing,
and [inaudible]
>> Hello everyone.
I'm Saurab.
Today I'm going
to be presenting
mHealth infrustructure.
My title of the talk
is secure mHealth
infrustructure for
real-time data transfer
with fine-gained
access control.
So this is our team.
We've been developing
this system
since quite a while now.
Whatever devices
are growing
exponentially as
you know that we
all have a smartwatches
that stays in our hand.
And we use for
various purposes,
for example health
wellingness and so on.
The mobile health
data that is produced
by these devices can
do a lot of things.
It can assist in
emergency management,
do a real-time medical
interventions and so on.
But there are a lot of
challenges in
collecting and sharing
the mHealth data
before we can achieve
those wonders that I
saw in the previous slide.
The data are highly
diverse in nature.
A lot of different
devices are
used like for example
smartwatches,
tensors and all
those stuff to
collect those ML data.
There are privacy
and legal concerns
surrounding those
data because that's
the participants
and the rest
of data and there is
a lot of private
information
about the participants
in the data.
That's why usually
they are protected by
IRBs and also by
the federal
laws before you
share this data to
do the research.
Maintaining a security and
privacy for those data
is nontrivial task,
especially when they
are generated at
a high rate and are
also from several sources.
With these challenges,
the main goal of our
project is to develop
a system that can achieve
an end-to-end data
collection and
distribution system
and that can
support this complex
heterogeneous mHealth data
and also can
support large scale
and real-time data
distribution.
On top of that, you
also want to achieve,
most importantly,
end-to-end security
on the data.
So once sharing and
collecting this data,
you need to have a trust
between these
entities involved
in this system,
for example consumer,
producer and operators.
And also, we
want to achieve
a fine-grained contextual
access control
based on the policies.
So contextual
access control
is sharing the data
based on the context
of the data itself.
For example you can
see in this example,
Alice wants to share her
blood sugar data and
heart rate data
with her doctor if
she's eating,
but not at home.
So that's like a activity
and the location,
that's the context
of the data.
Similarly, she
might want to share
her physical
activity data with
her gym instructor if
the data was
collected at gym
and at particular time.
So that's like
a context of
the data is time
and the location.
So we want to achieve this
access control based
on these contexts.
Before going
to our system,
I want to talk about
the limitations.
In the existing
mHealth system,
one of the example like
we are here is MD2K.
We looked at the MD2K
mHealth resource
cyberinfrastructure.
So MD2K is NIH Center
of Excellence.
They collect a
lot of data from
the participants and do
the sensing of those data.
So we are collaborating
with them
to the double of
this whole system.
So we looked at
their system and
then found out that
researchers and
other users
cannot retrieve
the data in
the real time from
the study
participants because
this data when they are
generated in the
sensor or devices,
that takes a while to get
to the MD2K repository,
that is mHealth repository
because it involves
a series of steps.
Because of that, building
a real-time system
becomes very
complicated on that
infrastructure.
Also, we look at
their access control
and it was very limited.
>> Username, password
based authentication
system was
used in many cases and
in some other cases,
the data were
manually identified,
encrypted and stored
flash drive and mail.
So obviously in
that scenario you
imagine a slow
process over it
and also human errors.
We also looked at
some of the state of
art systems and found
out several limitations
in them as well.
For example, in
this table you can
see some of this is
state of the art system.
And then we compare
the mHealth
matrices across
the systems and
found out that
none of these
systems supports
contextual access control,
which is very important.
And also in many
of the system,
the real-time
distribution was only
partially supported.
So we found out that.
I've already talked about
contextual access control.
Given those challenges
and limitations
of existing system
and the data itself,
we thought of building
the mHealth
infrastructures using NDN.
So this is our basic
high level diagram.
We want to collect
the data from
different sources and
this data will be
inserted into
the repository,
and then the consumers
can access this
data based on
their access
control policies
from the
repository itself.
There are several
benefits of using NDN.
We've been talking about
that since morning.
So some of the benefits
that I want to highlight
is that a data-centric
security,
because security is one
of the key component
of mHealth system
infrastructure.
So with NDN you get
automatic key management
, end-to-end protection.
Data encrypted in
transit is stored,
meaning when you
are collecting
you can encrypt
the data and then
also in storage when
you are storing.
So you don't
have to rely on
the channel based
security mechanism.
You can gain a fine-grained
access control
using hierarchical
semantic namings.
For the more you
get real-time
data sharing using sync,
sync can leverage
that thing.
The real time system can
be filled using a sync.
That's another benefit,
large-scale data
distributions.
And also another
important aspect for
our project was
NDN repository.
We could just use
NDN repository
to restore our NDN data.
So that's also
another benefit.
So given all this
benefit, we have the NDN
obviously stands
out as choice to
build a secure
infrastructure for mHealth.
So this is our
system overview.
There are a lot of
things on the system.
I don't know if you
can see it or not.
But in this talk,
I want to talk
about some of the
major elements
of our design.
That's naming trust model,
access control and the
publisher subscriber API.
So naming scheme.
So as we talked in
the first panel,
naming is very important
for NDN based system.
So we wanted to design
a hierarchal names.
Obviously they have
lot of benefits
of using a
hierarchal names.
We wanted to
make it flexible
and also generalize,
if not just for
the MD2K which we
were working with,
but also for other
mHealth system.
So for that,
we looked into
their existing
naming scheme for
the MD2K and we found
some loosely
defined structure.
We've worked on
those structures,
analyze hundreds of
name they had for
the streams that
the data were
produced under.
And then we converted
those streams,
their naming into NDN
hierarchal naming.
So this is basically
based on the semantics and
the physical property of
the component in
the name itself.
For example,
you can look at
here one of the example of
semantics and properties
like a sensor
can be under the devices.
Similarly they can be
stuck and have a
several participants
on very study name.
So that's the
semantics we wanted to
maintain while
designing this naming.
And so that's how we
get the stream names.
And for the data naming,
which obviously
needs to be
unique as Lan was
talking in the morning.
So we don't want to
repeat the name
of the data,
so you have to make sure
that the data naming
is so unique.
So we added the
timestamp component
at the end of
the stream name with
this data component
in between.
So that's how we get
the unique data name.
And we also design
naming for attribute
manifests and keys.
I'll be talking about
this stuff in the
later slides.
Another thing, as
I was mentioning,
like a trust model is
very important
when you design
a mHealth
infrastructure because
all the parties
involved in
the system has to
trust each other.
So these are the
entities of our systems.
So operator,
Access Manager,
Publisher and
Data Requester.
The operator will certify
the public key of all
these components,
like Access Manager,
Publisher, and Requester.
So similarly,
Access Manager
will sign the data
that it will produce,
which are obviously
public parameters
that are used for
encryption and decryption.
And also the
decryption key
for the consumers.
And the Publisher
will publish the data
as manifest and the data
so that will be signed
by the publisher.
For the Data Requester,
Data Requester can
be from outside
of the whole mHealth
infrastructure.
So they can be
from anywhere.
So they get the name
under the participating
organizes and then achieve
a key and the
certificate using
NDNCERT from the operator.
And then once they obtain
the decryption key from
the access manager,
they will verify
that based on
the trust relationship,
the trust anchor.
And also another
important thing is
access manager
verifies that
request to the
public-key cert.
So which means if the
request is requesting
for some further
decryption key,
then they will verify that
whether that is a
legitimate request or not.
So that's also important
trust relationship.
Another component
I want to talk
about is access control.
So when you have
data that has
been generated
by the ML system,
you want to provide a
fine grained access to
those data based
on the attributes
or the context
of the data.
And also based on
the access
control policies.
But that's the main goal
of the access control.
So given the time
of encryption where
the data is generated,
so what do you know
about the data?
So that's how you can
realize the encryption.
So at the time of the
scenarios and you
know the context and
the attributes
of the data.
So we want to use those
information to
encrypt the data.
So that's why ABE becomes
a natural source.
But the problem is, you
don't know who is
going to access
this data because they are
unknown during the
time of encryption.
So that's why among
different flavors of ABE,
which shows key policy
attribute-based encryption
because in KPABE,
your keys associated
with the policy,
the decryption key is
associated with
the policy,
that's the side
of encryption.
But the ciphertext is
associated with
the attributes.
So the ciphertexts when
you generate during
the encryption was
associated with
attributes.
So you don't have to
know about the policies.
But that's why
KPABE becomes
a better choice for us.
As I was saying
that you don't need
to know access
control policy.
So also this will
avoid the re-encryption
when the policy changes.
So in the policy side,
when the data
accesses size,
you can change
the policy as
many times as you want.
That does not affect
the interesting side.
So you're good with that.
This is our diagram of
famous diagram with which
we see in many papers.
So that's basically intact
in our design as well.
We use attribute to
encrypt the content key.
So this is one
thing we need to
note that we don't use
the actual ABE keys
to encrypt the data,
but rather we use
the symmetric key
which is a content key.
So we use ABE to encrypt
this content key,
meaning the attributes are
used to encrypt
the content key,
not the data directly.
So using a symmetric key,
you get faster
encryption, decryption.
And also, you might
wonder like when
do you have to re-encrypt
the data? There
will be some case.
So only case
when you have to
re-encrypt the data is if
you want to change
the attributes to
encrypt the data.
If you want to
do that, then
that's the time when you
might want to
re-encrypt the data.
So since we are
using symmetric-key,
you don't have to do that.
You can just use this
new set of attribute
to re-encrypt
this content key
and you'd be good.
So it does not require
any encryption of
the actual payload.
So another thing is
access control policies.
So little bit
Alex thoughts in
his presentation
about access
control policies.
So access control policy,
the goal is to
limit the access to
the data to authorize user
only in terms of use
and privacy risks.
So this access
control policies
defined by the
data owners.
So whoever
generates the data.
So we have a quite
relation to learn when
we design these policies
during the evolution of
our access
control policies.
So this is the
old structure,
what the MD2K system have.
This was their
only structure and
this structure
was converted
to database queries
or firewalls.
So that's how they were
doing the access control,
that's how they wish
to define their policies.
You'd have column name in
which to exact table.
In database, you
will look for
the columns and
the values.
What do you look?
And then you hit
the code is on
the base on those, and
then you get the data.
But this was pretty
hard when you
want it to do is design
a data-centric system,
you cannot realize
this. It's really hard.
So we did a couple
of iterations and
then redefined
the access control
policy structure
based on the attributes.
So once you define
it based on the
attributes,
everything becomes
very simple.
We can just use
NDN names that we
defined in our
naming scheme.
And you can use
these names
to do the access control.
Exactly these
attributes can
be used in the
encryption side as well.
So it simplifies
all the designs.
So that's how we come
up with a new
policy structure.
So you can see the
structure here.
You can just define
what attributes
you allow and what
attributes you
want to deny.
And based on that, you
can define a new access
control policies.
Yes.
>> Now, since we
have established the
security stuff's
trust and encryption,
decryption stuff
and everything,
we want to design
a pops-up system that has
a security embedded
inside in it.
The benefit that we
get with that is
that the consumer and
the publisher doesn't
have to care about
how the security
things is setup.
Once that's initialized,
everything is underneath,
so they don't have
to care about that.
So our pops-up system
is best of sync,
and it authorizes
the subscriber
based on their access
control policies.
So they don't
have to worry
about what the policy is.
They can communicate
with controller to
get the right
decryption keys,
because that's
already internally
built in the
controller side.
Who controls who
can access what
data based on the
policy structure.
And it also
helps in getting
real-time data and
the latest verified
data as well.
So this is a flow
of how it happens.
You have a publisher,
they will publish
the data.
This data will be
encrypted and inserted
into the repository.
Here you can see
that inside of
the repository,
consumer app will
subscribe for some of
the data streams
and they will get
the manifest back with
their subscription
list and
the publisher will send
the corresponding
manifest,
I'll talk about that
in the next slide,
back and then
they will just
fetch the manifest and
then correspondingly
fetch the data.
Time is running out, so
I'm going to move on.
So one important thing
to note is that
signing and
verifying millions
of data packets
using public-key crypto
is very expensive,
so we wanted
to avoid that.
Also, you can directly
use those data names in
the sync because it
will create a lot of
overhead so we decided
to use manifests instead.
So you just have
a manifest.
So manifest is only
verified using
public-key crypto
so we just list
the data and
they're digest
in the manifest packet.
So once the consumer
will fetch the manifest,
they will know
what data packet
to fetch and then they can
verify the data packet
using the digest.
So basically, only a
manifest needs to
be verified using
public key crypto
and the rest
of the things can be just
verified using the digest.
So that makes our
life much easier.
These are unlimited
in detail.
Some of the open and
future works I want
to talk about.
So the NAC-ABE
based on openABE,
which is very fragile,
not maintained
since many years.
So that will break in
some point in time,
so we will not be
able to use it.
We have to find
some options.
KP-ABE approach has some
scalability issues.
If the number of
attributes that they
are accessing is large,
the decryption key
becomes very big.
So there are some
problems to solve
there as well.
End-to-end privacy is
our future work, which
we'll be working on.
This figures,
so we've been
talking about this
since morning.
So developing a
NDN application
is very hard right now.
So in our infrastructure,
these are the component
that is involved.
Smartwatches, devices,
smartphones, server,
and client applications.
So you need NDN on
every single of
these devices or
in environment,
we don't have
that right now.
So if I'm an
application developer,
I have to use all
of these system,
either you develop NDN for
those devices
or maintain or
upgrade whatever is there
or you just give up.
So that's why
it's very hard.
We need to have
minimal NDN
supporting these devices.
That's also one
of the things to
note and we might be
working on that on
future work as well.
Thank you. [APPLAUSE].
>> Thank you,
Saurab. Very nice
presentation.
Do you have any questions?
>> This is just a
quick question about
the overall data model
and I guess the
security approach.
Do you include
the person who
this health data is
about in the
security model?
I only saw the researcher,
instructor, clinician.
>> So for them,
as an access or
the default policy
is they will get
access to their data,
everything, so that is
on the policy side.
So the default policy
is whoever data is that,
they will be able to
access everything.
That's the default policy.
And then that
owner can analyze
that policy and define new
policy for other people.
The owner
which means who
produces the handheld.
>> Got it. Sorry
if I missed that.
>> So I have a
quick question.
Do you anticipate the need
for revoking
access at anytime?
>> That's a very
good question.
I didn't include
that inside.
Yes. Revoking access on
ABE is really
interesting problems.
So we had two different
access to revocation,
for example, you can
do timely revocations,
you can define the
decryption key to
expire in X date,
and that's how you can do
this manual inspections.
Then another one is
immediate revocations
which is tough.
So for immediate
revocation,
which means you want
to kick someone out of
the system immediately
from tomorrow,
let's say.
[OVERLAPPING]
>> And make sure they
don't have access to
the data they had
access to before.
>> Oh, that thing
cannot be solved.
Felicia has a very good
point on that one.
Whatever is gone, is gone.
You can't control
that data.
>> If they have
it locally,
then yes, you
cannot control it.
But this shouldn't
be able to get
new content from your
system and decrypt it.
>> They will
not be able to.
So for that problem,
what we do is we
the access manager
or the controller
will generate
a new public parameters,
meaning data that
will be encrypted
afterwards will use
a new everything new keys.
So that guy will
be kicked out
of the system and
you'll not be able
to fetch the new keys
to access the first data.
Not for the old
data, old data
will be still going out.
>> Thank you. Any
other questions?
>> I just wanted to
try to understand
what's new will
be in there?
The data encrypted using
policies that
is related to
the [OVERLAPPING]
attributes from the data?
>> Yes.
>> But then how
can change it?
What will be changed?
>> So for the education,
it uses attributes for
public parameters
that is generated
by the control key.
so if you change
the public diameter
and you are [OVERLAPPING]
>> So you just have to
change the public
parameter so?
>> Yeah. Basically,
all the keys will
be regenerated.
That's the revocation
mechanism we have found.
>> Sounds good.
Thank you, Saurab.
So next we have Davide.
Davide is a researcher at
NIST Smart Connected
Systems Division and
has worked on
various aspects
of NDN over the
years, including IoT,
security, network
measurement, forwarding,
and bay color,
Ad Hoc Networks.
[BACKGROUND]
>> Not seen this
[inaudible].
I don't know
which one it was.
>> [inaudible]
We can close
everything and we
should be able
to see the desktop.
>> No right there.
[inaudible].
>> Even the mouse
is misbehaving.
[inaudible].
>> Anyway. I'll be brief.
This is very
much a work in
progress collaboration
between team
with NIST and the
team Tennessee Tech.
Thanks for the
introduction by the way,
just able to speak.
I'm sure many, if
not most of you
have needed to use
or generate traffic traces
while you were doing
your earlier research,
either for performance
evaluation
or for your
simulations, etc.
I think we can't deny
that traffic traces in
general are very important
for research and this
is true in general,
and not just for
NDN research,
but some particular
reasons why it's important
for foreign NDN is
that I often hear,
oh, I don't know
how to optimize
this algorithm or I
don't know how to
tune this algorithm
for the common case.
What is a common
naming scheme for
applications,
are name super long,
are name super short?
What's the average
packet size?
So this question is
don't really
have an answer
because we don't
really know.
We're building the
plane as we fly it
and there's no
clear answers
to these questions so far.
Another reason for why
traffic durations are
important is completely
different is the
network troubleshooting
and debugging.
They can be very
helpful to find out
where the problem is,
both in real time
and after the fact.
Finally, recommendation
that came
from the review from
the National
Academies of Science.
The National
Academy of Sciences
periodically
appoints a panel of
experts that
reviews and needs
activities and last year,
our division was
under review.
One specific
recommendation was given,
needs expertise in this
field to contribute
synthetic and real
traffic trace.
This and probably
many other reason
is why we're doing this.
The next question
is how we do it?
How we generate this
traffic traces?
One proposed solution
that I've heard is to
take existing traces
from IP-based
applications,
typically HDB or
network file systems,
because they already
have a name hierarchy,
built-in, an
aim hierarchy.
So you can take
those traces and
somehow convert
them an NDN name.
Sure it could
work, but first
of all it's very
complicated
logistically
because it's almost
impossible to obtain
the traces in
the first place.
And even if you
do obtain them,
they often come
with limitations
like you cannot
publish this,
you can not
republish this.
You have some NDA or
some other constant.
Also we did come
across some traces and
these trace is actually
obfuscated for privacy
reasons and they
basically destroy
the name hierarchy
that it's present in
the packet trace.
At that point, you just
get a flat namespace,
just a hash of the name
or the path in
the HTTP request.
So it's useless
for NDN purposes.
Even if we had the
name that's not
all of NDN I guess it may
be the proceeds
of 90% of it,
but still not everything.
You don't get.
Things like a prefix
matching, I guess.
And also the biggest
problem with this,
they hinted that
before is that,
okay, these are
HTTP applications.
Maybe one, when we
build the NDN
applications,
we will build them in
a completely
different way,
maybe based on sync.
So the next step
in this process,
this thought
process on how
to produce NDN
traffic traces,
is okay, let's
generate them.
Let's synthesize
the trace.
So you build a
traffic generator,
but what parameters
that you use.
As I said before, what's
the average packet size?
What's the
average length of
a name in terms of
name components and
how many different
prefixes we have.
it's chicken
and egg problem
because you would
like to already
have existing traces of
real applications and
from those you can
extract these metrics
from which you
can educate
your traffic generator
or your trace generator.
So eventually we
end up to capturing
from as real as possible
NDN deployment.
This is also a
problem because
we don't really have
a real realistic
NDN deployment
or there are very few.
There might be
specialized domains
only some specific
type of networks.
And then there's the
problem of real users
versus synthetic users,
meaning we don't really
have that many users.
So we embarked in
this journey and
the only way to
do this is really
the last one,
but I'll explain more
specifically how.
The goal of the project is
to publish a dataset
of traffic traces.
Initially it
will be probably
small opening certain
type of traces,
limited types
and hopefully
over time it will grow.
In addition, not
just the dataset,
but also software,
an open source software
toolkit that includes
tools to capture
the traffic,
anonymize the traffic,
compress the traffic,
create nicely packaged
traces and also,
and this is the
capture side and then
there's the replay
and analysis side.
So you take that, you're
doing your NDN sim
simulation and
you want to take
the trace and replay
it in a near sim
with the producers and
consumers and so
on, so forth.
And we try to
design all of
these to be modular so
that if you don't
like a piece of it,
you can swap it
out with yours.
Let's say you
want to capture
in 100 gigabit network
and our total is
too slow for
that so you use
your own tool to
do the damping
and the rest of
our toolkit to do
the rest of the pipeline,
or vice versa, you use
your own tools
for analyzing,
but you can use
our toolkits for
the capturing side or
mix-and-match combination.
[NOISE] So starting from
the first of these tools,
the traffic damper,
we already, as I said,
this project is a
work in progress,
some pieces are in
a more advanced
state and others.
The traffic
damper is already
available on GitHub.
It supports live capture
from one or more
network interfaces,
or you can also read
from an existing trace,
as I said
earlier, modular.
So if you want to capture
with your own tool,
but then you want to
use other features of
this tool like
anonymization you
can do that by reading
another trace from a file.
The trace is saved into
a common standard that
I would say formats with
compression and we also
implemented some
best effort
anonimization features
that some are implemented.
We'll probably do more
work in the future.
>> Purchase those.
The next step
is to actually do
the collection.
And our first
thought is to
collect these traces
on NDN testbed,
what we call the
NDN testbed and
we could open up
parentheses on
whether this is
a testbed or not actually,
maybe we should call
it pilot deployment,
but it's a separate
type of discussion.
And the immediate question
is, what are the
applications?
We're looking at two
applications right now,
just because it
was the easiest to
deploy and that
we know best.
But we're seeking
feedback and
other idea suggestions on
what other
applications we could
use to do this.
So these two applications,
one is coming from
the N-DISE project.
There's a producer
and consumer of
basically large files
that are used by
the high-energy
physics community.
You can see these as
a bulk data transfer,
I would say that
kind of application.
The other one is
video streaming.
So based on Shaka player,
which is a web
based or JavaScript
streaming video
player using
things like HLS and Dash.
But running over again
using NDNts library.
We are almost ready,
literally days away
from collecting.
We'll start small first.
We are going to have
a few instances
of the ndntdump,
the traffic dumper running
on a few nodes
of the testbed
and distributed
a certain number
of consumers, producers.
This is just a subset
of the nodes of
the testbed in the US,
then eventually
will expand to
a global scale, etc.
In the meantime, since we
haven't done this yet,
we started working on
some analysis and
feature extraction,
metrics extraction
using a sample trace
that we got from our
Junxiao's network,
this is 24 hours.
It's not a lot of packets,
1.3 million comes to
about 15 packets per
second so it's not
a lot of traffic,
but it's a good
starting point.
And this is mostly
video streaming there
is no N-DISE application.
This is the
sample trace and
some results
characteristics,
there's no results per se.
Characteristics
of the tracer.
So we can see most
of the time it's just
background traffic,
probably, sorry, analyzer
think there's not
much happening.
Not too many new nodes
are disappearing.
So the network is pretty
stable and lots of
interests here are
not being
answered probably
because the sink interests
are just expiring.
And once in a
while, there's
a few peaks and
this is probably
where some viewers,
we're watching the videos.
The other one is we
looked at the name length
in terms of bytes,
how many bytes, and in
terms of components.
So we can see
there's a correlation,
of course,
as the number of
components goes up,
the length in bytes
obviously grows
a little bit,
but there are some larger
clusters here with
a fairly large names with
not so many components but
there are some
components that
must be pretty long.
And also this one, I
think it's the darkest.
So the highest frequency,
which is consistent with
the previous graph,
the previous
plot of a number
of interests, blue
is interests.
We have a lot of interests
with 12 components
that are not
being answered.
So this is just
two examples of
all the metrics
you can extract.
And then the idea is
that you as a researcher,
you're working on some
specific caching
strategy or
foraging strategy
and you'll
want to look at some
specific traces,
how does your
strategy behave?
And you can pick
whatever suits
your use case or
workload best.
And you look at this
graph, this plots,
you extract metrics from
the traces and get
your trace and use it
in your simulations.
And that makes
your results
hopefully more
reproducible and
easier to compare
to other solutions
for the same problem
or similar problems.
So to conclude, as I said,
we are looking
for feedback,
do you have any ideas?
If you think this
is useful or
not useful, let us know.
But more importantly,
how do you think
you would use this,
use this and how,
and how we can improve
the usefulness
of this project,
make it more broadly
useful for the community.
In the future, we're
not saying we
will do this,
definitely not in
the first iteration,
but some ideas
are to extend
this ever shared database
where you put your traces
and then there's
an API to query
the traces and
do crazy things
or a dashboard for
real-time monitoring
of the testbed
or any other network
really for troubleshooting
issues in real time.
Finally, there's
speaking of testbeds,
the FABRIC testbed,
we might think about
how to integrate
it with FABRIC.
FABRIC has or will
have a built-in way of
dumping large volumes of
traffic as it travels
through their network,
their switches.
Maybe we can integrate it
dumping. That's
all I have.
>> Thank you,
Davida. [APPLAUSE].
>> Hi, is the NDNT
dump tool different
from the other
packet capture tools
we have been using,
like NDN dump,
and T shark.
>> Yeah, that's
a good question.
So the main feature
that is missing from
the other tools
is the anonymization.
That's one main advantage
or feature that we added.
The other one is that
we want to be able
to capture the traffic
and on the fly in real
time, we wanted to,
for instance, zero out
the continent
application parameters,
not just for
privacy reasons,
but also so that
the compression
would be more efficient.
Having more efficient
compressions
results in a smaller file,
which means we can
capture for longer.
Ideally, you would want
to be able to also to
capture over several
days at a time.
So we cannot ask
people to have
terabytes of space
when capturing
the traffic.
So doing this also
allows us to capture for
longer without asking
for crazy hardware
requirements.
>> So there's no actual
content in the
data packet.
>> So the data packets are
exactly as you see
them on the wire,
except that inside
the content DLV,
you only have a very
long string of zeros.
If your packet had,
I don't know 100
bytes of content,
you will have 100
bytes of zeros.
>> Do you make
any changes to the
name component?
>> No. Not at this time.
There may be privacy
issues from that too,
at some point, but
we're not there yet.
>> Any other
questions? If not,
then please give feedback
on the work as
Davida said,
how you'd like
to use this,
what are the use cases
and what kind of
traffic traces you'd like
to see in the future,
I think that would
be good to see.
Thank you, Davida
[APPLAUSE].
So next we have
Varun from UCLA.
He's a PhD student in
Lisa's group
working on NDN in
particular on distributed
dataset synchronization
and NDN APIs.
And his talk is NDN
Sync API overview.
>> Thanks, Usman. So
I'm going to try to
keep this short
because some of
this has already been
talked about before.
This talk is
about an overview
of the currently
available Sync,
which is the NDN
Transport APIs,
the high-level APIs and
it's also a request
for feedback.
This is available
right now,
what people are
working on and
how would you use it
and we encourage
you to use it,
try it out, and let
us know what
works for you,
what doesn't work
for you, what
could be changed
for improving it.
So I said that this is
a overview of the
NDN Transport APIs.
So for some background,
let's start with why
does NDN need transport?
In NDN communication is
based on Interest-Data
exchanges.
These interests
and data packets
are datagrams.
That means that
they are limited
by the MTU size
and that also means
that they have this
low-level API.
You set interest filters
and you get back
the data on them.
So that low-level
API is not
really for application
developers,
we don't use APIs to
send IP datagrams.
That is the first problem.
The second problem
is that we
have unpredictable
data production.
To get data in
NDN you need to
know the name of
the data and you
need to know that the
data actually exists,
otherwise you cannot
send the interests.
So we need a way to figure
out if a piece of data
exists and if it does,
then what is its name to
be able to face
this piece of data.
These two things need
help layer on top of NDN,
which is the NDN
Transport, that is Sync.
The Sync or distributed
dataset synchronization.
It actually
solves primarily
the second problem that
informs the group
participants
about the data production.
So if there's
a group of
communicating entities,
then as soon as data
is produced
inside the group,
Sync notifies
everyone else in
the group that
this new piece
of data is available,
and this is the
name of the data.
So this function is
called namespace
synchronization because
it synchronizes the
names of the dataset
and this serves as
a multi-party transport
protocol in NDN.
To use NDN in the real
world the second,
which was the
first problem
that I mentioned earlier,
is that application
developers are not
network experts
and so they
need familiar
high-level APIs.
The word familiar is
important here
because again,
they cannot use
Interest-Data directly
and they also cannot
sign and verify
each data packet.
They can do it but
it's very cumbersome.
Whatever the
Sync APIs would
the Sync APIs as they are
be able to solve
this problem.
Well, not really.
If you look at just
the pure Sync APIs
that Sync itself provides,
then I'm taking
the example
of data [inaudible],
the other protocols
are similar.
So Sync really
provides a very
simple API that you create
a Sync instance
which starts
the group then all
you can do is,
because Sync use a
sequential naming
for data for transport
layer purposes.
All you can do is
update the sequence
number like
increment the
sequence number for
your current
producer and then
if a sequence number
changes at some
other producer,
then you'll get
this callback.
I will quickly
talk about the
design of State
Vector Sync
in some later slides
which will make
this clear.
But before that, let me
just talk about what is
the high-level API that
you actually desire.
So we want high-level
multi-party communication
and that means there
should be no need
to deal with
these network or transport
layer primitives,
where by transport layer I
mean the sequence numbers.
That also means that
the application
should deal with
application data units,
not with network
layer packets.
There should be no
MTU size limitations
because this is a natural
clear limitation,
and we should allow using
semantic
application names,
not sequence numbers.
The second thing
is we should have
some built-in
security support.
So applications
don't need to sign
individual packets and
the security support
should be easy
to configure.
A sample API and
pretty much
everything looks like
this is the
Publish-Subscribe API,
which again, everyone
is familiar with.
We publish a
piece of data,
give it identifier,
and some content
and then we
subscribe to some
identify group,
where it corresponds
to some,
identifies and not
to some others,
and then we get a
call back as soon
as someone else produces
data for identifier
matching this group.
And the second
part of the API
would be security
configuration,
which I don't really
have a mockup for.
So the APIs that I'm
going to talk about
here first is
State Vector Sync
Pub/Sub, SVS-PS,
the second is
mGuard Pub/Sub,
which [inaudible]
already talked about,
and the third is I'm
just going to
put this here.
I'm not really going
to talk about it but
[inaudible] talk
earlier on DeftT.
So the Sync PS API
in DeftT is also
a Pub/Sub API.
The first one is
SVS-PS and I just put
the links in for the
implementation as well
as the spec for
SVS Pub/Sub.
So before I talk
about SVS Pub/Sub,
I'll go back to
what I said earlier
that Sync provides
some simple APIs,
and that can be
explained using if
I just explain how state
Patterson itself works.
So SVS represents
the namespace is
a list of tuples.
Each tuple is a producer
name and a
sequence number.
So whenever a
certain producer
produces a new
piece of data,
they increment their
local sequence number
and then Sync is
going to synchronize
this list of
tuples which is
the producer name and
the sequence number among
all of the participants.
So as soon as someone
purchases a new
piece of data,
the sequence
number increments
at some other place,
and then they know
that this
particular producer
produced a new
piece of data.
And now it should be
obvious why Sync has
this very simple API which
is just changing the
local sequence number.
So whenever you produce
a new piece of data,
all that Sync does is
update the
sequence number at
every other consumer to
let them know that
this new piece of
data was produced.
And that's why you only
get a callback saying
that the sequence number
changed for some
other producer.
Just for a bit more
context the way
SVS synchronizes
this is by
sending out a
state vector which
contains the
entire list of
tuples which is
the producer
names and the
sequence numbers.
And as soon as someone
has received this,
they know exactly
what the status
at the center of
this particular
Sync interests
because it contains
all state vector.
So why is it important is
that this is why you need
to sequence
numbers because
if you don't have
sequence numbers,
you can only put
so much inside
a single packet
that you're sending
out on the network.
You cannot put a lot
of names inside
the packet.
And the second
thing is that you
need the sequence numbers
for loss resiliency.
So for example, if one of
these Sync interests
gets missed,
then you don't have
the production of a
certain sequence number.
But if you receive the
next Sync interest,
it contains the next
sequence number.
So you know that
the previous one
was also produced.
So sequence
numbers are needed
in the transport layer
but at the same time,
applications don't want to
use the sequence numbers.
Applications want to
use sterile names.
So the sequence
number is like
a transport layer detail.
We don't use
the TCP sequence number
in applications.
So what applications need
is these semantically
meaningful data names.
And the second
thing that SVS or
any sync protocol
also needs
is we still need to do
data synchronization.
We're just
getting the names
of the consumers
inside the group.
We're not actually moving
the data from
the producer to
the consumer regardless
of whether the
consumer needs it.
So these two
things are what we
need to build
this high-level
API on top of Sync.
So the way SVS-PS
does it is,
first of all, we
need to solve
the problem of the
application names.
So we get the
sequence number.
The way SVS-PS gets
the application layer name
is just to send a
interest for it.
This interest
called the mapping
interest is just going to
ask what is the name
for this particular
sequence number.
This interest goes
to the producer
of the data and
the producer
replies with
the actual name
of the application data.
So now when the consumer
gets this mapping data,
which is the name,
then they can
decide using that name
whether they want
to face that data.
If they want to
face the data,
they'll send a interest
for the actual data
and then they'll
fetch the actual data
if they need it.
So the way it works is if
Alice, who is
the publisher,
produces a piece of data
with some
application name,
then Alice is just
going to increment
Alice's sequence
number and send out
the Sync interest which
contains a new
sequence number.
Whoever receives it is
then going to ask for
a mapping that what
is the name for
the sequence number
and then they'll
get this mapping data
which contains the name.
They can use it to
determine if they want
it and if they do want it,
then they can
actually send
an interest or
the data for
the sequence number and
then they'll get
the actual data.
One thing to note
here is that
because we are also
fetching the data
using the sequence
number if you just
encrypt all of the pieces
of data over here,
you also inherently
get in privacy.
So the application
layer name is
never revealed to
anyone who is moving,
only the sequence
numbers are equal,
that is the number of
publications
that went out.
So the second part is
segmentation and security.
So for segmentation,
SVS-PS provides
a simple API.
You just give it
a blob of data.
It is going to
segment it into
smaller packets
and then when it
receives it on
the subscriber then
it's going to
just reassemble
it and pass the data
blob back to the
application.
And similarly,
for security,
you just need to
initialize it
with a signer
and a validator
where the designers and
these validators are
going to be used
for signing and
validating data packets
but you don't
need to do that
yourself in the
application.
So the high-level API
looks something like this.
You initialize SES Pub/Sub
designer and
the validator,
and also the Sync prefix,
and then you call
subscribe on
a data prefix
which will get you
all the pieces of
the blobs of data
that are prefixed
with this topic.
And whoever needs to
publish the data,
they will just
call publish,
give the data name, and
then just give it
a binary blob.
This blob will
be segmented,
it will be signed, it
will be encapsulated,
and then the sequence
number will be changed
to the new one which
the subscriber
then fetch if
they're subscribed to
this particular tuple.
>> I'm just not going
to discuss this.
There's just one slide on
an overview of how
this works internally.
So the next API that I'm
going to talk about,
which again already did,
is mGuard Pub Sub.
So there's a link
to the code in some
slides I didn't have it.
So if you want to use
the pops up part of it,
you can probably go
there or you can
talk to Sarah.
mGuard is again part
of the MD2K project.
It's designed for
real-time data delivery.
In particular, an emphasis
on high-frequency data,
which relates to how
it's security
model is built,
and it gives us
fine-grained contextual
access control.
So mGuard Pub Sub is
built over PSync.
PSync also uses
sequence numbers.
Its design is
slightly different,
it uses an invertible
bloom filter
in sync interests instead
of sending the raw data,
but it's still is a
sequence numbers.
One difference is
that PSync replies
can carry the
new data name.
So the mapping data
in state vector sync
doesn't apply over here.
In the mGuard pops up API.
You publish and subscribe
to these data streams.
And the subscribers are
authorized using access
control policies.
So again, talked
about this.
I'll just quickly
go to the API,
which looks very
similar to the SVS API.
You subscribe to
data streams,
you get callbacks whenever
there's a new
piece of data.
When you're
publishing your
published on data name,
which is the
data stream is
just a prefix of
the data name,
and then you also
provide, in this case,
attributes because
mGuard Pub Sub also
has security built-in
inside the Pub Sub,
and then you
provide the content
which is going to get
to the subscriber.
Once again, you have
the manifest in mGuard
pops up because
as I mentioned,
the important
part is built
for sending a lot of
packets on synch.
So that's why it has
this built-in support
for data manifests,
which you can use to bulk
verify multiple
pieces of data.
So the manifest is just a
data packet which
contains the names
of multiple data
packets and their
digests to just verify
this manifest packet,
and then you implicitly
verified all of
the data packets
whose names and
digest are there
inside this
manifest packet.
Because the names
contain the
implicit digest.
These manifests are in
turn sequentially name.
So you can just publish
these manifests
on precinct,
and then as
soon as someone
receives a new
sequence number,
they can paste
the manifest,
and then they can
fetch the actual
pieces of data.
So very quickly,
mGuard pops up when
the publisher
publishes a piece
of data using
the Pub Sub API,
then the publisher is
going to insert the
encrypted data,
the current key and
the manifest
into the repo.
And then they're
going to send out
the sync interest that
this new manifestos
published,
and then the
subscriber is going to
fetch the manifest
content key.
And if they need it,
then they're going to get
the actual
content, the data,
and then they can
decrypt it if they're
authorized through.
The configuration.
Again, you need the
prefixes. You need.
Also need these
certificates for
the NAC-ABE to use
to encrypt and
decrypt the data.
So my point here
is that mGuard,
you need to do
a little bit of
more configuration,
but mGuard Pub
Sub is going to
come with this
in-built security
support as well.
So I just want
to summarize,
this is not exactly
comparison,
but all of the APIs
that we have currently
look somewhat similar.
We have this publish-subscribe
in SVSPubSub,
mGuard Pub Sub as
well as the ft,
where you send out
a piece of data,
you get back where
you subscribe
to prefixes,
which are topics.
And they have different
security support.
As this website provides
a very thin layer
of security.
You give it a signer
and validator.
And got has this
NAC-ABE security
built-in and DFT,
of course does the
trust schema security.
And so again, we invite
you to try out or use
these APIs in your
applications.
Or if you know someone
building an application
and then you
could recommend
one of these APIs
and then send
your criticisms,
suggestions, or any
general feedback.
Thank you.
>> Thank you Veron.
[APPLAUSE] Yes.
>> I just have a
clarification question.
I think are under
security support.
Your list, the things
it's very different.
For example assigning and
the validation I think
DFT does too this, not
that it doesn't do it.
Similarly, union would
trust the schema.
That's what you
need to decide.
Which key to sign and
which could use
for validation.
So I wasn't sure
how you listed
the different things on
the different nodes?
>> Yes. So I
was saying it's
not exactly a
comparison is just
I'm saying that there's
different
security support.
Like I'm goddess,
more security
coupled with the
API of solid API.
SVS has that a
turn earlier
and DFT has coupled
with the [inaudible].
I don't know if it's
the best way to put it.
>> [inaudible].
>> Yeah, I get
what you mean.
>> Any other questions.
So I think Ken had
a question about
sync, G12.
Thank you, Laura. So the
[NOISE] last talk of
the day is from Alicia.
We all know Alicia
is from UCLA,
DIE [inaudible]
Indian grant.
Our talk is tearing
new applications
away from centralized
realizing.
>> Between you
and the dinner,
I will try to go fast.
Also as the last
speaker for the day.
I'm not making any
new points for that.
My short talk I hope
is really short trying to
actually make a summary
of the previous ones,
I want to highlight the
points as I see it.
Because behind all
the great works,
there has to be
some SQL resource.
And I always wanted
to see what are those,
the SQL resources.
The others are details
that everyone can work out
the specific detail
for specific problems.
If you understand what
the SQL resource is,
then you can apply it.
[NOISE] Or you
should use that one
>> I heard that
there's some
family emergency.
He couldn't be here.
There's really
a joint talk in the
following sense,
if I know how to do it.
This talk could
collect the input
from two resources,
one is on a panel on
Internet Centralization
Decentralization actually
chaired by Alex here.
And then the IETF,
the decentralize,
the Internet
research group also
had a workshop
on the topic.
And the last
one is NDN had
a retreat last year
with a session on this,
I think [inaudible]
probably
hosted a live session,
and he had a talk there.
And so therefore this one
is some message that
together his talk at
NDN Retreat and
my summary of
the IETF DINRG
workshop report.
I'll make the
story work quick.
I want to tell a story
that I normally
say that Internet
started decentralized
somewhere will get
decentralized and
getting brighter
as the time goes,
getting worse.
So if I follow
my habit, why?
This is them. We started
by having an IP.
IP is a point-to-point
delivery,
then the TCP
point-to-point connection.
Then the driver is
really distributed.
You want to join the
internet IP address,
then set up some servers,
so your local users,
can have emails, can have
FTP and other things.
Why did you host your
own email services?
Well, if you want to
serve your local users,
that's the only
way you get it.
There's no
commercial services.
There is an AOL,
America Online,
but that's really
for home users per
se, not for institutions.
So therefore, individual
parties around
their own application
servers and the DNS
that's really handles
the gap between
network that
handle addresses
versus application
that cannot use addresses.
There's no a centralized
control per se,
although we hide the
DNS to start with,
it's after IP
got deployed.
One point I really
want to repeat,
perhaps more times in
future talks that a DNS
is not centrally controlled
name allocation,
please everyone
understand this.
ICANN, however political
or not political it is,
its job is to assure
the namespace uniqueness
and nothing beyond that.
Who gets a specific name?
I hate to flame on this.
That's not matter.
I used to work for Xerox.
Before Xerox company
was created,
did anyone know the word
Xerox and even
not existed?
Xerox made the word
and therefore,
you now understand
your copy paper,
you'll say Xeroxing,
so is the Google.
Before Google became fame.
There is no such
a word as Google.
Now, we don't say
search, we say Googling.
Individual names,
it does not matter.
I know that that's
trademarks and
pupils spend billions
for the trademark,
but the smart people
don't go that way.
If you have something,
you create our own brand.
It really doesn't matter
how you assemble of
you [inaudible] together
to make a name.
And I can merely just to
assure the names
are unique.
Flame up. So apps.
Like I said, in
the early days,
there's no
commercial services
for the popular apps.
You want your users
to how apps that have
your own server.
Those are not
the revenue generation
operations.
I want to make
that very clear.
But given that there's
a useful apps,
there's always
a smart people.
They are trying
to figure out how
I can make money
out of it.
And therefore, it comes
to commercialized
apps providers.
Once it become a
revenue-generating,
that's the market first
started that drive.
You'll become a
service provider,
you want to see how can
I get them all users,
you get the revenues
then even you, you
don't get revenues.
You still try to improve
the services
so you can get
more users in the future,
you will get the revenues.
And therefore,
the bigger size,
you can have
more investments
into improve
your services.
Not like our product
department email server
where single super
mail running it
but it doesn't have
the resources to
continuously improve
the service.
But once you become
a commercial services,
that's all you have.
And I think equally
importantly,
I want to emphasize,
cannot be overemphasized
in the security.
This days, there are still
people who wanted to run
their own servers
independent
from our grid,
Google email, maybe.
But can you survive
the security attack?
And that becomes
increasingly difficult.
Not only that, the real
attacks, the real
restrictions,
the ISVs would not allow
you to open the Port
25 because they're
worried that
there's become
potential sources
for exploration.
So running
individual services,
just become
increasingly difficult,
if not possible.
And then security
challenges
make more people
who are willing to
run their own services
to outsourcing because
the cost becomes
higher as time goes.
Now, I just want
to flame on where
we are the art of
networking today.
Well, how lots of
grid applications
as immediate streaming,
the people, remote
listening to the talk,
conferencing,
LTE smart homes.
I know lots of people here
they have smart homes.
We tried but we
to turn it off.
And then I always
use this example,
can laptops to talk
to each other?
My laptop has this talk,
so that's here
can affect it.
If you've
installed the NVA,
you can. Otherwise
you cannot.
How do I know my
laptop what that is?
Are you there
to connect to
my laptop without the TLS.
Why don't you have TLS?
My laptop doesn't have
a certificate
issued about NCS.
I don't own a DNS name.
So even free certificate,
like Let's Encrypt
certificate, I
cannot get one.
This has come
to personnel.
What's going on in
front of the queue?
This happening to me just
like about a week ago,
from my home to UCLA,
I go through the single
lane public land
and the traffic is
extremely sluggish.
We have no clue what.
It took me a half hour
to hit the front of
starting point
that the water
main break, the roadblock.
So I wasted total
half an hour and
everyone else
along the road.
You can go Google
Maps, will save you.
That's what was happening
in the morning.
At night, 07:00 PM, I
was going to go home,
I said hopefully
through the day
Google Maps already
learned the fact.
Google Maps go back
to the old way,
it's a free 20
minutes, you got home.
You got to the
same point in
the other direction,
road closed.
That's how much you
can trust centralized
services.
But most of the
time things work.
We have great
CDN services,
we have great
car services.
The desktops wants to
talk to each other,
even if they're
on the same desk,
you can still talk to each
other through the Cloud.
And with the
last question,
you hope that
with your finger
across the Google Maps
can become real time.
>> So last point,
are all the communications
secure? I need
to go quick.
I tell you for this
last question,
I can't give you a
positive answer.
All the useful
applications today,
I believe they're running
in some securities,
how? This is how.
You're just hanging
to the Cloud through
your secure TLS
connections.
And this picture
reminded me back in
1981 when I just went
to MIT as a
graduate student.
Each one of us had as
a terminal hanging on
the physical wire to
a mainframe on the 9th
floor, Impact Square.
So 40 some years back
we came back to
the same picture.
Just that my phone
is probably more
powerful than
that mainframe
back then in
Impact Square,
except that it is still
hanging to the core.
Is this the thing we
wanted for the future?
By the way, the
picture is not as
bad yet. You know what?
Call servers are
not too close to
you though they
are problems,
how do you solve
the problems,
you inject them patches.
So we can see that
the CDNs help you
disseminate traffic,
the firewalls to
assure your security.
And then Eric
mentioned earlier that
the mitigation
of the service
prevented the Cloud
from getting attacked.
And then load balancers
they have all things.
So picture of today for
the network and it's
not that pretty.
With all these
middle boxes
there's a further
fall for it.
If people haven't heard of
this talk, you may
want to find it.
They said the death
of an end-to-end Internet.
And this actually a pretty
popular talk on
the YouTube.
Going forward
so centralizes
thing is not great,
but I hope everyone
understand
the potential
danger of that.
There is a well-known book
and the people in
my group actually
pointed out.
I think you
mentioned twice
this week Lydia
about this book.
The Age of Surveillance
Capitalism,
I really suggest that
everyone take a look
at the preview.
When you reading it, pay
attention to the
centralization.
So why is the centralized?
Because you build upon
individual users behavior.
You collect their
data so that
you can make
money out of it.
But there's the fundamental
question to ask.
User data, who owns it?
And do companies
have the free right
to leverage my data to
make it their revenue?
What kind of a regulation
will be needed?
I think that's all
semi open questions.
There is a greater blog.
Just point out to
you by Geoff Huston,
I think two years ago
on the cyber governance.
And he said is a
truly amazing,
I really agree with that.
That the sum of
a human knowledge is
at my fingertips.
Instantly, you can
learn about everything.
At the same time,
it's truly frightening
to think that
all this
information is only
accessible through
a single entity.
And everyone knows who
that single entity is.
If you cannot see clearly,
that really shows
the search engine
market share
and everyone knows
what the top line.
That's the Google,
and everyone
else, they're noise.
So to sum up, that profile
within the networking is
networking shooting
the packets,
but this is no
longer the case.
We're used to be
that the network
can be dominated
by the carriers.
But today, the
focal point,
it really moved up to
the higher protocol
stack where you can
much easily exploit
the centralization
with this economy
of scale,
with a lot less cost.
Before you want to be
a monopoly to
provide networking.
You really have to
have the capital
to install the switches
and then draw the lines
, digging the trenches.
Today, that's along
centralized Cloud,
you can really capitalize
on your software
department.
Lower-level services
become a commodity.
However, personal
opinion, I feel
that many of the effort
they still focused on the
lower-level optimization.
It's very much useful
work, interesting work.
The question is
whether there's
a most critical work
that can help Internet
move into the future.
This is just saying that
the circle is going on
and moving the train
going into the direction,
not necessarily what
we want it to see.
There's some discussions,
especially in IETF,
to say we really need
to design new protocols,
to merge the Internet
out of centralization.
And then I brought
up the question,
to say that look,
the protocols
have not changed.
Back 40 years, we had
the distributed
decentralized Internet,
the same set
of protocol by
and large on the
lower layers,
but the operations
got decentralized.
So therefore, it's really
the protocol
not the design.
The protocol decides
where traffic goes,
or some other logic,
it drives where
traffic goes.
I brought up this
position statements
at the last IETF, and
it got a pushback.
It says that, okay, yes,
protocol has not changed
but the requirement
are changed.
So we need to design
new protocols
to prevent further
centralization.
The real question is
actually not so much,
hey, who can design
new protocols that
will be decentralized?
I think a
fundamental question
one must ask is,
what are the new
requirement?
Unless the new
protocols can
address the new
requirement.
Otherwise, you're not
solving the problem.
So to me, I think that
the new requirement is,
like I said before,
this is where we are.
Why we need the hanging
everything on the Clouds,
because only the Cloud
is a safety heaven.
The new requirement is
about secure
communications.
And all of those
little tiny devices,
like our laptops
cannot communicate
directly because they're
faceless entities.
Of course they are
faceless, so therefore,
they cannot securely
communicate with
each other.
Security start
with identities.
You know whom you
are talking to,
then you know what
this guy can,
or cannot do.
To move quickly, here's
collected small set
of sample applications
that's Cloud free.
We're talking
some here today,
like the DeftT, just
mentioned earlier.
There's no dependency
on the Cloud.
I put the pointer,
therefore,
all the things
I mentioned,
whoever interested can
do further exploration.
Can you guys
talk, explain how
we want to make hydra do
this semiautomatic
bootstrapping so
that all the
entities inside of
a hydra could
communicate securely.
I want to point out
that the hydra also is
entirely Cloud free
distributed application.
Now the next example
is something developed
at UCLA called
the NDN Lite,
is really a user
controlled smart homes.
Again, for people
interested,
you can look
at that paper,
that's a great paper.
Explain all the details.
Here's application
developed by
people at Memphis.
This was published in
ICN few years back about,
for social apps we
can really do it
in a distributed
way without
depending on the Clouds
to authenticate you,
to identify you.
Why we go to the Cloud to
communicate
because you and
I have no identities.
We go to the Cloud.
I would identify that
by my Gmail address.
There's a single
side. Now, once
the Google
authenticate you,
then you can talk to
all the other peoples,
but If one day,
I don't think
Google can do that.
If they drop on
my Gmail address,
I'll be dark.
I cannot communicate
with anyone.
That is a danger.
This really point us
to a new direction,
how you can do
social networking
without depending
on the Clouds.
What's the common
features of all of
this NDN based
applications?
We say security
designed into the apps.
So therefore,
we don't depend
on this intermediate,
the firewalls,
and anything
to protect our security.
But how can you have
the security built
into the apps?
Two things,
secret results.
That's my understanding
of secret results,
is that Cloud independent
user identifier
and Cloud independent
security.
With this two, then all of
our devices can
directly communicate.
Then those people
who are smart
enough will build
applications
utilizing this user owned
identity and user owned
security management.
So back to the
real serious talk
about we are out of our
end-to-end principle.
I think the end-to-end is
a principle and we
will stick to it.
The reason we have
so many mailboxes
is because
the new requirements
arrived
and the old protocol
stack cannot satisfy.
The current solution
is to inject
the patches in the middle
like the mailboxes,
like the CDNs, or
delivery firewall,
or so-called the security,
but they really create
all kinds of problems.
So therefore, this is
not about end-to-end
principle,
outdated, but rather
it's the architecture.
Then let another revision.
Once the
architecture enables
the end-user identities
and the security support,
we're actually not only
stick with the
end-to-end principle,
but we actually
extend it to have
end-to-end security
and that really
simplify the
future systems
in the fundamental ways.
So take a way
is what I said.
To enable distributed
applications,
we need identities and
securities that's
out of Clouds.
This is end my story.
I'm over by two minutes.
Thank you. [APPLAUSE]
>> Thank you, Lisa.
Questions? Yes.
>> So I think a
contributing factor to
the move to the Cloud
is the fact that
from the point of view
of my application,
there is no difference
between communicating with
something in the Cloud and
communicating
with the laptop
that's next to
me on the table.
IP completely
obscures that,
and part of that is
because of the way the
economics of internet
service providers
and the whole
infrastructure ecosystem.
As you pointed out,
it's a commodity now.
Dave Clark tells the
story about talking to
an economist who said,
this was a long time ago,
but he said, "You guys
screwed up the
money protocols."
Dave Clark says,
"We didn't
design any money
protocols."
The economist says, "Yeah,
that's what I said."
I sometimes wonder whether
things would have evolved
differently if we had
made the incentives and
the costs of the
communication
more explicit
and expose that.
Obviously it was a good
thing for the growth
of the Internet to
make things
simple like that.
But I think also where
we are right now,
which I agree with your
assessment of that,
is a partial
consequence of that.
I wonder if one
thing we might do
is try to unbundle
the incentives and expose
those more in our systems.
>> I don't know how
much time we have.
I think that's a great
[LAUGHTER] question
for discussions.
But I can just
reply quickly.
For one, I don't mind
the Cloud at all.
Cloud is economy of scale.
Use cloud as much
as possible.
The fundamental thing
is not whether you
communicate
through the Cloud
or not through the Cloud.
The fundamental thing is
a control power,
the control.
Like I said, I
might identify
that by my Gmail.
If I Google, I
would delete that
Gmail ID and data.
Data is a power.
Another example,
Google knows me
better than myself.
It is my data.
Do I have control over
the access to that data?
I don't mind that the data
is stored in Google,
but I should control
the access of it.
>> The key question
though is,
would you pay per
search for Google
for that service?
Because that's what leads
to the information.
>> I don't want to
forget David's question,
but I will answer
this question first.
Search, are we
doing a search with
driveway today?
Now withdraw
out things like
the maximum entropy way.
Then Google will do
the brute force browsing
to find out things.
We could help build
the search in a
fundamentally different way.
I had a conversation
with one long time
ago when we
were working on
this adaptable
web caching,
that was in '90s.
I think that's one
for the forerunners
eventually at a latitude
is the indirection.
When you put
out something,
you meant for
others to find it.
Why don't you
just build into
index service instead of
Google being the
only party that
has the power to crow
the entire world?
We could help build
the system in
a more structured way,
more fundable way,
more index way to make
your search in
a fundamentally
different business.
But now Google
has a power,
it utilize that power.
It knows what
you're looking for.
That's how they
learn about you.
>> Was asking if you're
willing to pay for it.
>> I mean,
there's different
ways to build a system.
That is today's
way building
system is not the way.
>> I'll bring back, I'm
following on
John's question.
>> Can I answer
Clark question?
I'm in a difficult
situation.
Dave is my advisor.
He taught me what
is networking.
I really learned the
architecture from him.
But on that particular
function to say we
didn't design money
into the protocol,
I have a different
opinion.
I really have a different
opinion on that,
but I need more
time to explore.
But I want to register
that question
with you. We
can chat later.
>> The obvious
question here,
and I think this
is what Ken was
getting at is that
the Internet today is
really ran on advertising.
Whether we like it or not,
the thing that
drives the internet
today is advertising,
and the advertising
business
has structured itself in
such a way that it will be
really hard to dismantle
what they've built.
We're now talking
about 500,
600 billion dollars
industry that
have mastered the ability
to figure out who we are,
packages and sell
us to advertisers.
Now, whether it
works or not, that's
a different story.
But this is what
we're against and
I don't really see people
complaining a lot
about that because
in return we get
these free services.
Unless somebody can figure
out a better way to
find the intranet,
back to Ken's question,
are we willing to pay for
all the free services
that we're getting?
>> I would point you
to a talk given by
Steve Bellovin in
July 2019 IETF,
where he gave a keynote,
he said that I
don't mind the
selling my data for money.
The question is now
data decision is
out of my hands.
If I have a contract with
Google, you can
sell my money.
Let us split the revenue.
For now that's entirely
controlled by Google.
The money goes to Google.
He didn't say
Google, I said that,
but that is a problem.
That goes back to my
original statement.
Who is in control?
We don't want
the small number
of separate giants
to control our entire life
and that problem needs
to be addressed.
It's not about
advertisement,
it's all about the
control power.
>> Well, the only way you
can address that is
through a regulation.
>> Yes.
>> Because the companies
themselves are not
going to do this.
Once you start going
into regulation,
you're opening
up a huge number
of cans of worms.
>> In my original
version of
this 2021 DRG workshop,
we're actually
talking about the
society turn down the
three-legged stool.
There's a market,
there is technology,
there's regulation, and
there's a constraint,
the growth of
each of them.
Now, I think the
market is taking
over way more power
because market-driven
economy
went really fast.
Of course the technology
feels that advances.
But the regulation
is too far behind.
We are yet to figure
out exactly what to
regulate before we can
bring that regulation
into the picture.
>> That's exactly
right. I suspect that
if we try to regulate
the Internet,
we're going to get lost in
trying to decide
what to regulate,
how to regulate, and
who is to regulate.
>> That's actually
the topics
for the DRG discussion.
I hope whoever
interested join
our discussion.
>> There are some
interesting comments in
Slack about ChatGPT
[inaudible].
>> I think for ChatGPT I
would have comments as
generally speaking for
all the machine
learning approaches.
I think machine
learning is great.
That's really a new tool.
You can think of
the new machine
industry revolution.
There's a second
level of revolution,
rapid, big jump into
a much higher level.
However, the same
Internet principle
will apply.
The ChatGPT is just
like all the
machine learning's,
something in,
something out.
What goes in is a
fundamental question.
If you don't know
what goes in,
then you do not trust
what comes out.
>> I didn't know
if you know this,
but there was an
article where he
started using ChatGPT and
it started trending,
but we'll leave that for
another day.
Other request?
>> First I have to
congratulate
this crowd for
taking so long to
mention ChatGPT.
[LAUGHTER] I was
at NDSS and and
ChatGPT was mentioned
at least 20
times every day
when we were there.
[LAUGHTER] [APPLAUSE].
>> Thank you,
Mr. Smith and all
the speakers.
We'll see you all
tomorrow 10:00 AM
for two presentation
sessions
and two interesting
panels.
We'll see you all tomorrow
at 10:00. Thank you all.