>> So we're back in
first afternoon session
is the panel on
standardization that
will be chaired
by Christos Papadopoulos
from University
of Memphis.
Christos you
want to start?
>> Thank you. How
are you everybody?
First of all, thanks to
the panel for being here
at making time
to, move closer.
So now louder,
thanks to the panel
for being here
and making time
for this topic.
Do we have the other
two presenters,
panelists on Zoom.
So can we do a sound check
for Luca and Kathyayani.
Luca and Kathyayani
you can hear?
>> I'm Ms. Kathyayani,
can you hear me?
>> Great. Yes,
we can hear you
Kathyayani. Luca
are you there?
>> Yes, I'm here.
>> Excellent. And
you can hear us too?
>> Yes.
>> Very good.
>> So the title
of the panel is,
might be a little
controversial,
or at least bringing up
many thoughts that we
have been discussing
and the MDM group
for a long time.
And I hope that
it brings up
a lot of reactions
that easily intense.
I'd like to run
this panel a
little differently than
the other panels,
which is,
I want to encourage
audience participation,
not just on the
Slack channel.
Slack interaction
has been great.
I've seen a lot
of questions,
great questions coming up
on the Slack channel.
But I also like to
encourage people
here and people
who are remotes,
assuming they have
the audio capability
to ask questions,
we will be monitoring
the Slack channel
and try to bring
the questions
that pop up on
the Slack channel here
so we can try to
get them answered.
But please, this is all
about interaction
and participation.
So let's keep this lively.
Without further ado, let's
go to introduce
our panelists.
So we have Luca
from Cisco,
we all know Luca and
he's been with NDN
for a very long time.
He's perspective is
clearly very valuable.
Randy is here in person.
Thank you, Randy.
We've known
Randy for the
last few years.
You brings in the very
interesting industry
perspective.
Very happy to
have him here.
Suzanne is here in person,
and Suzanne is the
only person who may
not be as familiar with
NBN as the others,
but she does work
in standards.
So I figured if
we're talking
about standards,
we should have a
standards person
here to guide us.
And that will be a
role here to keep
us in check.
And we have Kathyayani
from Intel.
Kathyayani has been
working with MDN for
several years
now as part of
the wind projects,
if I'm correct.
And she's also bringing
another industry
perspective.
Now note that we
have a lot of
industry representation
here that was on purpose.
Because we have
been talking about
MDN for a very long time,
asking the question, how
do we commercialize?
How do we move it forward?
How do we bring it to
market and so forth?
So that was by design.
Disclaimer that I'd
like to bring up is
everybody here speaks on
behalf of their
own selves,
especially the
industry folks.
They are not expressing
their company's opinions,
just their own.
Great. So I wanted to
give the opportunity to
everybody to briefly
introduce themselves.
And if you want,
you can also state
upfront your position.
So let's start with Randy.
> Sure. Is this on?
>> Sure.
>> So I'm Randy King,
CTO of Operant.
We're a small
company where
seed round funded
13 people current
and we've been
working on Indian
primarily with UCLA team
for about five years.
Our focus is on
energy networking
like cybersecurity
for utilities,
primarily, also
renewable energy that's
widely distributed.
So a lot of us came
from a background and
communications plus
the background
and the solar
energy industry.
So that's our
base business.
My interest here is
because our business plan
is based on what
we're calling
an open core model.
So if I had slides,
I'd make three
concentric rings
on them in the center 1,
which is what we
call the core.
And that's the open source
networking libraries
and the transports
that this
community builds.
And so this is
the center of
our technology
stack in a sense.
And the ring around it
is the set of
tools and APIs and
higher-level things
that are like
middle level stuff that we
use to provide value in
a business in a product
development sense.
And then the outer ring
is application space.
So we might focus on
energy, markets stuff,
but maybe in the future
people will work
on health care
or something
using these inner rings.
So the benefit
of the open core
is that we get,
a really key thing
for us is that we get
renewability and
improvement of
the security that's built
into the core stuff.
And because in the end
tends to encapsulate
all the security and
security support
functions in
the lower level
networking.
This is particularly
effective because
our customers want no
security by obscurity.
They want reviewable,
stable code.
So that's where we get
benefit out of
standardization of this core.
And I think in
the future we'd like
to imagine there's
a true open
source community
contributing to that
core and there's
some set of
processes to be
developed to monitor
and integrate that.
So that's my
opening statement.
>> Great. Very
well said, Randy.
Thank you. Suzanne?
>> [LAUGHTER].
I obviously have
cursed microphones.
I'm Suzanne Lightman.
I work in the Computer
Security Division
here at NIST.
And my expertise is
automotive and industrial
cybersecurity.
And I'm mostly
on this panel,
I think because I
have experience with
four or five
different standard
organizations.
I've worked on what
are called horizontal
standards,
which are standards
that are not
specific to any
particular industry.
And I've worked on
vertical standards,
which are
standards that are
specific to industries.
So I have extensive
experience across a range
of standard development
organizations
and because I
work at NIST,
a very clear
understanding of
what standards can
and cannot give you.
>> Great. Thank
you Suzanne.
When I met Suzanne,
I was at DHS and I
remember having
a conversation
that went something like,
do you know how
standards work?
And I think I gave
her some answer
which was completely
out of the blue.
And then she's like,
let me tell you
how they really work.
I really appreciate
you being here.
Going to our remote
participants.
Kathyayani, would
you mind going next?
>> Sure. Thanks Christos.
I'm Kathyayani
Srikanteswara.
I'm a principal
engineer at Intel,
working in Intel Labs.
And as Christos
has mentioned,
I was the PI for
the Intel NSFICN main
centre from 2017-2020.
But for the last
six years or so
have been looking at
India and in
particular commercial
applications
of Indian way.
Can we use it?
And we narrowed down
to the edge applications.
And in some sense,
even though Indian was
originally designed
largely for content
or fixed networks,
we felt it had a lot
of potential for compute,
or were dynamic networks,
dynamic resources,
multi-tenant
resources and so on.
And that's what we
have been looking
at for the last six
or seven years or so.
And in terms of my view
of standardization or
taking a step
back or looking
at a slightly
larger picture
of what does it
take for an Indian to
become commercial?
And why hasn't it
become commercial
on a large scale?
Yes, there are, of course,
as we have people here
who have been
looking at it,
but why hasn't it
then adopted on
a larger scale?
And one thing I
wanted to point
out was when we have
a new technology
or a protocol or
an algorithm for which
you don't have a solution.
You've never
seen a solution.
Then the minute
academia comes
up with a new protocol
or an algorithm,
industry tries to
absorb it immediately,
devil upon it, and so on.
But in this slightly
different space here,
where even though it
may not be optimal
or far from optimal,
there are ways of
doing a lot of
the networking and
networking data movement
compute solutions.
And a lot of them, I will
say that they are
far from optimal,
but when there is
a way to do it,
there is a lot much
more bigger barrier
for adoption of a
newer technology.
And then in those
situations,
the key becomes
the benefits.
Can you show orders
of magnitude?
And I'm talking about not
just even one or two
weights like 10x, 100x.
And I know some
of the benefits
cannot be quantified.
But the idea is the same.
Is there an area or
an application
where it's really
hard to do the
way we do things
now and can Indian help?
And in that respect,
I think I can
kinda see where
he's coming from as well
as some standardization.
If you have something
to start with,
it's not the only thing,
but it can certainly help.
But when you have
some form of
a standard or
specification that you can
benchmark against
and compare.
It makes things a
lot easier and I
think that's
where I stand.
>> Great. Thank
you Kathyayani.
So Luca I'd like to
go for you to go next,
if you're ready?
>> My name is
Luca Muscariello,
a principal
engineer at Cisco
during last seven years,
before that I was working
in a telco business.
And I've been working
on this topic since
2010 in different areas.
While working at Cisco
I've been working mostly
in incubation and product
creation based on ICN.
More recently on
real-time communications,
especially WebEx, WebRTC,
also mobile gaming but
also for web free
applications.
And I think that's it.
I don't want to
[LAUGHTER] bore
everybody with
a longer story,
but happy to be here.
>> Thanks Luca. So I
think we need the volume
a little bit up on
the remote people.
I think the volume from
the remote people
is a little low.
I think we need
to increase the
volume a little bit
from the remote people.
So moving on to
the first
question which is
what is a panel
started asking.
So is it time
to standardize?
And I know this is
a question that in
the NDN group we
have been talking
about for a long time
and mostly in
the context of
commercialization.
And it also in some
form it also came up at
the lessons learned panel
that we had yesterday.
So when I ask about
standardization
I mean that
in the broader sense.
So it could be
standardization in terms of
standards and RFCs
and so forth.
But it could also be
a specification
which means we
don't have to go through
the formal process of
standards and so forth.
In the arguments
that we had in
the past for and against
standardization,
I think everybody
knows them.
Let me just remind
them what they are,
at least the two
main arguments.
The argument for
standardization
obviously is to help
with commercialization,
help with adoption,
and all the good
things that come with
standardization.
The argument
against was a fear
of freezing the
specification and not
allowing improvements or
further research into
NDN that at the end
after many years we
may come to regret.
So think this is
the shoe key thoughts
that we've had.
I felt that people have
any other thoughts
I would love to hear them.
And then in addition
to these questions,
if we decide
that it is time
to look into some form
of standardization,
then the question is,
who should do it?
Who should pursue it?
And by who I mean,
the academics, industry,
both, and so forth.
So I wanted to have
Luca kick off the
discussion on this
because he has been
quite vocal on
the email exchange
that we've had and I
know in the past you
had a lot of
strong opinions.
So Luca, would you
mind presenting your
thoughts on this?
>> Well, the
topic is not new.
I think in the community
we've being going
back-and-forth on this
question several times.
Is it time to
standardize or not?
And I think that I changed
my mind several times.
First time I remember
the discussion
2012 when Park started
the first industrial
consortium,
I was working for a
telco at that time.
People were already
asking themselves,
should we
standardize or not.
And then later on
there was this
conversation
between CCN versus
NDN for a very
long time which
made that undoable
for many reasons.
And more recently
my opinion
moving to something
that is more
business-driven,
like why would
you standardize?
Standardize is
very complex and
very expensive
for everybody.
Unless you have ongoing
revenue streams to
justify the need for
a specification plus
interoperability,
standardization is
not actually needed.
And this is also
something that
is coming from
other communities
where they
can successfully
build a community
without standards
like for instance
the very successful
Cloud Native
Computing Foundations
where you
don't have any standard
and people can
collaborate
around code base.
In general I've noticed
during the last I
would say 20 years
that networks in
particular with
some very specific
exception
related to security is
not actually
something that
really need standards
to move on.
Like overlays can work
without any
standardization effort.
Interoperability
can be managed
by partners without having
a standard to do that.
And so I'm skeptical
about the need for
standardization in
general from a
business perspective
and I'm a little
skeptical in
particular for
this community
for a reason which
is mostly related
to the fact that
you really need
to share change control
of the technology and
essentially get
feedback from
the users and essentially
take into account
the feedback
from the users.
And so which implies
adoption to get
that feedback
and change the
technology so that
it matches the
expectation of the users.
So in a way it's a
chicken egg problem
where if you don't
have that option
you don't have users
providing feedback changes
in technology
until it gets
to a stable situations.
And so at that point
you may think about
standardization.
Ensure standardization
should happen
after adoption
and not before.
And for this
specific community
I don't think we
are already in
the curve of adoption.
I will stop here
for the moment.
>> Great. Thank
you Luca. Randy.
>> Well, so I think
I'm just going
to basically
agree with Luca,
but in a more
simple minded way,
which is, I wasn't
really sure of
the difference
between a
specification and
a standardization
so I looked it up.
And the first
Google entry,
because I have a short
attention span was
the specifications
are limited
to a specific
project or agency,
standards are
specifications
that are recognized as
the most practical
solution
that is agreed upon
by a recognized authority
for a recurring problem.
If I'd known I was
sitting next to Suzanne,
I wouldn't try this.
But if you pick some
of that is valuable,
I would point out
that there are
no recurring
problems solved
by NDN right now.
There really aren't
any recognized experts
to standardize on these
recurring problems.
So I would agree with Luca
that first you need those,
and that would apply
some adoption.
I mentioned this to our
VP Product at
lunch and he said,
there won't be standards
until there were
big companies who
think there's
something here worth
fighting over.
And I thought that was
a good summary of it.
>> Great. Thank you,
Randy. So Kathyayani,
can we get your opinion
and then we'll
come to Suzanne.
>> Sure. So one
thing I wanted
to just share
is I heard you
mentioned earlier as
one of the reasons or
the fear of
standardization
has been that we freeze
technology or innovation.
And just wanted to
clarify that that is not
the case if history
has anything to
do with it. Look
at the cell level.
We went all the
way from 1G to
we're now thinking of 6G.
So even if there is
a standard, yes,
you will keep
innovating beyond that
and there'll be
a new standard,
same with Wi-Fi.
Personally, I thought
we had 802.11n,
and then we had the ACAD
and I thought
we'd be done now.
We were far from them.
So just wanted to
point out that
that fear we probably
need not have.
The other thing I just
wanted to share was,
I agree In general, yes,
the whole adoption
versus standardization
there.
And in general, yes, if
their people are
dying to adopt
the technologies
to standardization
almost happens
instantaneously.
I agree with a lot
of things Luca said,
but also wanted
to add that in,
let's say cloud-native or
some of these
other areas, yes,
we don't have an
official standard
but what happened was like
Docker or
Kubernetes became
the de facto standard.
And everybody now
calibrates to that.
So if you're looking
at, how do you do it?
Assume it's Kubernetes,
assume it's Docker
containers.
And that's evolved
organically
as the de facto standards.
So even though it
wasn't officially
a standard
it did happen
in some manner.
>> Great. Thank
you, Kathyayani.
Suzanne, do you
want to jump in?
>> You want me
to start now.
There's some things that
standards can do and
there's something that
standards can't do.
The first thing
I will say is
a standard requires
a group of
experts who come to
a consensus on what
has to be in
the standards.
So you have to
have the group
of experts first.
Also, a standard generally
is not a how it's a what.
It isn't an
instruction manual.
It's telling you what
you have to have,
but not how you
have to get it.
This is how we
wind up having
standards about
risk assessments,
but everybody uses a
different methodology.
So if you're growing
an issue where you're
looking at things
and saying,
these are things that
you have to have and
ordering to
participate in NDN,
that would be the
basis of a standard.
If you are still at
the point where
you're saying,
we don't agree on
what you have to
have or we don't
have to interact
enough that it makes
a difference if we
have different things,
then you don't have to
worry about a standard.
But I will say
that you probably
want to set yourself
on a pathway to
standards because
standards do make
things more,
for lack of a better
word, respectable.
For industries,
when they say,
see their standards,
interoperability
standards,
operations standards,
then they can say,
so if I buy this
product that uses NDN,
and then I buy
another product
that uses NDN,
they will interoperate
and I will not have to
go and find somebody
to do something
very expensive to
make them all work.
Those are the kind of
advantages and there's
a runway to standards.
For example, it may be
time for NDN to
start looking for
a standards development
organization where
eventually you might have
the experts that will
then create the standards.
IEEE, for instance,
will do projects that
eventually get
to standards.
An example is Obtain
that winded its
way as a project.
This is an update standard
in the automotive
industry that started out
as a project and
then slid into
IEEE as a project and
is now slowly
standardizing.
So there is a very long
runway to standards.
Although it's not time
to have a standard,
it may be time to start
looking at where you
would be if you wanted
to standardize.
>> Great. Thank you.
So there's also
this question between
standardization
and specification.
Thank you Randy for
looking it up on Google.
And I think the way
we were looking
at this question is
maybe we're not
ready for standards.
It sounds like
something very finite,
very final, if you like.
But maybe we should
start looking at putting
together a
specification for NDN.
And I'll leave
that open as
to exactly what
that means.
But I think we
were thinking that
we need to have
something that people can
coalesce around and
have a common goal.
>> I think your microphone
might have
stopped working.
>> I think I might have
been keeping it away from.
Suzanne, going
back to you.
So in the path for
standards, as you said,
do you see
specification as
a bus stop going there?
How do you see that?
>> I will say depending on
what organization
you're with
, standards development
organization.
Specification
isn't that much
less than the standard.
They're generally
a little quicker
but there's still based on
consensus and on having
experts come together
to talk about something.
They're generally more
limited in scope.
They generally have
a quicker development time
that would be three years
as opposed to five years.
Standards are not fast.
And they're
generally designed
with a limited lifetime.
So the idea is
that they are
a step onto a standard.
So if you were to do
a specific technical
specification,
a TS, as it's
called in ISO or
a publicly available
specification.
I think that's
what ICE calls it.
I'm not sure what
IEEE calls it.
It's kind of like
a baby steps
towards a standard,
but they would
expect you to then
go on and standardize.
So you would need to
look at this and see,
is there a portion of NDN
that would benefit from
everybody saying this is
what you have to have.
>> Great. Thank
you. I think that
was the point that
Kathyayani made,
which is, if you
standardize it
doesn't mean
the end of the work.
You can standardize
in different phases.
Great. So let's move
to the next question.
This is something that
came up again on email.
And I think we had
some sort of a
general agreement
from all the participants
that in order to
move forward with
something that
the industry
would want to use,
we need to have something
like an industry
consortium
to take on the work.
And in the NDN team,
we have been talking
for a long time about
the lack of manpower
to create code,
proper code, fast code,
whatever you
want to call it,
but I think there was also
the thought
that academics,
graduate students, the
academia in general
would not be able
to undertake
the task of
creating the code,
the products that we
want to have as output.
And looking at
other efforts
that were successful
and progressed,
it seems to me
that there was in
most cases there was
some an industry
consortium that took
over the project and
pushed it forward.
In order to have that,
I think all of
these consortiums
had a few common themes.
For example they
always answered
the question,
what is the perceived
value of this?
And everybody
agreed on that one.
Then if we go
towards in this
industry consortium then
this other questions
that come up and I'm just
listing a few
of them here,
who should be on it?
Should we partner
with an organization
like what Suzanne said?
And then finally,
what should be
the output of
the consortium?
So with that very
brief introduction,
I'm going to let our
panelists comment
on this idea of an
industry consortium.
And I'm going to
circle back and start
again with Luca,
if you're ready.
>> Yes, I'm ready.
Where do you want
me to start?
>> So in general,
your thoughts about
industry consortiums
and whether these
will be an appropriate
path for NDN.
>> Industrial they're many
and I've participated
myself in many
of them in the past in
different contexts
beyond the NDN ICN.
And they are useful
because it's a place
where the industry can
meet and discuss about
the needs of customers,
partners, those who
build and those
who operate
the technology and so
you get the feedback
and it's very useful.
And in some cases,
I've been active in
the telco industry,
in Broadband Forum
or in mobile space.
You have a running
business there.
So you have partners
building equipment,
operators deploying
equipment and
so you have a very
large cost and
so the standard
is necessary
with Lockean, etc.
It has been already raised
here in this panel.
So it's very useful to
have in industry
consortium.
And the reason why
industry meet in
this fora is that
there is a business
behind it.
And so they meet
because it's required
to make the business
continue to grow or
continuing to work.
And so that you
have running
revenue streams and so you
want them to continue.
The incentives are very
clear for
everybody to stay
there. I go back
to adoption.
If you have adoption,
especially the
early stage,
you have the industry
that is willing
to invest because there
are opportunities
to create revenues.
And once those revenue
streams are triggered,
then you meet in these
fora to keep them
working as a continuum
in the case of
IEEE, Ethernet,
Wi-Fi than OWELL,
plus three GPP than OWELL,
the business is very
large and everybody's
there and keep
the standard of
living because there are
upgrades with technology,
but the business
is there to
find all that effort
and technology
evolution to
the different technologies
that I mentioned.
In the case of NDN is
different because
you don't have
recognized business that
can make that possible.
And so we're still at
the early stage if
you think about
the Gardner,
that cycle curve,
we are still
at the early stage
of that curve.
We are not very far
from the plateau and
so every single consortium
that I've seen
in the case of
IC NDN are
mostly research.
So that's where
standard is less.
You have less
incentives to push
a standard because you
don't even know if the
business is going to
start in the year
and for year or so.
Yes, consortia.
Industrial consortiums are
useful but they need
to be driven by a
business opportunity.
>> Great. Thanks
Luka. So Randy,
you have seen a
business opportunity
clearly with NDN and
that's why you're here.
Do you want to
comment on that?
>> I think it's
an interesting.
I'm really happy to follow
Lucas comments
because he's
ahead of me on
this thinking,
I think I can
follow along with,
we know it's not time for
standardization
because there aren't
big companies
fighting over this
so is the path for
standardization
helpful to
actually get over
the adoption barriers is
more of the
interesting question.
And so I've been thinking
about it in that terms.
And if you just
blur your eyes to
standardization and say it
includes the path
that Suzanne
was talking about
then I think
there's value of providing
what I call stability and
visibility for the
protocol because it
increases what you
call the respect.
When we go to a
customer who we're
engaging with as
the visionaries
in the customer,
they're not the
people that
do the day-to-day
work initially.
And so when we engage
with constellation,
we engage with
people who said,
we have solutions today,
but they will not
scale to 10 years out.
We need to be thinking
about what we
can do then.
That's visionary.
They need to bring
our proposal to
their management
to engage with
us and bring
us the first
project that could
lead to the future
that's bigger business.
And so we have to
give those guys
internal sales
tools that work
to provide a
respectability
of what we're doing.
And there are things
that seem to be
on the path to
standards and I
listed white papers,
human-readable
specifications,
stable and
reviewable codebase.
Those things are examples
of today to some degree.
There's a couple of things
that really don't exist.
Example apps that engage
real customers, no.
There's toy apps
which are great
for developers but
not for customers.
And there are
very few industry
business cases
that anybody can point to.
And so we need
to work on those
things which I
believe are on the path
to what we want
to do someday,
which would be
something so
valuable that people
will fight over.
And so I have
one small success
along the way,
which was we funded
an Internet draft that
Kathy Nichols and
Van Jacobson wrote on
deft as part of
a DOE project
that we're doing.
And it's a very good
intermediate step in
my mind between
a white paper
and a specification.
It's more detailed than
a specification
presented to
the IETF community but in
a request for
comment form notice,
proposed standards
of track.
And so I think
it's been going to
be quite useful
with our customers
because their experts can
look at it and go like,
this is put in front of
a respectable
community and
written clearly by
obvious experts.
And so that thing we
can use to build
our credibility.
And then that'll get us
to the visionaries to do
their internal sales
that may lead to
the actual business.
So I'll stop there.
>> Great. Thank
you. So just
to follow one on that one.
So it's really great
that you guys have had
so much success and
you're able to convince
your customers of
the value for this.
If we wanted to move
towards a consortium,
then which means bringing
other companies
into place,
companies that
would recognize
the value just
like you did.
Who would you like to see?
And I'm not talking
about companies.
I'm talking about what is
would it help you and
what would be the
way to do it?
>> I think the community
here, like our company,
has been until recently as
lacking a set
expertise in how to
explain things to people
in an understandable
format.
And there's a big
difference between
having the interest and
patience that takes
to engage with
the research community
and a business case.
And the government can
help fund programs
that make it better.
Some startups will engage,
like we have in some
researchers in
big companies
have the patients and
the intelligence
to do all this.
And so what I
think we want to
[NOISE] excuse me,
want to do is
lower the effort required
to understand what's here.
With us, we hire
product people.
There's a whole set
of experts that
do this for industry.
What's the equivalent
in academia
to make something
more available?
That would be more of
a question for you.
>> Great. Thank
you. Kathy,
I want to get back
to your thoughts.
>> Sure.
>> Go ahead.
>> I've been trying to
keep track of those.
So maybe I'll start
with the last
comment that Randy
just made and it's
about yes making
adoption easier.
I think that's the
critical part.
And also goes back to
the standards
versus specification
versus code.
It doesn't have to
be in the form of
a 3GPP solar standards
that we have those
documents, that you have,
the code can definitely be
standards too
and especially
if it's associated with
how do I couldn't work.
I have this application
that I, without NDN.
I want to implement
this using
NDN and some of all the
security features
that I want to use,
all those techniques that
NDN provides, caching,
security, all the
other benefits,
resource discovering.
So how do I go from
what I have to that.
Yes, I know each
application is different,
but in general,
if they at least even
like starting some of
applications and even if
they're initially
toy applications
and you can grow from
there if you have
something that shows,
in this particular
area, in this field,
we have these tools
or knobs that you
can use to take
your standard even if
it's a toy application and
then you convert it
and then you can
compare and see
what's going on.
I think that'll
be a big help.
And regarding the question
of industry consortium.
It's a chicken
and egg problem
and I think Randy
also touched upon it.
And industry consortium
works great when if
you have industry already
working on something,
they already almost
have a product.
Somebody else
has a product?
Yes, how do we make
it work together?
Let's quickly come up
with a standard or
some way that
these inter-operate,
it's great.
But if you're trying
to come up with
a standard it's easier
for industry to adopt,
then it's a lot harder
to go the route
of the industry consortium
if that make sense.
So just these
are things to
keep in mind as we go
about this process.
>> Thanks. Suzanne.
>> Well, from my
vast experience with
standard organizations
and industry consortia,
when you say an
industry consortia,
I don't think
you're thinking
of an industry
specifically,
you are thinking of
a horizontal
discussion of NDM.
And that is different
than what most people
think of an
industry consortia.
That's the kind
of consortia
that Cisco would come into
or Intel would
come into because
they are horizontal
suppliers.
But if what you're
thinking of
is to provide
a place where
let's say industrial
manufacturers like
Honeywell or Siemens are
looking at NDN and saying,
could we use this for
our industrial systems?
Because as we go to
more cloud-based,
we're tracking
all this data
and we're really only
interested in data.
They would go looking
for we're the
experts in NDN,
we're all flocking and
go there to try
and get answers,
steal graduate students,
that kind of thing so
that they could access
existing expertise, get
questions answered,
and get comfortable with
the idea of adopting
something like
that because it's a change
and they're going
to be like well,
has anybody
thought about X?
Has anybody thought
about this?
about that?
And what if we're
doing this?
So they're going
to be looking for
some place to go to
get answers to that.
And I don't know if right
now there is a place
they could go.
So that's one thing.
If you develop that
kind of place,
it would be nice to have
a relationship like
a liaison relationship
with something like IETF.
Again, because
you're right, IETF,
if you can say, well,
IETF gave us
comments on this,
then everybody is there's
real people
involved in this,
[LAUGHTER] it's not
just an academic idea.
There are people
who are involved in
real networking issues
and fundamental
grappling with what
needs to be done
to keep this vast
networking system
moving involved
with this so
we feel more comfortable.
The other advantage,
of course,
is that liaisons with
standard organizations
give you
access to other groups.
For instance, you might
want to establish
your liaison with the IIC,
which is the
Cloud community,
because they also would
be interested in this.
Just so that
they are aware
of this is happening
and this is going on,
I would say you're
not really talking
about an industry
consortium
so much as you're
talking about
a subject matter
consortium.
Also I will point
out SDOs are
the only one
who can put out
standards and generally
specifications,
and there are
standards for who is
this standard development
organization.
>> [LAUGHTER]
Great. Thank you.
>> If I could add
something now and
inside I didn't listen
to your last comment,
which is often
services are
vertical for the
energy industry,
and we're probably one of
the few vertical
focus people that's
crossing the horizontal
of this group.
And so our customers
could care less about
IETF standards.
They care about
IEEE standards,
NERC, CIP
regulations, IEC.
So if it becomes
important to my people,
they will become
IEEE standards
for the cybersecurity
of energy systems
using NDN like things.
We're working with people
like that that are
open to including
things like IEEE.
[OVERLAPPING]
>> Does NDN work
with IEC 62443?
>> No, 61850.
>> Oh, 61850.
>> But we're actually
working on that.
And so this is
a meadow standards
problem where now we're
talking about
two-dimensional things,
and there's not
enough resources
in this space yet to
address all of that,
but we can start to
make some progress and
help the horizontal
group that's doing
the hard technical work
understand the needs
of the vertical group
which will be
less technical
or application focused.
So if that made sense.
>> Great, thanks. I wanted
to give a chance to
look over Kathy.
I need to comment on
what's been said so far.
Any comments
from you guys?
>> I think those are
very valid perspective,
the whole horizontal
versus vertical.
And in some sense,
especially for NDN,
if there are groups
that are looking
at specific applications
or use cases,
it may make more sense to
look at those aspects
for a start small.
But I still do believe
that there is a lot
of benefit too,
in some sense,
standardizing the
code, if you will,
because a lot
of times, it's
open to this version or
something like that.
So if you have a way
to download the code and
try out your applications,
that may be a
good place to go.
While we are talking
on that discussion of
the path to specification
and standardization.
And we can start small,
it could be a couple of
a few applications
or even,
first we're looking at
the energy industry,
or first we're looking at
healthcare and
then we expand
to other areas, wherever
there's interest.
So those are all,
I think, valid options.
>> Luca, did you have
anything to add?
>> Not much. I
think there are
many good comments.
Maybe one last
thing I would
say is that as working
for the industry,
you try, you go
standard when you
really can do
it on your own.
If there is something
you can do internally
and it doesn't disrupt
your business, you
don't need standards.
And you may exploit
existing standards
and you can
change them as
long as you can.
You have full control
of your system,
including the system
you're using right
now before doing meetings.
It is not using
standard RTP to
something different.
But they own
the entire applications
and they deploy it
without any
interoperability
with other partners.
And that's okay for them.
So their business continue
to work without
any standards.
Standard implies that
you have a community,
you have multiple
actors that need
to cooperate for the
sake of the business.
>> Great. Thanks.
I wanted to
bring up an example
that I'm familiar with,
and I have to admit
my exposure and
experience with
consortia and
standards is very limited.
But this is an
example that
I thought was interesting,
and this comes from
the automotive sector.
And maybe that
would act as
an inspiration for
further thoughts
for this group
and the example comes from
an alliance called COVESA
or the Connected
Vehicle Alliance.
And they're working
together on developing
VSS or the Vehicle
Signal Specification.
So not a standard,
so specification.
Now what this is,
is a naming scheme
for all the signals
that you can get
from a vehicle.
So if you're familiar
with vehicles,
there's a lot of
information that goes
back and forth inside
cars and the way
these things are
transmitted is by signals.
And these tend to be
very small data pieces,
but they are,
for example, the
brake pedal has
been pressed
or the headlights need
to go on and so forth.
And all that
information is
really useful once you
get it out of the car,
put it in the Cloud,
and then you
start developing
applications on
top of those,
for example the
insurance industry
is extremely
interested in getting
all that data because
they want to offer models
such as pay as
you drive or
pay how you drive
and so forth.
Now, what happened with
these signals is
that every automaker
came up with their
own way of naming
them and
representing them,
and the result of that
is somebody was using
miles per hour,
somebody was using
kilometers per hour,
celsius, fahrenheit
and so forth.
It was a complete
mess when
it came to trying
to correlate
these data in
the Cloud and
to give it to a customer
like the insurance
agencies.
What COVESA did is
to sponsor an effort
to bring everybody
together and
standardize the names
for these signals with
the goal of
everybody now has
the same name and
now we can develop
common applications
over these.
They approached
W3C with the idea
and found a group
where everybody
was enthusiastic,
everybody agreed
that there
was a need for this.
And they came up with
a representation,
which by the way
is hierarchical,
very NDN compatible.
And they're
working on putting
together the
specification and code
to manipulate all the data
that the specification
represents.
Then moving forward, this
seems to be successful,
it seems to be a
success story,
and a lot of
the automakers
seem to be embracing
this effort.
The reason for
mentioning this is I
was wondering if
this is something,
an example that
NDN could follow.
I think the value
proposition for
VSS is that everybody
speaks the same language,
we can now build
applications.
We have a broader value
proposition in NDN.
We have to offer security,
we can offer transport
and so forth.
And therefore,
I think there's
a good value
proposition there,
although the
story's a little
more complicated than VSS.
Is that a model that can
potentially work in the
case of NDN, Randy?
>> Well, I think
based on what I've
learned in the
last 40 minutes,
I would say that's
the follow-on of
adoption because
now you said over there
for multiple car companies
using them in the
standards or
specification,
in this case,
would evolve.
And so I don t
think we're there,
I don't think we're
really close here.
And when we're getting the
first taste of that,
in our case, I
think it will
happen naturally when it's
time now that I
think through this.
So I think it
would be an indicator
of success,
but it's not a way
to cause success.
That's bad news.
[LAUGHTER] That
I think that's
the reality.
>> Fair enough.
Luka any thoughts
on this one?
>> I perfectly agree with
this last comment because
the use case you
mentioned is
essentially again,
we have people,
big industrial
partners that require
that standard
effort to happen
to continue doing
their own business
essentially.
So unless you
have a proof of
value in the end let's
take this example,
in the end, can be
adopted in that industry.
And then
standardization will
come right after.
You mentioned essentially
a technical advantage
that you see if
that matches
also in adoption
from those people,
then yes, you may end
up doing standards,
but not the other way
round you need to
do this first to
get the adoption from them
because essentially
they adopted
the technology.
It was everyone doing
different things,
well the same
thing differently,
and then at some point,
they decided that
standard was
important. Not the
other way around.
>> Thanks, sounds good.
At the end, I will give
you a chance to respond.
>> Sure. I
personally actually,
I've always believed
that especially
the namespace
part mean it need
not be the first team
to be standardized
as Randy and
Luca have said.
This is what I personally
always believed.
But I wanted to
share a couple of
interesting anecdotes
where in some of
those commercialization
discussions it's
actually come to a halt
because you mean there's
no standard way of
representing all of these
are anion is named based,
but you mean there's no,
at least even if
there are multiple
options, again,
you use this naming scheme
or use the other
naming scheme?
Well, you mean
there's nothing I can
do that it's actually
come to a halt a couple of
times when
people find out,
you mean there's
nothing out there and
you have to do everything
all by yourself.
So just wanted to share
some perspectives.
>> Thanks [inaudible].
So I did say I
wanted the audience
to contribute if
they wanted to,
anybody from the audience
here wants to
add something.
>> Hi, this is
Jeff Flight.
>> Go ahead.
>> I have put some
comments in the chat,
but I agreed standardizing
it from end to
end is probably
not necessary and maybe
counterproductive
but there's a couple
of areas that standards
are really required.
One is in the
networking aspects.
If you're going to
build devices and
network infrastructure
that can
operate with endian
directly and by the way,
that network
infrastructure
is increasingly
software-based,
Kubernetes as a CNI.
And of course, with
all the other
stuff going on
in the networking world,
you have to have
some degree
of standardization
because a high degree
of interoperability
is required.
Not a little bit
of it a lot.
And you just can't
do that through
bilateral
discussions and swap
meets and stuff like that.
I found that to
be very problematic
in my career.
The second area is
with Application
Development.
So endian presents
a new way
that applications
can network
and share data etc.
So you need an
adaptation layer
that's a bit
different than
a file system or an
object store or
something like that
that can be interacted
with by the applications.
endian presents
an opportunity
for the application to
actually control
a lot more
about their data
than they can today.
So if you want developers,
they've got to
have a target
to develop against,
otherwise, it won't work.
So those are
two areas where
a degree of stability
and a high degree of
specification in
my experience,
would be very helpful
so that you can
drive developer
adoption with
an application
interface and you
can dive networking
standardization.
So if people
feel comfortable
developing interfaces to
endian and hosting
endian capabilities
with their equipment.
>> Can I say a little bit?
Just from the point
of view of standards,
interoperability is one of
the oldest points to
the standard to come
up with something that you
agree what something
is everywhere.
That's why weights
and measures
are some of the oldest
standards because
you had to have agreement
on how much that
was if you wanted
to trade in it.
So if you're looking
at endian and there
are things, I
guess I would say,
what's that you have to
have in ordering to get
an endian-based
application to work with
any other
endian-application or
with non-endian
applications.
That is something that
is an adoption problem
because customers
and I'm not
talking about
Cisco or Intel,
I'm talking
about the people
Cisco's selling to
want to make sure that
what they buy isn't
a one-off because
they've gotten
caught in that before
where they've
bought stuff.
In fact, the
industrial world is
littered with things
that they have
bought that are not
upgradable or
interoperable with
anything else.
And then they have to
buy all new layer stuff
on top of that.
They've become
shy of things.
I also have to
point out in
terms of your
consortium for the
automotive in the
automotive industry,
the communications within
the vehicle are allegedly
based on an unacknowledged
standard called Canvas,
which was developed
by Bosch.
And then Bosch said, hey,
everybody can use it.
And they all name it
differently because
they never have to
talk to each other.
[LAUGHTER] That's
how that wound up.
So I can see that
the naming
convention might
be an issue with
people saying, "Well,
if I name everything
myself and then I want to
inter-operate with
somebody else
and they've named
all their stuff
differently,
then do I have to
rename everything
or is there a translator
that it can run through?"
So that is an area
of interoperability.
The idea that you'll
be able to work within
a larger universe
than just yourself,
that could drive you
to at least a
specification.
>> Yeah, it's interesting
that you say that you're
absolutely right about
the automotive industry.
They didn't
name everything
the same way because
they didn't have to.
>> Because they don't
like each other.
>> And they don't
>> Or insurance companies.
>> So this was in
complete contrast
with a tracking industry
because they came up with
the naming standard
DJ 1939 standard.
And the reason for doing
that is that in the
tracking world,
you don't order a car from
a single manufacturer and
you get it complete.
You say I want this,
I what these, I want that.
And then everybody
had to be able
to talk to each
other because
to obey the specification
that you ordered,
the attracts us.
A little bit of history
there in terms of
them trying to
work together.
>> I will say this will
also be a major issue
with any heavily
regulated industries.
>> Yeah. Talking about
interoperability
and getting things
to work with each other,
I always had this sense
that with the NDN,
could we come to
a point where
all somebody has
to specify was
the naming scheme and
how things relate
to each other?
So in other words, a lot
of people mentioned
so far that it would
be great if I could
use this without having to
write any code or
very little code.
How easy it is to use
from the beginning,
it's crucial and it's
a big factor in terms
of me deciding
to adopt it.
Would it be possible
within the end to come to
a point where
somebody comes
in with their
naming structure,
the hierarchical
and we can help
specify how that is.
And then the relationships
we talk about security,
for example, tracks,
schema, and and all that.
Could we get to the point
where somebody comes in
with a naming
structure and
the relationships
between the data,
the content that
they want to adopt,
and then import this into
NDN and then they
release, you can use it?
Or is this too much
of a pipe dream?
>> So when you say
import it and there
you can use it,
are you talking about
application development
or are you talking,
okay I just have
the naming scheme
and now I can use
that in the
application that
I've already developed?
>> Yes. You have a
naming scheme in
the application that
you want to use,
you import it to NDN
and now you have
transport and
secure transport.
I think Lisa has a lot
to say about this one.
>> You want me to talk?
So outrageous opinion.
Take a big grain of salt
before you hear me.
Look, we're getting into
this award of
name the data.
Think about the older days
we still have this
award of I dress,
identify the nodes with
the Internet
still exist if
everyone has their
own registries.
So I think it's a similar
analogy is the same thing.
One thing I learned
from Jeff Berg,
I learned so many things
from him over the years.
Data is not bounded to
specific applications.
Data will cross
application boundaries.
The trivial
example, you drag
a picture out of your
[inaudible] and you
drop into email.
You incorporate that into
your PDF files and
no one who knows where it
goes, things like that.
So if we think of
the future world
is everyone swaps
named the data,
then you do have to have
a shared namespace.
I think that's a
fundamental points.
>> I will say that
the Internet
naming schemes
may not be the
best example,
since that was owned by
the US government
and just had
a single owner impose
it on everybody and
then eventually it got
taken over by the world.
But the naming convention
had already existed.
So it was a little easier.
>> For namespace,
this part,
I realize that people
have all the
different opinions.
I think that's where
given a discussion,
maybe we'll have
a yet another
[inaudible] next year.
And specifically have
a panel on maybe.
In Panel 1,
I think one of the topics
we touched upon is naming.
And you can remember
the panelists have very
different opinions,
so I will stop.
Am not going to drop into
that wormhole for now.
But I just wanted
to point it
out that, "Hey, guys.
Look at the the
big picture,
we're getting to
name the data."
So you have to think about
a shared namespace
so that there's
interoperability.
>> Great. Harman,
you had a comment?
>> Yeah. Just a quick
comment and a question.
So I'm less worried
about the naming,
but more worried
about the features
and functionalities
because
each industry have
different needs.
The health
industry, they need
different features
compared to
the automotive
industry, for example.
Energy industry,
same thing.
So I liked the
discussion about
vertical standards
versus horizontal,
for example.
So the mainstream
will be horizontal,
but industries needs
vertical centralization,
which means different
specification,
different features.
I can't just take
the general NDN
and just put it in
a car and expect
it to work.
No, it's not going to
work. For example,
does not support
automotive
specific features.
How does it communicate
with other communication
standards?
It was like
the can communication
we talked about.
There is flex rate, there
is Linn, there's ethernet.
So there's a bunch
of other standards
that needs to be
supported as well.
That's at least from
an automotive standpoint.
There is time sink,
there is diagnostics.
It's going to be a can of
worms, but it's not.
It has been done so
many times with other,
I would say, contenders,
I would say.
So NDN really brings
networking and
security in one place.
But the question
is, what resources
are available for
the standardization?
Because it's a huge topic
and standardizing a
horizontal, it's
extremely difficult.
So my opinion, starting
with the verticals,
like small industries or
different specification
for each industry,
for example, I think
that's the step
towards global or
horizontal standardization.
>> If I add onto that.
First of all, I understand
your concern about
the horizontal,
but I want to add,
however, horizontal
is based on
today's model of
how system works.
We already run into
problems with this,
for example, cases,
Internet drafts.
I think she tried
to transport first
and transporters we
don't care about security.
So today's I hate to
make too many enemies.
But today's like the
IETF areas structure,
totally based on the
old modeling of areas.
So transport cares about
congestion
control and seems
like don't kill me.
Congestion control only,
security, not
part of that.
Because we have this model
of a security is really
outside of
[inaudible] area,
transported area, or
your application area.
There's an add-on. But at
the end fundamentally
change in that.
In the inside,
security is a part of
the basic gene as
a design the end.
So therefore,
our security
shouldn't be really
a totally separate
area per se.
But security must be
a ingredient, all
the components.
So maybe in that sense,
I would support your
things so-called heart.
Where do you go? But it's
not really what they go.
Essentially, as a new
architecture model,
and really asking for
different ways
to partition
the functional modules,
that's different from
what I have [inaudible].
>> I'll just clarify.
Horizontal standards
exist outside security.
Basically, a
horizontal standard is
a general statement of
best practices for
whatever it is.
There are horizontal
standards in safety,
there are horizontal
standards in security,
standards
in other areas.
And then the vertical
standard says,
within this particular
industry or usage,
this is how we are taking
that horizontal
standard and
making it
particular to us.
So 62443,
I'm going back to
the security space,
but this is true.
The safety stays too,
62443 is a
horizontal standard.
It is applicable to
any industrial automation.
AGA, the American
Gas Association has
a whole series of
security standards that
are based on 62443,
but then talk in detail
about what's
necessary for,
say, pipeline or
refineries, cyber security.
And they've done the
exact same thing
with the safety standards.
So a horizontal
standard is meant to
give the broadest
possible,
highest possible set of
best practices
and requirements,
which then in
vertical standards
can be specified.
So I just wanted to say
that there's actually
a formal definition of
a horizontal standard
verse a vertical.
>> Great. So I wanted
to move to the
last question for today,
and I wanted to make sure
we have some time
to cover this.
So this has to do with
how to make impacts.
And so it goes a
little broader than
standards or specifications
and so forth.
But I wanted to get
thoughts from the panel
about ways to make
impact with NDN.
And when we
started with NDN,
it was part of
the future internet
architectures project.
It was a project
at the NSF
that essentially
challenged
researchers with coming up
with the next version
of the Internet.
So it was a very
big change.
They essentially
challenged us with,
you're complaining
about Internet
all this time,
tell us, if you
were to design
the Internet today,
how would you do it?
However, making
impact doesn't
necessarily mean that you
have to be at that scale.
You can make impact
in many other ways.
For example, you can make
a small change
that affects
a large group
or you can make
a big change that
affects a small group.
And I wonder if
we need to start
looking at other ways
of making impact beyond
perhaps the original
task of NDN.
Randy, I think you
have some thoughts.
You have some
work on that one?
>> Well, [NOISE] I like
it because it allows me to
reiterate my
basic point here,
which is that we really
at Opera only care
about the bottom lin.
We want to affect
a small group,
and the small
group is literally
the few customers
that will buy
our product in
the next year.
Like we just need to
influence a few people.
The next stage
of our company
requires a couple
of more customers,
the size of the
constellation people.
We just need to convince
them and the rest of
this will follow.
So that's the big change
to the small
people I think.
And we're really close
because we can
totally engage with
visionary early
adopters inside
significant corporations.
We can get in
front of them.
They like the message.
We need the material
that I call
the internal sales
tools to get to
the pragmatists
within the company.
And so that has a lot of
similarities to
the things that it
takes to build a
specification,
as I pointed out, but
we need them for a
different purpose,
which is a
predecessor step.
And my product VP
told me another line
I wanted to put out there,
which is customers
buy benefits.
I think Lucas said that.
Technologists talk
about elegance
and future dreams,
and up until the stage
right now we're really
good at selling
future dreams
of customer benefits.
We've made that
much progress.
So we can tell
them what it's
going to do for
them someday,
but we need to get to
the thing where
we can say,
what will it do
for you today?
And we're not
quite there yet.
So that's how all this
work could help us.
>> Great. So
looking at the end,
I guess you guys
are coming from a
bigger, large
company perspective.
So I wanted to
see what you
think about this idea.
[inaudible], did
want to go first?
>> Yeah, thanks.
I agree. We
started out with,
yes, a new Internet,
a big change.
And I think that's going
to be a lot harder,
not even realistic
in some sense.
So then the
question becomes,
how do you make
those improvements or
changes in specific areas
and agree with
where Randy said in
general is identify
those applications,
where really NDN can make
a big benefit and
go after those?
And then work with
the Internet that
we have today,
making it better
rather than replacing.
And in fact, when
I started working
in this area,
I would preface
all my slides.
Initially we're
saying, no,
we are not trying
to replace IP.
We're not trying to
change the Internet,
because a lot of times
you could be like,
now you're going to say,
we're going to
change everything,
I don't even
want to listen,
and people would shut
down immediately.
So right now even when
I talk, by the way,
I don't even use
IP versus NDN,
it's more existing
networks,
or existing technologies,
existing application
versus doing it.
You're implementing
those with NDN.
And I think that's where
the discussion needs
to be in terms
of adoption and actually
seeing light of day in
terms of
commercialization.
So here in this area
or in this particular
computing application
in this, and I'm just
throwing things out there.
[inaudible]
environment, yes,
we see a lot of benefits.
Let's make that real.
How do we do it?
Whether does it needs
some standardization?
But I think the
first step is
just identifying
where these big changes
are and then we can
go after those.
>> So [inaudible],
I'm curious,
would you say you
have success when
you're talking to
customers in this,
I guess, more limited?
>> That's a very
good question and
a tough question
to answer.
Yes and no. And it
has been a journey.
Initially when
we started out,
we were exploring
the entire area.
And that's when
we realized
when we're talking
about content,
delivery people
didn't even
want to hear because yes,
we have CDNs, why
do we need this?
And especially,
that applied
when data was moving
from the core of
the network to
the edge of the
network like Netflix.
But then as
applications evolved,
there are situations
where data is generated
at the edge of
the network and
used at the edge
of the network,
and there's a
lot of mobility
and lack of stability
of the networks,
if you will.
Our mesh networking
where tracking
down your addresses
becomes a lot harder,
but people do see
the value there.
And another area where
people see values,
like if you even
look at Kubernetes,
all the resources have to
be in the control
of one domain,
and that's how
Kubernetes operate,
which is great for
the Cloud or for
the most data
centers everywhere.
But if you're looking at
this far edge where
you're talking about
client devices, cars,
laptops, cell
phones, and if you
want to pull together
these resources,
they will all
never agree to be
owned or controlled
by one entity.
So how do you do that?
People saw that,
yes, it's useful,
then that's
where the question of
adoption also becomes.
Then the question
becomes, okay,
how much gain
am I getting,
and how much do I
have to change?
And that's where the
discussion gets tricky.
And this is where the
inertia also kicks in.
How can I make
some change to an
existing code?
Yes, I don't get the
perfect solution,
but can I live with
it at least for
the next five years before
things really break?
It's the same question
that Randy also
brought up is,
how can it solved
my problem
like tomorrow
or this year?
So yes, I think
to some extent,
yes, we've seen success,
but then the adoptability,
ease of writing
applications,
all of that also come in.
But I think overall,
and I'm making this as
a general statement
from what I've
seen like even like from
a lot of the RFPs
that come out,
I think the
defense segment is
a lot more open to NDN.
And I'm saying this in
a very broad manner,
just looking at RFPs
that have come out
from DARPA and so on,
and not based on any
scientific
research per se.
So that's my take on it.
>> Great. Thanks. So Luca,
I was wondering what
your thoughts are,
how do you see NBN,
trying to move
into this more,
I think the term
that I heard
was limited
network domains?
And if you have
talked to any of your
customers and if you
had any success in
terms of NBN going
in that direction.
>> So in my personal
experience,
we moved into HACN,
which is essentially using
a different namespace,
but all the machinery
is similar.
That doesn't change
the experience.
And we moved into
something we
control completely,
which is online meetings
because it's a segment
that Cisco owns,
WebEx for instance, and
WebRTC and these things.
So that was easier, but
the community doesn't care
about NDN or ICN
or whatever.
Essentially
because you have
to talk with
product manager,
you have to talk
people who have to
invest money to insert
the feature in
running product.
And the motivation is
always revenue driven,
which is if the
business is growing,
is not really about cost,
is more about
application quality.
Essentially, if I get
this picture
in my product,
is my application product
in service better
than the competition?
So you need to answer
that question.
If your business is
stagnating or decreasing,
then you can
focus on cost.
And so you're going
to need to answer
the question how much
can I save from my
operational costs?
For instance, in the case
of WebEx Cloud costs.
And so during the
last few years,
we've seen both
growing and
stagnation and then for
COVID and then decreasing.
And so we had to answer
all those questions.
And so you need to have
a way to answer
this questions.
How much can I say
from Cloud cost?
Or how better my video
or audio or general
this application?
How better with
respect to Zoom,
I'm going to be?
And how many more
customers can
get if I use
your technology?
And so you need to
be able to measure
that one way or the other.
So AB testing was
our approach to have
measurable answers
to those questions.
And this is a very
limited domain,
because essentially
we don't have
to interoperate
with anybody.
It's our application, our
infrastructure that we can
deploy all software
and [inaudible].
So we don't need
any standard.
We just need to
essentially to
bind to it as a
business unit.
So that's an opportunity.
But as also Rainey
was saying,
you need to make your
customers happy,
because at the
end of the day
this is your
revenue stream
that is going to fund
everything else.
And so I don't have
the solution
for everything,
but as long as you have
a good answer for
your customers and
they are buying into
it, follow the road.
Because it means if
they're ready
to pay for it,
that's enough,
you don't need
more than that.
>> Great. Thanks
Luca. So we've got
just about five or
six minutes left.
And I did want
to give an opportunity
to the panelists.
So given that most
of us here are
in academia.
If there's something
you wanted
to say to us academics,
what would it be?
And since we had
Luca talking,
I think I want to
continue with him.
So Luca, here's all
the academics here.
Is there some advice?
Is there something
you want to
tell us about NDN?
>> Well, I think that
academia should focus
on solving our problems.
The industry doesn't
have time to focus on,
because the industry
has to focus on,
again, make your
customers happy.
And so in some
cases you need to
fix things in quicker
dirty manner so
that it works as long
as the revenue continues
to get in and that's it.
But the academia should be
there not to write
a codebase that is
used in the industry.
The mission of
the academia
is to solve our
problems and I
think there are many in
general in this domain.
And then if
there is again,
the industry that is
making profit out
of components of
this technology,
then this is going to
flow back to the
academia because
the industry will
need the academia
to work and to think about
longer term problems
that are hard
and that the industry
has no time to focus on.
But the data
examples like in
the Linux Foundation where
you get a lot of people,
100% funded by the
industry where they sit
together, they
fix problems,
which are
essentially around
codebases which
going into their
own products.
There's nothing to do
with academia and so I
think it's fair to
distinguish the
two things.
The industry and academia
is not the same codebase.
>> Great, thank
you. So Kathyayani,
given that academics
were probably most
likely are not
going to write
the code that
industry will use.
So what should we
be focusing on?
How can we help
you guys industry
promote NDN better?
>> That's a great question
and thanks for
asking that.
One of the ways I think
as I brought it out
is identifying
where there are
the really big
bang for NDN.
And sometimes that's
a very hard problem
because in general,
we say yes, it
provides security,
it provides
caching, discovery,
provides all of these,
but where are we
really seeing the
100x benefits?
Where are those use cases,
their applications?
And it's bringing
those out to
the forefront
and it doesn't
have to be perfect
commercial code.
But even
comparison, saying,
there is this application,
do it this way and look
at how much easier it is.
And it doesn't
always have to be
quantified in
the traditional manner
of performance.
Even security saying, yes,
and I'm just giving
examples here.
Either these many lines
of code versus
you can just
do it with x number
of lines of code.
Or it requires
this many hours
of development
versus this,
or even more
concrete saying,
look how much easier
and quicker or faster,
and how much
better performance
you get if you do it.
And there's
really big ones.
The general ones
we all know about.
But identifying
in some sense
the silver bullets that,
where is the really
huge impact?
And that could
be a big help.
>> Great. So
what I'm hearing
is quantifying
the advantages.
Give us something
to [OVERLAPPING].
>> All sensor silver
bullets where
it's really the advantage
it's huge here,
because in general, yes,
we are all aware
of the benefits.
But obviously
it's not been
enough to move
the industry.
But there are areas
where NDN can
provide much
bigger benefits
than other areas.
So pointing,
showing that out
and bringing those
to light and telling
the industry look
at these areas.
Focus on these
areas and you
will see huge benefits.
That will be a big
value, in my opinion.
Great. Thank you.
Randy. How can
we make your life easier?
>> I wanted to
make two points.
I think one is, I've
worked in a bunch of
different industry
sectors and
research areas over
my long career now.
This is one of the most
open and accepting
academic communities
for industry
collaboration.
Everybody wants to provide
this question
you're asking.
And so keep it
up that's going
to be important if we
make the next steps.
So that's a good thing.
I personally feel falling
up on Kathy Annie's point
is that mandated
cybersecurity is
the opportunity
for NDN because
mandates don't
allow industries
to measure benefits like
they have to do it.
And so a utility has
requirements
and accept they
must meet these
requirements.
Now, the question is,
how much will it cost?
How good will it
be? That thing.
And in our case,
the Department of
Energy has funded us in
early years
largely to provide
technology they
believe will
be necessary to meet
the mandated
requirements for
security that will
come to the grid.
And so they see
the vision.
They pay us to
get there first.
Academic partners are
super-important to
that research program
because that's where we
get our credibility in
our actual technology.
And so continuing
to partner with
industrial people who
are going to meet
mandated cybersecurity
things is your best bet.
So health, like
land's doing, pharma,
energy, there's
maybe automotive
or trucking like these
will be mandates.
And so we had a
little luck in
our last company
where we made
solar measurement
technology equipment
like test equipment and
the government
required you measure
the solar potential
of any site and
so everybody had the buyer
or equipment all
of a sudden.
That could happen
here. We don't know.
So that's my
encouragement.
>> That sounds
great. Thank you.
>> Suzanne,, you
have the last
word of the day.
>> Oh, my goodness.
I have the last
word of the day.
I think there's two
levels of development.
There is the level
of development that
takes place at
places like Cisco,
Intel, Honeywell, etc,
where they are
implementing
it into the products.
I think one of the most
important things
from their point
of view is that
their customers
have no idea they did it.
They don't want to explain
this to the
grid operators.
They don't want
to explain this
to the chemical plants.
The chemical plants
just want this to work.
and if they then
get all these
security benefits,
that's great, but I am not
retraining anybody
to do this.
I just want it to
work and I want
to be able to buy
things going on
that all work
together and not have
to deal with any of this.
Because if I never
hear anything
about NDN I will
be happy for
the rest of my life
because they're
operators and they
don't really care.
So I think that
it's helpful for
academics because they are
willing to deal with
all the things that
go on under the hood.
So that when the grid
buys this from Cisco,
whatever, they
don't have to care.
Just like they don't
currently care how
the Internet works.
They really could
not care less.
And most of the
time they have
no idea and they
don't want to know.
So I think that you
have to realize that
NDN is the thing that
no one is going to
care how it works as
long as it works
completely invisibly.
And if you get
to that point,
they will all be
happy with it.
>> Sounds great.
Thank you.
That concludes the
panel for today.
Let's thank the
panelists. Thank you.
[APPLAUSE] Luke
and Kathy Annie,
thank you so much
for participating.
Luke, special
thanks to you for
staying up late. We
appreciate this.
>> Thank you.
>> Welcome back, everyone.
Agenda now is
session number
five on applications
and services,
and will be chaired by
Demetrius from MITER.
Demetrius is
head of R&D of
infrastructure
networking division at
MITER and has been
involved with NDN for
a number of years.
So Dima, go ahead, please.
>> Thank you. So
we're about to
start for everyone
in the back.
So for this session,
we have one demo and
we have four
presentations.
We will kick it
off with a demo.
mGuard is secure
mHealth data-sharing
infrastructure
over NDN from
Suravi Regmi.
He's a PhD student and
research assistant at
the University of Memphis,
working with Dr. Lan Wang.
And she'll have
a video to play.
>> Thank you.
Hello everybody.
My name is Suravi Regmi.
And I will be doing
a demo on mGuard
secure mHealth data
sharing infrastructure
over NDN.
So this slide might
look a bit familiar
because we've been
through this
yesterday as well so
the presentation
started barons.
So I'll try and keep
this very short.
mGuard is designed
to achieve
fine-grain contextual
access control using
user-defined access
control policies.
And it provides real-time
data delivery using
high-level Pub-Sub API
and supports
high-frequency data.
So the goal of this
presentation is
to demonstrate the
overall system,
especially the access
control policies
and the Pub-Sub API.
So let's get into
the access
control policies.
It is designed to
limit data access to
only authorized
users based
on terms of use
and privacy risks.
And it is defined
by the data owner.
So our policy description
looks pretty
simple because we
want users who are
not technically
inclined to be
able to write
their own policy
descriptions.
So we've got
requestor names.
It can be one person,
multiple people,
a team of people, and
attribute filters.
We can have
multiple attribute
filters as well.
We are using policy A, B,
and C. These are
the policies that
we are using in the
demonstration as well.
The first policy we've
got requests for data
requests to Alice.
And they have the
attribute filter
where we allow them to
access all the streams
under the prefix org md2k.
For policy B, we've
got requester Bob.
We allow them to access
everything with
prefix org md2k,
but we deny them the
GPS stream of data.
And for policy C,
we've got user Saurab.
We allow them the semantic
locations stream.
But we've got
another thing right
there that says
attributes location home,
which basically means
that Saurab can access
all semantic
location data if
they're generated
in location home.
Next, we use policy parser
to parse the access
control policies,
to create ABE policy,
which we will use to
obtain the decryption key.
So you can see
in the example,
we've got our policy,
which is a bit
simpler than
the ABE policy which
explains it a lot more.
The current status
of our project is
that we've implemented
all the modules in C++.
Feel free to go through
the source code
installation guide.
Let us know what
we're doing
wrong or you
can help with.
So for the demo setup,
we've got mGuard server
that's running producer,
controller, and
repository,
which is connected
to the Memphis node.
All three of these
applications
can be run separately,
but for the demo purposes,
we've run this in
the same server.
We've got three
different consumers with
distinct policies
running in three
different nodes.
And the controller
is configured
with all the access
control policies.
We've got three
data streams,
the semantic location
data stream,
the battery data stream,
and the GPS data stream.
And for the data
generation,
we've used 120 data
points per minute.
We could have
got to bigger,
but for demonstration
purpose,
we wanted you to
visualize that data.
And policies, as I
mentioned already.
We've got three
different policies
for three different users.
So this is the topology
that we're using.
We can see that
the mGuard server
is connected to
the Memphis node.
We've got Alice
on the UCLA node,
Saurab connected
to Arizona node,
and Bob to Osaka.
So I just play
the video next.
[NOISE]
Is there audio available?
I'm just completed.
[BACKGROUND]
>> [BACKGROUND]
>> Yeah. That's good.
Can just explain it as
the video plays.
Thank you.
Let me just increase
the resolution first.
I just wanted to show you
the policy that we're
using that I
just described.
We got policy,1 where
it shall access
all the streams under the
prefix ndn/org/md2k.
This is for
request for Alice.
Policy 2, we've got
Bob who shall access
all the streams under
the ndn/org/md2k prefix,
but we deny the GPS
stream for that user.
And for user 3,
that's Saurab,
they shall access
all data under
semantic location collected
at home location.
This is the runner script
that's basically
running the repo,
the controller
and producer.
So here we have
the runner script.
So we're running
the mGuard server
and we have advertised
the md2k prefix as well.
Next we will move on
to the consumer end.
So we've got
three consumers.
The first one is Bob.
If we go back
to the policy,
Bob should be allowed
two of the three prefixes.
They're not allowed
the GPS stream.
So we can see
that they can
subscribe to any
of those stream.
The battery and GPS
semantic location stream,
we will try and
subscribe to both.
Here we get the data for
semantic location
and battery.
You can see that
there's batches
of data being produced
because our producer is
generating data
in batches.
And as it inserts the
data into the repo,
the consumer gets
a notification
and then it fetches it.
So it's going
continuously.
So it's real time.
Next, we've got Alice.
Alice is the one with
the policy where they can
actually fetch all
of the streams.
We ran into an
error. [LAUGHTER] So
I had to do this again.
So all three streams
available for Alice.
Let's just subscribe
to one, I guess.
We've subscribed to
the GPS stream
and then Alice
gets all of the GPS
related data that
they subscribe to.
And finally,
the last consumer that
we have is Saurab.
In Saurab's policy,
we mentioned that they
can only access data
related to the semantic
location stream
and the attribute also
states that they should be
able to access data
generated only at
home location.
They're are only
allowed to subscribe to
one stream and
when we do that,
we can note that
the data that they
get are all generated
in the home location.
If we go back to Bob,
we can see that they
were able to access
all semantic location data
generated in
different locations,
like shopping mall,
home, gym, work.
But in Saurab's case,
it was just home base.
What our policy
was defined
for and that's what
the user wanted.
That is the end of
our demo. Thank you.
[APPLAUSE] Are there
any questions?
Yeah. If there's anything,
you can put it into
Slack as well.
>> My question is
[NOISE] [inaudible]?
>> Yeah. So currently
we're using data
generation,
where I think
we're generating
like 120 data
points per minute.
And then we use sleeper
while and then
send it again.
Since we do not have
access to them
to get data,
we've created a
library where we
generated data and
then run our program.
Thank you. We've got
another question. Yeah.
>> [NOISE] Is that
better? I may
have not been paying
good attention,
but did I see that your
access control
policy includes
both deny and allow
as operations?
>> Yes.
>> How do you mitigate
interactions of
those to prevent
impossible situations?
So it's just a
curiosity question.
>> Yeah. I guess,
we need somebody
to evaluate
the user control policy
because a user
get to decide.
And we were
discussing that,
what if a user adds in
one attribute filter allow
this policy and in
the second
attribute filter
deny that same thing.
So I guess we will
need to implement
a feature to prevent
that from happening.
>> The parser will detect
all the conflicts and
will warn the user
there's conflicts
in the policies.
>> Yeah.
>> So that's similar then
to the vasec compiler
[OVERLAPPING].
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> Where it won't
compile if you create
a logical mismatch.
>> Right. Exactly.
>> They seem very
adamant that denial
by default was an
important thing for users.
So I've been keeping
that thought.
So this is just the topic
to discuss. Nothing
meaningful.
>> Yeah. The parser checks
all the potential
logic errors.
Thank you, Dr. Wong.
>> Thank you.
[APPLAUSE] So
our next speaker
or title for
this speaker is is
NDN opportunity in
5G, 6G core networks.
And this is from
Junxiao Shi.
Junxiao is a computer and
information scientist
at National
Institute of Standards
and Technology.
He is a core NDN developer
and has been developing
NDN network for
[inaudible] since 2013.
He also enjoys
building websites
and browser-based
NDN applications.
>> Hi, my name
is Junxiao Shi.
Today I'm presenting
NDN opportunities
in 5G and 6G
core networks.
In this presentation,
I will first give
a very brief
introduction of
a 5G core network
architecture,
especially its control and
user plan separation
principle.
Then I will talk
about ideas on
how to run NDN
application over
5G network and how
to simplify 5G
and 6G core architecture
with NDN ideas.
First, let me introduce
the 5G architecture.
In the 5G network, first,
we can have the
user equipment,
UE, such as your
smartphone or tablet.
The UE connects tools
that you know the beat,
which is the component
in the cellular tower
and it's these two forms
the radio access network.
On the other side, it's
the data network,
usually the Internet.
And between the
radio access network
and the data network,
all the services are
provided by the
5G core network.
5G core network,
contains many different
network functions.
And in the 5G standard,
they're separated into
the control plane
and the user plane,
so that each
partner can be
deployed and scaled
independently.
And this helps with the
5G network slicing,
which is a new
property in 5G.
The control plane has
many network
versions providing
services such as
authentication,
morbidity management,
IP address or
location and so on.
The user plane implements
the data plane
functionality,
including packet
routing and forwarding,
traffic usage reporting,
and the QoS handling.
And NDN can be applied to
both user plane
and control plane,
but let's first talk
about the user plane,
how to run NDN applications
over 5G network.
The use case I want to
cover is a live
video streaming,
such as concerts or live
news report from
a 5G phone to
worldwide viewers.
On the left, we have
our streamer
using a 5G phone
and their cameras,
they want to stream
to viewers around
the world and
as the phone is
attached to one of
the 5G networks.
Then there would
be viewers on
phones on the
same 5G network.
There could that
be viewers on
a different 5G network
and there could
be viewers in
front of their computers
on the Internet.
The baseline
scenario that we can
already do today
is everyone
connect to NDN routers on
the Internet through
UDP tunnels.
The streamer has
a UDP tunnel to
a router outside
of the 5G network.
And all the viewers
also connect
to NDN forwraders outside.
But this approach
can be done today,
but it has
drawbacks because
the 5G network doesn't
know anything about NDN.
So that it doesn't
have caching.
The same data
packet would flow
through the 5G core
network multiple times,
which yields
more bandwidth.
And as the 5G
core network has
a very limited QoS
control because as far as
the 5G can see
is they're UDP
tunnel, UDP packets.
They don't see
their names.
There is no way
to prioritize
video traffic over
download traffic
for example.
So to improve, we want
to add NDN forward into
the 5G core network.
Earlier I mentioned that
the UPF user plane
function implements
data plane.
>> So you muted.
Sure you're back.
>> So as NDN User Plane
Function is on
NDN Forwarders
that sets us apart
stateful forwarding an
caching functionality.
Since it's a five GOPF
it to show that also
support high traffic or
usage reporting and
some QoS handling.
With on the IP UPF in
the 5G Core if
you are user,
incremental
suppose and yet
it controls to
connect with
the NDN data network
in addition to
the IP data network and
both current at
the same time.
Then since the
5G Core network
are usually performance
a centralized control so
that in the control plane,
we want to add application
and finishing.
It will provide those
services such as
the preferred registration
or producer
mobility support,
and a centralized routing.
Waste and the IUPF in
the 5G Core can
enhance that scenario.
As a streamer and
as a viewer says,
they will connect
to the NDN UPF
within their 5G network,
and since NDN UPF,
contains a forwarder.
So we can have interests
aggregation and
the network occasion
within the 5G network.
Or we can also have
name based QoS.
Apart from the user plane,
we can also add IUPF into
5G Core network
control plane.
And simplify the control
plane architecture.
Since it's a 5G Core
network diagram,
it has many
different functions
So we want to just improve
the control plane since it
has led to network are
quite complicated.
So we'll improve. Here is
a 5G control
plane currently
has a service-based
architecture
[inaudible] for follow
Microsoft's approach.
What it means is,
all the control
plane functions
are connected that
to a virtual bus.
It's currently realized
as the IP subnet.
And as there is a unified
protocol stack rates on
HTTP tool transport
and the JSON encoding.
So the benefit of adopting
service-based architecture
is to have less
complex in their
communication
and a better
scalability since
it allows,each
network function
will be scaled
independently.
One off, the
network function in
the service-based
architecture is the NRF,
or Network
Repository Function.
It provides a
service discovery
to this IP subnet.
The way it works is
every network
function need
to know where is NRF.
It's a pre-configured with
NRFs IP address and
the port number.
That every network
function where to start
it were rigid
itself with NRF.
Well, one network function
want to talk to another.
It's a need to ask
the NRF where is the
other network version?
Ask her for its IP
address and port number.
So as an example is
the AMF access and
the mobility
management fishing,
neither to talk
to the AUSF,
I sent a caching
server function
during user
authentication.
So way it works is when
a USF initially start
it need reduce its own
IP and port with NRF.
Then NRF remembers
that information
when AMF want to
talk to AUSF,
it ask the NRF,
where is AUSF and
a better answer.
Only after that,
AMF can talk to
the AUSF because it
doesn't know
its IP address.
And AUSF was under the
response to the AMF.
When we replace
IP with NDN we
still have the
service-based architecture,
all the control
plane functions are
connected to a
virtual bus,
but now it is NDN
local area network.
And we still have
a unified the
protocol stack
which is now NDN
transporter.
And the JSON encoding.
But instead of NRF,
we don't need it anymore.
We can perform
a service discovery
using NDN naming.
Since the network
onboarding,
we can notice network
name is example 5G.
So AMF can derive
the AUSF name is
example 5G/ AUSF.
So it can send
this interest
to the local area network.
And because the local
area network currents
and the self-learning.
So self-learning
forwarding strategy can
find as a forwarding
path where it's AUSF.
And if there are
multiple instance
of AUS deployed,
it can also help
with load balancing.
The interests
goes to AUSF and
AUSF can respond a
wizard data to the AMF.
That's how we simplify
the 5G control plane.
To sum up, I presented
a two opportunities
in the 5G network.
One is adding
a forwarded to
the 5G user plane to
enable stateful forwarding
and the network caching.
The other is simplify
5G control plane waste and
beyond sexual as the
service discovery
and some other
features are possible.
But these are just ideas.
So our future work
is we need to
think about as
a protocol design
and prototype
implementation.
Thank you. [APPLAUSE]
>> So thank you
Junxiao, let's see.
Are there any
questions in the room?
>> I have a quick
question if I may.
>> Go ahead, please.
>> Junxiao, the
fantastic idea,
but are you aware of
any network equipment
vendors that are
open in that core network
at the moment that
you could do this on?
>> There's a core network
is entirely a
software-based,
so it's that g node B or
UE is in useers hands
I cannot change,
and g node B is
the hardware.
But as a core network
it's software,
it's the containers, so we
can change it very easily.
And as they are
open-source ones,
there are commercial ones.
>> On Nokia,
Ericsson or
anybody's equipment?
>> This equipment are
usually g node B.
But core is open.
Why it won't open
example such as open
5GS and the 35GC is
the open source.
>> You've just solved
a huge problem for us.
Thank you.
[LAUGHTER] We
need to talk.
>> Other questions online?
So there's one on Slack,
I'm going to read it.
You showed a technology
where the UEs connect to
a single anchor,
NDN enabled UPF.
What are your thoughts on
the possibility of
mobility management using
unique end to end
features such as
simplified and
careless mobility?
>> Roaming, produce
and morbidity.
Yes, it's possible we can
use either NDN user
producer morbidity
and we can also
assist to it
with the NDN application
of function in a
control plane.
>> Thank you, Junxiao.
[APPLAUSE] Our third talk
is from Edmond Yeh,
from Northeastern
University,
is going to work in
NDN for quite a bit.
The title of the talk is
N-DISE NDN base data
distribution for
large-scale data intensive
science experiments.
>> Can you hear me?
>> We can hear you.
>> So thanks for
the opportunity.
I have 20 minutes.
Is that correct?
>> Yes, 16 for
discussions.
>> Great. Well,
I just wanted to give
you an update on
this N-DISE project,
which is an NSF
funded project
for using NDN for
data intensive
science experiments.
And we have actually
a number of
people involved with this
project including NIST.
So the idea is
that we have
many large-scale data
intensive science
applications,
including Large
Hadron Collider
is high-energy physics,
astrophysics applications,
genomics applications
that share similar
challenges.
And the challenges are
that they need to index,
they need to
secure storage.
>> Edmond can you
go full screen?
>> Oh, sorry.
So here we are. Thanks
for the reminder.
They share a similar set
of problems in indexing,
securing, storing,
distributing,
analyzing, and learning
from the data,
coordinated use
of computing,
storage and
network resources.
And as it is today,
these domain experts are
dealing with these
problems themselves.
And since they're not
network specialists,
they have their
application needs.
They develop their
solutions in isolation,
somewhat incrementally
replicated efforts.
And this is mainly
due to the fact
that there is a
gap that exists
between the
application needs
that they have and
existing networks
and systems
which focus on addresses,
processes, servers,
connections,
whereas the
application needs
are really about data.
And so our
approach is to use
ideas from NDN to develop
a data-centric approach to
system and network design
that provides
support for data
through the entire
data lifecycle,
from naming to
authentication to securing,
and the delivering
the data using names
and scalable
data retrieval
in network caching,
automated joint caching
and forwarding,
multicast delivery
in order to
enable network wide data
intensive computation
and learning.
So this is a big project
and we want to develop
a common framework
to support different
application domains.
So this was launched
actually already five
years ago now with
the SANDIE project under
the CC* NSF program.
Continued with the
N-DISE project
in 2020 under the
same program.
It involves
Northeastern Caltech,
UCLA, Tennessee Tech.
So our main focus
has been on
the LHC program in
high-energy physics,
which is one of
the world's largest
data-intensive
applications.
Its volume is set to grow
another 10 times due
to high luminosity
experiments,
which are going to
happen in 2027.
We're also interested in
the genomic applications.
The human genome data
and earth bio genome data,
which is also approaching
exabyte range.
Though all of these
applications need to
use very diverse
computation,
storage and
networking resources.
And we would like to build
an ecosystem to
support that.
The update that
I have is that
the latest results are
really from the
supercomputing
2022 conference.
But let me recap a
little bit what
we have done in
this project up
to this point.
We've developed a
data-centric naming scheme
for a fast access
and efficient
communication in
high-energy physics
and other fields.
So this involves
essentially translating
naming scheme that
exists currently
in high-energy
physics to NBN names.
We've implemented
and integrated
jointly optimal
caching and
forwarding algorithms
developed at
Northeastern
some years ago.
We've integrated
the high-speed
NDN-DPDK forwarder
developed by NIST a
couple of years ago.
And we have developed
an NDN-DPDK base
consumer and
producer application
developed by
Caltech and
integrated that
with the CMS
software stack.
CMS is one of the
big experiments
in high energy physics,
Large Hadron
Collider geophysics.
Integrated with
the CMS stack
through the XRootD plugin,
also developed by Caltech.
We've started to
have FPGA acceleration
subsystems,
which are essentially
accelerate
the hashing function of
the NDN-DPDK forwarder.
And this is
produced by a group
at UCLA and also
the Tennessee Tech
Group has started
to work on the
genomics application.
And they've been doing
some interesting work
on linking
NDN with Kubernetes
implementations.
The detailed results here
have appeared actually in
the proceedings
of ACM ICN paper
that we had in 2022,
which summarizes a
lot of these results.
So for details, you
could go there.
I'm just going to
present some of
the latest results
that we had from SC22,
where we had a major demo.
In fact, we've had
demos actually
for the last five
years or so,
all the SC conferences
starting from SC18.
So we've
gradually improved
their performance.
So here what we
have is when
we have wide area network
that we have set up
consisting of five nodes,
Northeastern, UCLA,
Tennessee Tech,
Caltech, and Starlight.
That's the persistent wide
area network testbed.
Of course, at SC22,
we also had a presence
at the SC22 booth.
So these links
tell you about
the propagation delays and
the speed of the
various links.
So this is really
a continental
wide area network testbed
over which we're
testing this.
I forgot to mention
that through the
collaboration
of various partners,
we're able to
provision VLANs,
which allow us
to implement
NDN protocols at layer 2
of this wide area network.
So let me talk a
little bit about
what performance we
were able to get.
This is from new
consumers at
the SC22 booth and
Starlight and one
producer at Caltech.
We had 100 gigabit per
second tagged
VLAN connections
to both consumers,
with each forwarder using
six forwarding threads and
each consumer
server running
18 consumer
applications to request
18 one gigabite
files named by CMS.
This is a local
testbed at Caltech.
The local testbed gave us
around throughput of 96
gigabits per second.
However, in the WAN,
we were able to get
about 63 gigabits
per second with
a fixed pipeline of
packets with 18
consumer applications
running in parallel at
each consumer node.
So this is a record
for us at SC22.
Certainly the best we've
gotten over the years.
We also tested the
caching performance.
Here we're using
VIP caching,
which was developed by
Northeastern
some years ago.
We [inaudible] two
different topologies.
One topology is a
service topology,
which basically
has fixed routing.
So we're just testing out
the caching performance.
I won't go into all
the details here.
But we compared
the caching
with the case of no
caching and with ARC,
which is a variant
of LRU caching,
which is actually
also used in
the NDN-DPDK
forwarder, I believe.
And you can see here that
the plots are in
terms of throughput,
in terms of
delay, in terms
of cache hit ratio.
And in each case,
actually the green,
which is the VIP
performance, was the best.
And in many cases
the delay was
decreased quite
substantially and
throughput increased
and cache hit
ratios increased.
So this is just
with fixed routing,
and then we also tested it
with a multipath topology.
Here, the difference
is that you can do
joint caching and routing
at the same time.
So you're
dynamically choosing
the route taken by
the request as well as
the caching policy.
And here, actually, again,
VIP caching gave the
best performance
in terms throughput,
delay, and cache
hit ratio.
So this is robust
performance
across a number of
different topologies.
And the main theme
here is that because
NDN has in network caching
built into the
architecture,
we can really
exploit that to use
an optimized joint
caching forwarding
strategy
to get great performance.
And since this is
a data distribution
network,
caching really plays
a huge role here.
In LHC, for instance,
caching is a very
significant component
of the architecture.
And here all we've done
is actually to
combine that with
the fast NDN-DPDK
forwarder to essentially
extract the best
performance
we can extract from
this combined system.
Now, we have also
actually integrated
that with
a CMS stack through
the XRootD plugin,
which was developed
by Caltech.
Now, what is XRootD? It is
a software
framework used for
file management at CERN,
which is where the
experiments are conducted.
It enables
developers in LHC
and CMS to implement
various types of plugins,
file systems,
caching security.
It's written in C++.
And the OSS plugin is
a C++ dynamic library.
These are details of
file operations and it
interfaces with the
Ceph file system.
So what we've done is,
this is Caltech group,
has embedded what
is called an
NDNc consumer into
the XRootD plugin,
developed by
Catalin Lordache,
one of our team members.
It translates each
file system which is
submitted in the CMS
system into NDN name.
So for instance, this
would be the NDN name
for open and fstat
and for read,
and then sends
the interests
over the NDN network.
In other words, you can
submit a request
for a file
or a certain file
operations in
XRootD would be translated
into an NDN name.
And then from there go on
into an NDN network.
So then it receives
data packs,
validates them,
it replies to
the XRootD worker threads.
So now at the present time
when we did this
integration,
the throughput
that we get,
so we implement
these things in
darker containers.
Without going into
all of the details,
the performance
that we get with
the XRootD Plugin
is substantially
less than with the
pure NDN system.
Right now we're getting
about six gigabits
per second peak.
Now why is that?
Because if you
do it directly
in NDN actually with
the NDNc file
transfer client
is using two threads,
one for encoding
interests and the
other for reading
and decoding data.
The two threads operate
asynchronously and
do not communicate.
This approach
eliminates overhead
and benefits from
parallelization,
which leads to
improve throughput.
However, in the
XRootD OSS Plugin,
the configuration
that CMS only
allows for
synchronous requests.
And so each worker thread
will read a
certain amount of
data and then wait
for the response
before continue.
This really limits
throughputs.
So this is one of
the factors limiting
throughput.
So we're still working
on this integration,
but we expect to
improve the
performance there.
But right now there
is this bottleneck
that's some limiting
throughput.
I have limited time,
so I will say
that in terms
of a little bit about
FPGA acceleration
performance,
basically the FPGA
performance is being used
to accelerate the
SipHash function,
which is used to
handle variable
length names
in the NDN forwarder.
And so far we've gotten
about two times
acceleration
in terms of decreasing
the delay in terms of
doing the hashing.
But we expect to improve
that performance.
And that's still being
worked on by
the UCLA group.
In terms of the
genomics application
I'll just say
briefly that what
has been done here
is to essentially
connect NDN
with a Kubernetes
infrastructure.
Basically, there's the
Tennessee Tech group
has created an
infrastructure to
transparently
place data and
computation in a network.
And one can name
computations
and map them into the
Kubernetes namespaces.
And so basically
I think what
has happened is they've
worked on this
translation of
NDN names onto the
Kubernetes names.
So there's an ability to
name both data
and compute,
and allowing the
workflows to treat
the network as a
distributed compute device.
I think there's a lot
of potential here actually
to connect NDN
with Kubernetes.
I think this is a
very nice first step
that we've taken,
but in the genomics
application context.
But there's a
lot more work
that has been done here.
And due to limited time,
I won't go into
too much of that.
Now through
this process in
the CND project and
the NDNs project,
we actually
learned a lot of
valuable lessons
which might be
useful for other groups.
And let me talk
about that briefly.
So there are
various challenges
in mapping application
names to NDN names.
So it turns out that
the naming structure
various applications
do not really
correspond to
the underlying
hierarchical structure of
the data organization
sometimes.
So this is true in
your CMS case where we
had to do
additional mappings
to associate data objects
used by workflows
with data units directly
used in network requests.
So the naming scheme of
the application does not
really correspond to
the structure of the
files necessarily.
So you have to do
additional mapping.
That's one of the
lessons we learned.
The other is,
we'll might want
a decoupled control-plane
information from
the forwarding threads
because the
transmission in
parsing of control
packets may
interrupt
the operation of the
forwarding threads,
increasing the
queueing delay
of interest and
data packets.
And so what we did
was to allocate
dedicated threads
to generate
and parse control
information.
That's another potentially
very valuable lesson.
One of the things we
encountered is
the impact of
middle boxes on NDN
based protocols.
So when we were running
these things over the
wide area network,
what happened was that
a lot of the NDN packets
got corrupted by
middle boxes.
So some of the
networks switches
misidentified
the EtherType of
NDN packets with
a bare VLAN tag,
and so they inserted
extra tag protocol
identified
before the NDN EtherType,
resulting in
the NDN frame,
in the Ethernet
frame no longer
being a valid NDN packet.
So then subsequently all
of these things
started being dropped.
This was a big mystery
to us that we
eventually solved.
And we had to
actually go and
check every switch to
see whether this
was being done.
In the end, we used VXLAN,
Virtual Extensible LANs,
encapsulation protocol
to tunnel NDN packets over
UDP/IP to avoid
this problem,
but this led to some
reduction in throughput.
So this is definitely
a problem encountered.
And then there's also
a lot of system-dependent
configuration tuning.
That is just when you
actually operate
this over a wide
area network.
So we used Docker
containers to package
the forwarder,
consumer producer
applications.
However, you still
have to spend a lot
of manual effort to
configure drivers,
ensuring proper
storage, integrating
software stacks
into workflows with
diverse server equipment,
OSS, networking
configuration.
So this is definitely
a challenge.
But what we've shown with
this project is
that it is possible
to put together what
is available in terms
of the NDN technology,
in terms of the forwarding
and caching and so forth,
and put it over an actual
wide-area network,
running a very
pretty high speeds
and using directly or to
control using VLANS and
get pretty reasonable
performance.
This is the N-DISE team
with many members and
I like to thank them all.
And it's been
a great effort
over a number of years.
And special thanks to our
partners from ESnet,
CENIC, StarLight,
Internet2, RNP.
So a lot of partners
have helped
us to make all of
this possible.
This is really a
quite integration
and deployment job.
Though, as I said,
these results are
presented in detail in
our proceedings of
ICN 2022 paper,
and there's also a NRE,
network research
exhibition document
that you could
find from SC22.
So let me skip
the rest of this
in the interest of time.
Thank you very much.
>> Let's thank the
speaker. Thank you.
[APPLAUSE] So I'll start
see if any questions
in the room?
Any questions online?
>> Can you guys hear me?
>> Yes.
>> I would agree with
your observation and
finding on the lack of
standardization
causes problems with
general purpose networking
equipment that you
observe that we
did in some of
our experimentation
as well.
>> Thank you.
>> There's one
question online.
I had the same question
is from [inaudible].
I'm wondering about
the bottleneck
for your testing.
I think you got up to
60 something
gigabit per second.
So the question
is, what do you
see the next bottleneck
that needs to
be addressed to achieve
100 gigabit per second?
>> Yeah. So we
can go into this.
I think we were
running a lot of
threads simultaneously,
a lot of consumers, a lot
of threads simultaneously.
At some point,
the throughput
started to get
diminishing returns.
And I think that the
way that we're going
to try to deal
with this is to try
to look at these pipelines
that we're using,
which were fixed pipelines
of certain number
of packets.
We're not sure
whether those are
necessarily tuned
optimally and
there's probably some
additional gains we
could gain from that.
But we have to know
to a large extent.
I think we will get 200
gigabits per second.
It's a matter of
tuning the number
of threads,
number of consumers,
and the pipeline,
the window that we use,
which is a fixed
window right now,
and possibly if we use
adjustable window,
we could possibly get
a better throughput.
That's another
possibility.
So we're still working on
the actually
the congestion
control aspect of this.
So there are a couple of
directions we could push
to try to improve
the performance.
But I think it's
within reach actually
on the local testbed,
we're already getting
90 gigabits per
second so it's really over
the wide area
network that we're
having some gap
and this is actually
a Wide Area Network,
things are much
less controlled.
>> Thank you.
There's a follow-on
online that asks
if there are
any performance
optimizations that
are possible on
the producer side.
>> Yeah, so the
producer side,
well one of the
things we do is
we put the datasets
that we're
fetching in DRAM at
the producer side.
But possibly there are
other optimizations
that could be done.
I'm not sure exactly
what they are
referring to.
I'll be interested in
learning about that.
>> Thank you.
>> I have one
more question
regarding your
Kubernetes integration.
When you were
looking at that,
was it more
efficient to look at
the storage interfaces
like the CSI or PVC,
the persistent
volume claim,
more than networking
site interfaces
when you started bringing
this into India?
>> Good question.
[inaudible].
Are you around to answer
this because it's
really seismic project?
>> So we look at both.
We looked at PVC for
the storage and also
the network interface.
I think the
network interface
was more straightforward.
Interfacing with PVC
had its own challenges.
But we did both.
>> You actually
use both. We had
a similar
experience looking
at PVC. Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Let's thank the
speaker one more time.
Thank you.
[APPLAUSE].
Our next talk is
edge information
management demand is only
growing by Jeff White
from Dell Technologies.
Jeff is the CTO for
Edge at Dell Technologies.
He's focuses on Edge
Software Defined
Platform technology,
Edge Native
infrastructure,
Edge execution
environments,
data management,
applied AI, networking.
He has developed
intellectual
property filings and
Edge application
infrastructure scheduling,
control algorithm design,
edge data management AI
IML drift mitigation
, and emerging networking.
Jeff has also held
senior roles at
early stage artificial
intelligence machine
reasoning-based
robotic process
automation technology
provider and the CTO
of health Fanta group,
a stratospheric
wireless communications
platform.
Also held senior positions
at Hewlett Packard
Enterprise Erickson,
Alcatel-Lucent, where
you let technology
initiatives,
solution development,
business development,
service delivery.
Prior Jeff worked at
Singular Wireless and
BellSouth and technology
and operations roles.
>> Thank you. I
appreciate it.
Can everybody
see my screen?
>> Yes.
>> We can see it.
>> Great, It's
great to be here.
So I'm going t go through
some review of edge
and what edge is
because it's such
an emerging area
that it's helpful
to understand some of
the vernacular
and then I'll
get to the information
management piece.
Real quick time check.
Here at Dell, we'd been
doing research and I
had a long list
of things we're
interested in and
it's not by choice,
the edge touches
everything,
data management,
management of AI,
workloads, runtimes,
execution environments,
orchestration,
and the list is really
long because Edge
it's a new deployment
pattern similar
to Cloud or
telecommunications.
So it touches quite
a few things,
but not all equally.
So three real genesis to
the modern edge framework
that's appearing.
So first of all, telecom,
telecommunications
carriers
have been building edges,
really complex edges since
the late '90s but it
started far before that
so really active
electronics
being embedded deep into
their networks really
started with the advent of
broadband communications
and the advent
of cable modems and DSL.
But it's progressed
far beyond there
with wireless
networks now and
eNodeB and a lot of
the capabilities
that we looked at in
June shells discussion.
So what we've learned
from telecommunication and
incorporating here is
wide area service
delivery, very important.
And then from
the IoT world
that started emerging
really mid last
decade, 2012-2015.
It's all about
device management.
So how can I interface
the cyber and
physical worlds?
You perform
automation and do
a lot of very
interesting things.
So everything from
cameras and multimedia
for a host of
applications of
computer vision beyond,
as well as how
do I actuate and
control capabilities
are remote
from a data center or
from my operation.
So we learned a lot
there about device
management.
And then of course
cloud, which
emerged the decade
before that,
in the 2000s timeframe.
What we've really
learned about that
is utility, consumption,
and how do you
manage resources
elastically and
those are all
combining to
create this edge,
this world of edge.
If you see up in the
left-hand corner,
these are a lot
of the use cases
we're seeing and they
are all interrelated.
So the amount of
data intensity to
manage analytics-based
workloads or
computer vision-based
workloads is
a tremendous amount of
data being generated.
And it's being generated
from a host of
devices that are
very distributed.
Even if you go to
a single site,
to a factory or
a military base,
or a port or an airport,
even over that wide
area that could be
square kilometers or
mini square kilometers,
you've got
devices that are
producing immense
amount of data and they
need to be able to
gain insights very
quickly and then also you
need to be able to
control capabilities with
very fine scale
and very fast.
So this is where
the latency
requirement comes in.
Even in retail
stores today,
their predominant
use cases around
loss prevention so as
you're scanning things
out at a self-checkout,
they've got to be able to
stop the process
if there's
a problem before you
scan the next item
and you may think,
that happens in
terms of seconds,
but you've got
to think about
what has to happen there.
You have to capture video,
you have to
scale the video,
you have to perform
a inference function
and identify
the object and
match it against
a database,
make sure it's a match.
And then if
there's a problem,
send a command
back to the point
of sale to stop the
checkout process.
And you've got to do it
before someone picks up
another item and scans
it. Really hard to do.
So in any event, also,
data security
is a big issue
because all of these
use cases I just talked
about private
tremendous amount of
data that you
want to ensure
security and
governance around
independent operations is
a big issue across almost
every one of
these use cases
that they cannot count on
the reliability of
a network or cloud
to be able to continue
these workloads
have to run,
vary continuously
or there's
major business impact
if they break now.
And then lastly,
mobility management.
And this is something that
we're working on
understanding.
But if you go to a modern
factory these days,
the workloads are
moving around.
Virtually all the material
handling now is
being done by
robots whether they're
operating forklifts,
where they're
moving material
from building
to buildings,
or they're a robot
that's running on
a track and the operations
people are
strapping gateways
to the back of these
robots and they're
communicating with Wi-Fi
and they're
loading them with
tasks via some local
area networks.
It's just amazing
to see this,
but we're also going to
be running workloads in
vehicles that are going
to require Edge support.
We're certainly going
to be running them
in soft form and
robotic process
automation in
a variety of
different frameworks.
So mobility management
becomes really important.
Every one of these use
cases interacts and it
creates quite a worthy
technical problem.
So we have to manage
network constraints,
we have to manage
data mobility,
computer vision is
a huge workload.
A lot of people
see Edge is
an enabler of
multi-cloud so that
they can use Edge is
a natural glue between
clouds and they can
put different workload
backends into
different clouds.
These are operational
workloads.
They're not, IT,
there's some IT,
but it's predominantly
operational
functions that
we're running.
Of course, since
it's a large
distributed systems
scale becomes an issue,
cost becomes an issue and
quite a few
technical challenges
begin to appear as you
start running this.
There aren't a lot of
distributed systems
in the world today.
People say, clouds
distributed,
well now cloud are
giant data centers
that you use
the Internet or
direct connection
to access.
Really, I can
only think of
two very large-scale
distributed systems
that operate
one or telecommunications
networks.
And they operate
because they have
highly standardized
protocols and interfaces
around those that
allow them to
interwork on a
global basis
and the other are
financial exchanges.
And they've done
pretty much
the same thing with APIs,
that when they're handling
settlements and all
the background,
those are very
distributed systems,
globally distributed
and they
have to inter-operate
and of course
they have to deal
with financial
regulation and
the surety of handling
people's money.
So if you think about
edge topology in
taxonomy around this,
we see the functional edge
and this is vehicles,
robots, metaverse
gateways,
etc, whatever you want.
But very close, tens
of square meters
of surface area,
tens of millions
of locations,
probably ultimately
hundreds of them.
But I like to be
conservative and
extremely low latency.
Everything has
to happen in
less than two milliseconds
in many use cases,
if you look at,
for instance,
environmental
simulation or the
so-called named by
Mark Zuckerberg metaverse,
if you look at
those, I mean,
you're talking sub 100
microseconds and
heavy requirements in
the area of jitter.
And then of course in
robotic control,
autonomous driving,
the same thing if you've
got a vehicle that's
operating at 70 miles
per hour it has
to make decisions
in microseconds on
what to do as a
scenario develops.
So very low latency,
a very much
single use case.
So the computation
that's placed in these,
if you've got a
system that's
operating a vehicle
or a forklift,
that's all it's
going to do.
It will not be handling
the inventory that
the forklift is carrying
or some other use case,
it's going to
be targeted at
that very narrow set of
use cases for that
physical device.
Then we look at
the far edge,
so still pretty tight
latency, say 5-10
milliseconds.
But now you start to look
at square kilometers
of coverage.
Large retail stores,
factories, ports,
utility locations
for power generation
or upstream oil
exploration, etc mining.
Now you've got
square kilometers to
cover and you have
general purpose compute.
There will be a lot
of that deployed as well,
and in fact, in
the Enterprise Edge
as we call it,
across manufacturing,
retail, energy,
health care,
this is already
appearing in quite
a few areas.
In fact, I think
Dell has publicly
announced we have
$6 billion worth
of business
going into the far in
the near edge today
with products that
were designed a while
back and now are really
useful for Edge.
Then we have the near
Edge and think of this
as a small form factor
datacenter and
then core cloud,
everybody knows
what those are,
so no need to
talk about them.
One thing that's
notable here is
just like telecommunications
networks,
Edges will be nested.
So functional Edges will
tie to far Edges for
support and then far Edges
will home to near Edges
for additional support,
caching of data, other
types of functions.
So we expect to
see these to be
architected in a way that
they have a
progressive set of
capabilities that one Edge
can rely on another,
just like telecom
networks do today.
So Dell Technologies,
what are we doing?
So there's two
things on the side.
So we're building a lot
of hardware platforms
that are specific
for Edge and
we've watched those are
called Edge
Native portfolio.
And then we're
working with
software ISVs to enable
their capabilities
on our platforms
and enable them to
operate in the Edge.
But the two that are
really important,
that are information
management
related are the two
here in the middle.
So first of all,
private 5G and OpenRan,
I talked about
mobility management
marks the capabilities
of how to tie that.
We really need to
have solutions
there for supporting 5G.
So we have an
entire division
called the
telecom solutions
unit and they're building
private 5G and open
ray and capabilities.
But the relation to Edge
is they provide
the ability to do
Wide Area service delivery
of Edge hosted
capabilities.
Think of the Edge as
a service execution
environment
where applications
and data are hosted.
You can think of
the pirate 5G and
the telecommunications
network as
a way to distribute
that capability.
And then we're building
what we call a software
defined Edge or a
software operating
platform.
So you can think
of this as
a Edge cloud that can
manage other Clouds and
perform capabilities as
a software platform
and we'll talk a
little bit about that and
then we'll talk about
information management
relation to that.
So this is a diagram,
some of this exists today.
We are going to
launch very shortly
our Edge software platform
around the orchestration
exists today,
our ability to
do application
management exists today,
our ability to do
security in hardware,
onboarding and manage
execution environments
exist today.
Things we're looking at in
the future, information
management,
which will be the
last slide and I
specifically say
information management,
because we need
to start thinking
about data and not as bits
and bytes is the
quantification of
information but
we've got to start
thinking about
it semantically.
What is this
objects intend?
Why is it being generated,
where is it destined for,
what are the
sensitivities about
handling and managing this
as an object or a file.
We need to start
thinking about
the data structures and
what information they're
meant to convey.
Think of information
theory and Shannon bits,
or Hartley gnats that
really starts to become
important to us in
the future and I'll
explain why in
the next slide.
We're also
looking at how we
manage what we
call external
services or
external service
fabrics, which are clouds.
It said CMAC so we can
talk to white
area deliveries,
I was talking in
telecommunications
networks and then how
do we create utilities
to manage devices.
So there's a lot
that's going in,
it's a major
initiative for
Dell and we're
learning a lot.
We're learning
how to build
a distributed
system that can
host and manage
the applications,
which is a very
interesting area
and quite as I
said before,
a lot of technical
challenges in terms
of resource management
allocation,
in terms of information
management,
in terms of how
do we maintain
state on something that's
impossible to
maintain state.
So how do we
build processes
and orchestration
capabilities that
will ensure that even
if the system we
don't know the state,
we can still eventually
reach an eventually
consistent state.
So a lot of really
interesting and
challenging problems
to solve there.
But let's talk about
information management,
why we're here.
So one of the things,
our journey in Edge
started back in
2017 and it started
working with the
automotive industry.
And we believed
at the time,
and I think that
our belief has
been born out
that ultimately
the automotive or
vehicular industry
is going to be a superset
of the challenges.
The only one that's
close to it is
public sector and
military applications,
they even have a
larger challenge
because they have
an adversarial
issue to deal with,
as well as they
don't operate
on road systems very much,
but very specialized in
terms of its application
into enterprises.
So automotive is
the next best thing
because they're
going to be managing
massive amounts of data.
They have to manage
extensive numbers
of AI workloads.
This is a year,
year-and-a-half old,
so I'm sure it's
changed now,
but Tesla had
published that they
have over 60
models running in
a Tesla today for
really what's Layer
2 plus autonomy
in the vehicle.
So it's really just
assisted driving,
although it's so good,
it can give you the
impression that
it's actually
really driving
your vehicle
when it is not.
So, even that requires
around 60 different models
and different
types of models.
It's got to run NLP,
it's got to run
capabilities
for the perception,
prediction, planning,
and control pipeline.
So lots of CNNs,
it has to run
different capabilities
in terms of control.
It has to run
autoencoders,
the list goes on
and on and on.
It touches a
wide variety of
different neural networks
and machine learning
technologies.
So in any event, we
started doing
research there,
we quickly concluded
that there was
going to need to be a
computational Edge that
will manage the
communications
environment and
manage the data associated
with all those AI.
One of the capabilities
that came to mind was
NDN because it's a
distributed world.
So on the production side,
we needed to identify
data and that's
beyond NDN.
We needed to characterize
semantically what
the data was
doing and we've done a
lot of work there with
various different
approaches and
come up with some
really good ideas.
But then we needed
to advertise
what that data was
and expose it in
a way that it
can be accessed.
Once that
advertisement is done,
as a service we can
apply capabilities
like encryption or
anonymization or
other functions
that need to be
done on the data,
given our government's
policy around
the framework.
Of course, we
needed to make sure
we knew where this
data was coming from,
so we needed strong
provenance and we needed
security to make sure
that it's not been
tampered with.
Some of the
automotive folks,
they have regulatory
requirements
that they have to keep
data for 15 years.
And so it's important
to make sure that it's
secure and that it's
not been tampered with.
And then something I
call push movement.
And what that
is, is we needed
to find a policy
around data movement.
If the data is too
large to move,
either the networking
environment
can't effectively
move the data.
It would take too long
and it would
lose its value
by the time we
got it moved
or it'd be too expensive,
can we apply a
compression service
on it in a
different degrees,
higher degrees of
compression in maybe apply
a lossless type
of compression
versus a lossy type
of compression?
So these are
all the things
we thought about
that needed to be
done on the data
production side
and NDN fit the
bill very well.
Highly scalable design for
internet replacement of IP
and Pub Sub based
subscription
so that we could
create and maintain
consistency,
or we could choose
not to maintain
consistency and go
with availability.
I'm sure this audience
is familiar with
the CAP theorem from
Eric Brewer and Google.
So you can have
one or the other,
you can't have both.
And that's now a theorem.
So I believe it, there's
ways to minimize it,
but certain use
cases consistency,
making sure that I have
the absolute latest,
greatest data that has
the latest
modifications by
the producing workload
is very important.
Other use cases that's
not so important,
so what's important
is having
the data available now.
I need to make a decision.
I don't really care if
it's the latest stuff,
but I need to have it
highly available and I
needed a very
short time frame.
One of the things
we discovered was
that certain use
cases lean one way,
certain use cases
lean the other.
And we need a system that
can distinguish
between the two
and we think that
NDN presented
some opportunities in
that area to do that.
Moving over to the
consumption side,
again, how do I get
access to the data?
NDN present some
real capabilities in
terms of encoding
semantic location.
So data localization,
so we know where
the data is
at and that becomes
very important in Edge.
Because today,
enterprise
applications and
even non enterprise
applications,
they work on two
fundamental assumptions.
The date is local or
the data is reachable,
and we believe as
Edges mature and
some of these
emerging use cases
appear like multiverse,
like autonomous systems,
and they really start
to be widely used,
those two assumptions
are no longer valid.
The data could be remote,
and it could be of size or
sensitivity where it
cannot be easily moved.
So we needed to bring in
a platform understanding
of the data,
and that becomes very
important on the
consumption side.
We believe there are
other solutions on
the data production
side that
could work and be
implemented on the
data consumption side
NDN even is more
compelling because
we can take
that policy and
we can make
decisions based
on network hops,
the size of the data, etc.
How do we give
that application
access to the data?
Do we provision it as
a symbolic link or do
we do a network coded
file and only cash
a component or
part of that data locally,
and then we can
bring it in
with network coding for
multiple different
directions
when the data is excess.
So that really covers
the first three data,
access, localization
and acquisition.
But redirection, Pub
Sub for subscription.
How do we ensure that
the data has integrity,
that it's signed
and authentic?
That all goes into
the pole movement of
data consumption.
So a couple of things,
you see my little
Kubernetes
in the middle there
and my little double
year orchestrator
and my little
policy document
with all the little
check marks on it,
might be hard to
see for those of
you in the room.
But how can I
interface this capability
to an orchestrator?
So if I'm making
any decisions or where
do I place applications,
and in the Edge,
that's a very
complex equation.
You've got to make
sure that you can
allocate sufficient
resources for it to run.
You've got to
make sure that
the security
level is right.
You've got to make
sure a lot of
things that
aren't quite as
important to do in Cloud
because of the
nature of Clouds,
the highly elastic,
large resource pools.
Clouds can do things after
applications
are deployed to
optimize their execution.
In Edge, you've
got a pre optimize
and predict a lot
harder problem.
So one of those issues
is, where's the data at?
So the orchestrator
can make
a good decision on, okay,
I can fit it here,
but my data may
not be available.
It may be over here. Can I
access that data remotely?
Is the dataset small
enough and do I
have enough networking
capability,
can I do that?
So that's the whole
placement paradigm.
How do I interface
this to something like
a Kubernetes
orchestrator or
other orchestration
frameworks we're using
Kubernetes as well as
a building our
own orchestrator.
How do I handle this
placement decision?
Again, content management.
How do I make sure that
the data is governed
properly and then I'm
not violating any policy
or governmental rule.
And again, I've
already talked about
availability, consistency,
and persistency.
So a lot of this
data, in fact,
98% of the data
generated in
an autonomous vehicle is
never going to leave
the autonomous vehicle.
But the 2% that is,
is very important to
get that data off
the vehicle into its
intended application.
So how do we persist
capabilities?
How do we make sure
that that data that
is very important
to get to
an application is
protected and has
the appropriate
governance around it
and geared in the
right way that
it can only be accessed
by that application.
Again, NDN can be
part of the answer.
So the reason I say
this is growing is
because the Edge is
exploding a bit,
we're very excited
about our platform.
It's already a large
business for Dell.
And we think it'll be
a lot larger business,
and Dell's not alone in
pursuing this space
it has becoming one
of the hottest topics
really an IT/telecom
right now.
So it's a very
interesting space
and this is going
to be one of
the top three
problems to solve is
this information
management
in data
mobility/management.
So thanks for your time.
I don't know how
I'm doing on time.
I think I'm
pretty close, but
any questions for me?
>> Let's thank the speaker
[APPLAUSE] So
we'll start with,
are there any
questions in the room?
Any any questions online?
There's a question
in the room.
>> I'd be curious if
internal to Dell,
NDN is seen as a
differentiator.
Are you using
it to enhance
the competitive
position or is
it purely a research
topic at this stage?
>> It's purely
research topic.
We actually built
some capabilities,
collaborated with low fee
and the guys at NIST
on using their high
performance folder
when we built a research
prototype around it.
This data
management problem,
you need to understand
problems before you
can solve them,
and it's still
coming into focus.
So I don't think anyone
has solved it as of yet.
Most data services
are focused
on how to enable
application pipelines
around like email,
for instance, or how
to deliver
storage services.
Clouds are very good
at that. They've got
a broad set of
capabilities.
So this problem really
hasn't been tackled yet.
So we're in the
process of trying to
decide what's the best
vehicle to tackle it.
We learned a lot from
our research prototype.
And I think I
had some points
and raised some commentary
in the standardization
discussion.
I think for NDN to
really move into the
commercial realm,
some of it has to
be standardized
and adopted by
communities that are
going to ensure that
the standardization
has a long lifetime.
And I hope to see
that because I think
NDN has solved a lot
of the problems,
the state vector sync,
and other
capabilities that
we could leverage
in the Edge.
One of the
challenges of Edge
is that we can't consume
all the hardware
with our platform.
So we have to have very
efficient execution
on the software side.
And I think NDN
can lend itself to
that because it's built
on high performance.
And with Ross coming
along and other things,
there's a lot
of capability.
So still a research
prototype.
We haven't made a
decision how to
commercialize the
capability at all.
But as we do, we'll
certainly consider NDN,
and depending
on the maturity
of the ecosystem,
it could definitely
be a choice for us.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah, I wanted
to comment because
those two comments
you made in
the standardization
panel resonated with me,
that you need standards
of transport level of
the networking and also
at the application API.
And it seems that
the Pub/Sub API is
meeting a lot of needs and
that's our findings too.
>> Yeah, and we found that
in our prototyping
exercise,
what Dr. Yi shared
earlier in this thing.
We've got to get
standardization.
I can remember,
and we don't have time for
me to tell war stories,
but we implemented layer
2 tunneling protocol for
broadband access
in the late '90s,
2000s timeframes.
And it wasn't quite
standardized even
though there was
an IETF paper out
on it in the RFC.
And I paid the price
for deploying
a non-standard
capability in a network.
So you've really
got to have
some degree of
interoperability
so when things don't work,
you can go back to
the standards
document and you can
figure out the
most efficient,
most compliant way
to correct it.
And that's really
important.
And then on the
application side,
the platforms can do
a lot of mediation.
So our goal was
the applications be
unaware of
what's going on.
Our goal is to create
the environment that
applications think
they have in Cloud or
in a datacenter
in the Edge.
So they don't know there's
an underlying NDN
substrate that's
moving data around and
performing services
on the data.
So we can create a
mediation layer,
but ultimately with
the capabilities
NDN brings to the table,
you want to be able to
expose it directly to
the application so they
can leverage it directly.
And that's in some
ways a harder problem
than telecommunications
network because
you've got to get
adoption there.
It's not a standardized
capability.
It's a way of
doing business,
and that's why
Kubernetes did it and
it's been fantastically
successful.
And you can run
Kubernetes-based
applications.
As long as it's
in a container,
you can run them
on the Cloud,
you can run them locally.
It's across a variety of
different distributions
and they almost
always work.
It's absolutely
amazing what
Google did there.
And then the Cloud
native community
afterward.
>> Thank you, Jeff.
Interesting discussion.
I think we tried
to take it
offline 45 minutes over.
So I appreciate your time.
Thank you, Jeff.
Let's thank them
one more time.
[APPLAUSE]
>> You're welcome.
>> Then our final talk
is SPAN-AI
federated UCDN POC.
I don't know if I'm
saying that right.
First commercial ICN
network at scale
by Rhett Sampson
from GT Systems.
Rhett is the founder
and CTO of GT Systems.
He's been designing,
building,
and selling networks
globally for industry,
government, defense and
telcos for four decades.
Jamie, the coauthor,
is GT Systems Head of R&D,
was a senior researcher
at Bell Labs in
network optimization
for a decade,
where he pioneered
the concept
of software-defined
virtual CDN.
In his PhD work,
he invented
physics-inspired graph
Edge Bayes Cloud network
flow models to do that.
Rhett and Jamie are the
driving force behind
SPAN-AI and coauthors of
several of its patents.
GT Systems is building
the world's first
commercial intelligent
information
centric network at scale,
is on their
SPAN-AI protocol
and operating system.
>> Thanks very much.
Can you hear me?
>> Yes.
>> Great. All right.
We're very
conscious that we
stand between you and
your travel arrangements
to get home,
so we'll try and
move through this
pretty quickly.
Jeff, I don't know whether
you saw me nodding
my head off during
your presentation,
but thank you for just
perfectly elucidating
our business case
applications
for what we're doing.
And you didn't really
touch on it so much.
Yeah, you're going to love
this presentation,
my friend.
What we think is,
and where we
started in all of
this was video
distribution.
So 80% of the internet,
it's a massive problem and
it's what's broken
the Internet.
So let's just get into it
and you'll see what
we're talking about.
So it's a protocol and
an operating system.
And the key piece
is this concept we
have of a federated
network of
intelligent networks.
We all know the Internet
is a network of networks,
but to put it
bluntly there, it's
just done as a rock.
And so we are
pioneering the use
of AI or machine
learning in information
centric networking.
That's our stretch goal
down at the bottom.
[LAUGHTER] We figured
once we've got that,
we might try on
something harder.
What we have,
and I'm going
to move my little
thing here so I
can actually read it
to the other side,
just bear with me.
So it's fully distributed,
content-based within
network routing
and caching
with the AI inside
the network at the
routing level.
And everyone's on
the same network.
You'll see a picture
later at the end
that still blows
my mind away.
That scales and
meets next-gen QoS.
Like I said,
pioneering the use of
AI and Information
center networking.
I'll let Jamie talk about
the results we got.
We modeled this
on state of
the art models that Jamie
developed and that's the
result as you
can see there.
Jamie, do you want to have
a quick talk about this?
>> Yeah. Thank
you, Rhett. Yeah,
just to comment on
these modelling
exercise that
we did with GT Systems is
based on Cloud network
flow models that were
developed at Bell Labs
during my time there.
And those models
were developed
with the vision
at that time
that the application
was getting
disaggregated and out
of the datacenters.
So as well as many
of you guys have
already encountered in
these NDN sessions.
In the end, that's
what's happening.
The application is getting
out of the datacenter,
that is getting
desegregated,
the composable
applications and
they run in the network.
Essentially we say that
the network becomes
the compute platform.
So that edge in
the premium real state
that telco operators own.
But in essence, any
resource that you can
leverage to run
applications and host data.
Also, business logic
and data get
disaggregated.
They live in the network.
They move in the network
is driven by
efficiency, ideally.
So with these models,
what we do is we try
to look at what's
the optimal
configuration when we
model an infrastructure
that has compute,
storage and
networking resources
at different levels
from the device,
to the Edge, to
the core, and
that continuum.
And then we model
applications as
flexible service
graphs composed
of multiple functions,
live data sources,
static data sources and
functions that
are, in the end,
processing both live and
static data sources
into consumable
experiences.
So when you describe
well your set of
applications and
the infrastructure,
you optimize their
configuration
and you understand when it
is actually efficient to
move those applications
to the Edge.
When things start
moving to the Edge,
what functions they are
moving to the Edge?
What contents start
Then we see how as
you increase
the data rate,
the quality of the video.
Especially with low
latency applications,
you start seeing
more and more
benefit of moving
to the Edge.
And that's only the
benefits of distribution.
Then we add the
benefits of
actually changing
the protocol.
So when things
leaving the network,
when you have
multiple functions
and data that is moving,
and ideally you want
it to move and live
in the network,
you have a lot of space
for optimization.
What people don't
realize is that,
you can do a lot
with optimization
on a connection-oriented
architecture.
But if you remove that
constraint and you
optimize now on
a connection-less
architecture,
the benefits of
optimization are
even greater.
So you have more
granularity
for optimizing
the placement of
these functions and data
and you get even
more benefits.
So that's the
exercise we did.
Try to understand in
different stages,
what are the benefits of
using available
resources in the network
and change in also the
protocol that we use
to find content and
functions in the network.
>> Thanks,
Jamie. And I was
pretty happy camper when
those results came back.
We were hoping for
a good result,
but we were blown
away by it.
And really the good news
now is we're going
to build it.
So that's even better
news. Why is mine.
That'll work. There
are the components.
We've got the
content-based protocol
and operating system,
which is span.
The span agents or the
local autonomous
containerized agents.
They're locally
optimizing.
SPAN-AI is doing
that local
optimization but
also global optimization.
And then we use API in
the old-school sense,
like you, Jeff you've
been around for awhile.
This is basically so that
the intelligent
networks can
talk to each other.
This is a bit
of a new thing.
It's an AI API,
which will also
developing.
There's only really
three of them.
There's this,
the running API
at the local level,
the operational API
and then the
global routing
and optimizing AI.
So we federate
these networks
so they're built inside
the telco networks
at the edge,
but also on the
datacenters,
which you'll see
in a minute.
Spanish DKA, which we're
going to give to the
likes of Disney and
paramount to
enable the client
in their applications
to talk to the network,
and then when you
federate all this,
it becomes
a universal distribution
that works.
This is the roadmap
we're doing proof of
concepts were originally
in Australia.
They started with
laser-like communications,
global satellite,
laser background network
about a year ago.
It's now expanded wearing
a deep conversations
with Canada
about them
participating in this.
They've very advanced in
their network into things
that they're doing,
and that will be signing
within Tilt to
Fino peoples,
which is X86 servers,
innocuous Linux
servers, routers,
and video Bloomfield
trade APUs.
These are our
starting platforms,
but eventually we're
going to be on
everything and every
box in the network.
We understand, as
everybody has said,
Jeff, we all know
this isn't finished.
There's some areas of
works to required.
We're already been
talking to everybody.
They all know me by now.
We're starting
to circulate
a discussion paper
around building,
if you are like
a cooperative
research group,
to plug the gaps
and then extend
the research.
By all means,
talk to me if
you're interested.
I could say attraction
with Bokeh Canada.
They have a lot of very
interesting friends,
and we're getting
incredible engagement
from the datacenters,
particularly,
we've had
conversations with
unit tests and Equinix,
Bell Canada, as everyone
probably may or
may not know,
outsource their cord
data centers to
Equinix, or they've got
a very close
relationship there,
and then a year ago
we met Laser-Like
Communications,
who are launching
medium-earth orbit
global laser satellites
with a big ground network,
and they've chosen us
as the next-gen protocol.
The guys who were
at ACM, ICANN,
Asoka, will know
this picture.
I won't go into
detail on it.
I assume the slides will
be available to everybody.
But if you look at
that picture
in the middle,
that's the one we
put up at a soccer,
but it's actually changed.
And it's changed
to this and
I still get
goosebumps when
I say that because when
99.9% sure that
top one is true,
what we're gonna do
is the way things
have gone,
the centralization
with the hyperscalers,
everyone is joining up
these datacenters on
massive bridged lands
using the excellent
and it's incredibly
complex and
incredibly
inefficient so much
so that it requires
really complex orchester
to configure now
to the extent that
they now need YAML
driven model AI to
do it and it's just
so inefficient.
We'd gone back to
the 1980s, I'm old,
but I remember bridged
Ethernet networks
with multiplexers.
That's really
what we're doing.
It's just crazy because
it's okay if you can
figure stuff upfront,
but if you decide, hey,
I want to access
to something
that I didn't know
about and you
have to go all the
way up through
the VX lands and add
into IP to find where
it is and you
come back and it
could be in the right
next to you and
you just didn't even know.
That's in the datacenters
when you try to get
to the consumers
via IP and you bridge
these lands over
IP, it gets worse.
A lot of the customer
access network
satellites 2.5,
so I need to tell
you where
information centric.
So we're great
at layer two.
We can do last three
if we have two.
And basically
it's as simple
as this join up
the data centers,
put information
centric networking
on the network.
Job done. That's what
we're doing with
building it.
We're doing a big rise
at about the middle of
the year to build
this, we're going
to code it.
We figured we'll have
a demonstration.
We've also building
a distributed
origins store and I
mean really
distributed like
way out at the edge,
like no one has
done before.
Now the data centers
at the top of our network.
The bottom of
our network is,
thanks for some new words.
By the way, Jeff,
extreme edge and
whatever else
came after that.
We didn't even know
about that one.
But we agree with
you and I we
totally agree with
you to get this done,
there's only
one way you're
going to do it and it's
that picture and you
need a protocol to do it.
And that's what
we're building,
and we're going
to do, as I said,
a very big rise
out of the West
Coast mayhem here.
We're already talking
to some East Coast
TMT guys have said
they want to be
next and it's getting
really, really
interesting.
That's it. Thank
you. Questions.
>> Thanks for Speaker.
First I want to say,
I apologize for screwing
up your name Haimy.
I'm a victim of that
myself, so I apologize.
Let's see.
Are there any
questions in the room?
>> Yeah. That happens
because quiet.
It's a lot to get
your head around.
>> Are there any
questions online?
I don't see anything
in the chat,
so I have a question
regarding this.
So articulate it a little
bit the role of
MDMU where that,
where it could play in
your vision of the future.
Have you prototyped
any of that at
this point or is it
still just a vision?
>> We've modeled it, but
let me give you
the vision.
It's really simple.
So we set out
ten years ago,
we brought a technology
to Australia called
manufacturer on-demand.
We're burning CDs and
DVDs and retail stores,
working with all
the studios.
And we had a retailer, and
see biggest retailer in
Australia, by the way.
And he said I want to
do online and I said,
so don't go
anywhere I give you
a couple of
months and then I
went away to research
how to do it.
And I found about
the single
adaptive bit rate,
which causes the
spinning wheel of death
and steals your money
because you're not
getting what you
paid for and
only went well,
that sucks and
then set up,
set out to find a
better solution.
And the better solution is
really a combination
of brand cones,
BitTorrent, which is
a genius protocol.
Some of the stuff that
Michelle was
talking about.
Basically the
concept is very
simple and you
will recognize
this as soon as I said,
we came up with the idea
of slicing the video,
which we do
already, tagging
it and in the words
of the pattern,
Recording word for word,
tagging it with a hash or
some other efficient
database mechanism.
I eat a name we didn't
know about names that
stage and then moving
those bits around
intelligently.
That was another keyword.
That's it. That's
the core concept.
That is information
centric networking.
But ten years
ago, we didn't
know what information
centric networking was.
Then it only just come up
with the idea back then.
We were working
in parallel.
So we've discovered IPFS,
we thought that was great.
We tried to help them
with some scaling issues.
They've got a bit of
a black hole so we've
moved on from there.
But information centric
networking we love,
and that's really
the design we have.
And it's
just that fundamental
change when you go from
the connection-oriented
DOM bits
down a pipe to
connection was talking
about the actual content.
It just changes
everything and
it's become a journey of
discovery as to really
how much it changes.
Because the last couple of
days, I've been saying
quietly under my breath
in the middle of the
night in Australia,
you guys have no idea
what you've got hold on.
We've got hold of
the tail of a tiger.
Jeff, I think you
would agree with
me on this.
This is going to be
huge and we're
going to build up.
>> I think everybody talks
about in terms of edge.
It's all about latency
and independent operation
and all but
soon they're going to
figure within months,
two years, so two
to three years,
they're going to
start talking
about how do I have to
manage that data remotely
and how do I
make it happen,
and it's only the folks
that are really
active in Edge that
are already having a lot
of their systems deployed
into Edge that are aware
of this problem in,
so we're the ones
talking about
it because we're already
having to work
with customers to
try to figure out how
to solve this problem.
It's very exactly.
>> I'm in the middle
of a discussion
on LinkedIn at the moment
about the problem is
that once people
start to wake up,
everyone wants to push
to the edge so
you just want to.
Video,
Netflix they've got
their own network,
the tribe try and
push out Akamai,
I've got their network,
all of the other
CDNs have got this.
Now Azure and AWS
are trying to push
out to the edge.
That's Toko, golden
real estate.
They all want it for free.
Netflix want their
stuff carried for free,
and they all want
to be there.
There's this simple
fundamental problem.
They can't all be there.
So we're going
to have to have
some virtualized
content-based service
that allows everyone to
run a service at the edge,
but you don't
have to be there.
>> Thanks. I appreciate
the perspective,
the future is bright.
Thank you, gentlemen.
>> The future is huge.
>> Back to you Letif
for closing remarks.
Thank you.
>> Alright. Thank
you very much.
I think this concludes
our program right on time.
Thank you all
for attending
and the income 23.
Thank you to all
the presenters,
the panelists
and the chairs,
or the panel chairs
and the sessions here.
I think we had very
interesting discussions
and new ideas that
this meeting,
and hopefully we
should be able to do
some new work
and report on it
during the next Andean
community meeting.
So thanks again, everyone,
both in-person and
remote attendees,
and see you all at
the next meeting.
Bye everyone
now. [APPLAUSE]