>> Welcome
everyone to this
year's named
data networking
community meeting.
My name is Lotfi
Benmohamed and I'm with
NIST communication's
technology laboratory
and it's good that
this year we're
finally back
face-to-face after
the last two NDN community
meetings were
fully remote.
So this time it's
a hybrid event,
and the last
registration counts as
roughly one
third in-person
and two thirds remote.
This one is just
a safety slide,
I guess it was sent
to you already.
It shows the layout of
the space that we are in,
and the different
emergency exits.
So we have a full
two day agenda
with three panels and
five presentation
sessions,
and we have compiled
all the abstracts for
the panels and the
presentations,
and we have posted them
on the Event page.
As you can see from
this screen capture,
there's a link to
the full agenda and the
link to the abstract.
In terms of
presentation sessions,
we have 20 presentations.
Twenty minutes
are allocated
for each one of them,
and we ask the speakers to
limit their
presentation to
16 minutes to allow for
Q&A and discussions
roughly four minutes.
This year presenters and
panelists come
from academia,
government research,
and industry.
We have speakers
from Airbus, Cisco,
Dell Technologies,
GT systems,
Intel, and
Operant networks.
Panels this year
we have three,
one on lessons learned
from more than 10
years of NDN research.
The second panel we'll
explore challenges
and opportunities
for designing Metaverse
systems using
NDN and the third one
we'll tackle the
question of,
is it time for doing
some form of
standardization for NDN?
And two of these panels
will be shared by
two of this year's
NDN community meeting
co-organizers
Dirk Kutscher
who is I think
attending remotely
and Christos
Papadopoulos who
was with us here
in the room.
In terms of Q&A
and discussions,
let's primarily use Slack.
And we have one
Slack channel for
each panel and for
each presentation.
So please post questions
and comments to
the appropriate
Slack channel.
Also for people who are
in-person there are
two standing
mics so people
can ask questions or
make comments
using the mics.
If you like you
can also raise
your hand and we can bring
a wireless mic to you.
For people who are
attending remotely,
you can use the raise
hand feature in
BlueJeans and
unmute your mic
to ask a question
or make a comment.
So the session
chairs will be
going through the
Slack channels and
reading questions as
they come up on Slack
and of course you're free
to use the mic as well.
With that, I think we
are ready to start.
The first agenda item
in this year is NDN
community meeting,
which is Panel
1 on lessons
learned and will be
chaired with Ken Calvert.
So I ask the chair
and the panelists
to please come
up to stage.
I will bring up
the slides for
the panel and I
will introduce
the panel chair.
I hope I'm
getting the right
one. [BACKGROUND]
This one.
You may want to put it
in presentation mode.
[BACKGROUND] So
the chair is Ken Calvert.
Most of you know Ken.
Ken is a professor at
the Department of
Computer Science
, University of Kentucky.
Before that, he was with
Georgia Tech and with
Bell Labs in Holmdel
New Jersey and he
also spent a
number of years as
division director with
the National
Science Foundation.
Ken go ahead please.
>> Thank you Lofti
and thanks everyone
for being here.
Let me get this.
I'm trying to monitor
the Slack channel also.
Let's get that going.
So I want to introduce
the panelists.
First of all, [inaudible]
Yuan could not be
with us today.
He had a family medical
situation come up,
so he sends his regrets.
But we have Alex
Afanasyev, Jeff Burke.
Luca, are you on?
Can you say hi?
He hasn't joined yet.
Lan Wang from
the University of
Memphis and Lixia Zhang
who I'm sure
everyone knows.
So at the NDN community
meeting of 2020,
there was a lessons
learned panel
on 10 years of
NDN and it was
quite interesting.
And these were some of
the takeaways
from that panel
that the basic idea of
semantically
named secure data
as a basic
building block was
a good thing
and that it is
not just about a
network communication
protocol,
but it's also a new
way to think about
building
distributed systems
and applications.
The research
focus had changed
over the 10 years
and started out more
focused on the network
infrastructure
and then evolved towards
application driven
architecture development
and there are still
some implications
of the security aspect
that haven't been
fully explored.
I think van Jacobson and
Dave Clark both
made that point.
And we really need a good
introductory
article about NDN,
that was a quote from
one of the
panelist I think.
So for this panel,
we wanted to
follow up on that
and have another
lessons learned panel.
And I asked the panelists
to weigh in on these
three questions.
So first one was
about naming and
the fact that named data
is about a lot
about names,
and what lessons have
people learned
about naming,
how names can
be supported,
or structured,
organized, etc.
And the second
question was
about business cases for
NDN and how
important are they.
Are they necessary as
a time to be
focusing on those,
and where should we
be looking for
those things?
And then the third
question was
about application
programming interfaces.
In other words, supporting
the development of
applications by building
toolkits and APIs.
And the panelists were
kind enough to respond to
these somewhat high
level questions
with some really
interesting ideas,
so we had an exchange
over email for
the last week or so and I
have tried to collect
the main points
that each of
the panelists made
to summarize them.
And I hope they will
all forgive me for
any inaccuracies
in my capturing
what the sentiments that
they were trying
to express.
What we're going
to do is I'm going
to put up a slide
for each panelists.
I'm going to give
each one five-minutes
and I will time it.
I will run out in front
of you and hold up
this yellow sign
when you have
a minute left of
your five-minutes.
I'm going to try
to be strict on
that so that we
can stay more or
less on time and
you can say whatever
you want to.
The bullets that I'm
putting up are
nothing more than
a prompt to remind
you of what you
might have said.
Feel free to say
something completely
different.
We're going to
go in random
order for each question;
different order
for each question.
And I hope Luca will
join us at some point.
If you're here Luca,
go ahead and speak up.
So as far as naming,
I'm going to ask Lixia
to go first on that.
And these are her points.
I'm not going to
read them to you.
I'm just going to go
ahead and let her start.
So take it away.
>> This works?
Great. Thanks Ken
for organizing this final.
I don't know where
to get started.
I'll tell you a story.
When I decided to pull
off this proposal to
NSF Future Internet
Architecture Program
at a time the project
was called the
CCN, Content
Centric Networking.
I remember I told Ren
that if you
change the name,
I'll help you build
the team because
this whole direction is
not about content exactly.
It's all about utilizing
names to build systems
and the networks.
I started with the
Name Based Networking,
NBN and then he said,
if you're changing
the middle one name
the data networking,
then we reached the
conclusion agreement
so that became NDN.
I think back in the days,
I only have five minutes.
I need to go quick.
Back in the days of our
IP started in 1981,
that's when I started
networking at a
time there was
no data all people
wanted was to connect
the computers together.
That's how we started
with the addresses,
because that's
something close
to what people understood,
the telephone numbers
connecting two
nodes together.
But since the connectivity
was established,
people built the
applications.
Therefore, all the
applications use names.
Nobody want to
remember the 4-byte IP
addresses now IPV6,
you cannot remember.
So therefore, there always
is this gap between what
applications are doing
versus the carriers,
the IP, trying to
get the data to
the right place.
And I think in the end,
when I first explained
this idea it's really
to address the gap.
Why don't we just put
down the [inaudible] of
naming to the
network layer,
called data delivery.
And I think more
importantly,
just as important as name,
maybe is once
you name data,
then you can secure
the data directly.
I think so
selecting a name on
the data enables secured
naming of the data and
that's really the
basic building block.
About the names there's
misconceptions as
put down there.
Many people I
have heard do not
like names that
started with the DNS.
They thought DNS is a
centrally controlled.
Now there is this moment
against the internet
centralization,
DNS was one of the target.
I wanted to clarify
that to say DNS
is not the centrally
controlled.
There's icon.
What icon does,
is just to assure that
DNS names are
unique so that
the data top division
having top-level
domains and after
that I want people to do
their own business
for the allocations.
I think there's
a misconception
perhaps has
something to do
with another
misconception that is,
the trust
relations somehow
follow the DNS hierarchy,
that's entirely not
necessarily the case.
Here among the panelists
that we trust each other,
we have no relations in
terms of our DNS names.
If we got one, I guess
you'll have one.
I haven't gotten
one yet, although
my kids will get one.
Well, I already
mentioned about
the relations
between names
and security.
There's a lots
of discussions
or proposals and
even projects
that's going around
saying that the keys
are the unique names.
Yes, keys are unique
identifiers but how
you reason about
the relations
between two keys.
You never get that
Crystals key.
I have no clue
that's Crystals key
because I don't have
the super memory to
associate the 64 bytes
with pretty good
at [inaudible].
So therefore our semantic
naming really is
the key to reason
about the security,
that's how NDN build
the whole set of the
security solutions.
>> Thank you very much.
Perfect. Lan, I've
got you up next,
and then Jeff, and then
Luka and then Alex.
>> So I think everybody
is familiar with
DNS names as Lisa
mentioned, and web URLs.
Well, we know how
to name data.
We can do something
similar to what we
have designed web
applications,
but sometimes we forget
there's differences.
Today, if I send
a URL request,
I get back the webpage
and I can send
another one.
The webpage may change
and I get back a
different webpage,
even though they
have the same name.
But in the end,
you have to uniquely
name the data.
You cannot do
something like
what we're doing in
web applications.
So sometimes we
forget about this
and we slip back
into our old habits.
So that's something we've
learned again and again.
In our application or
protocol development,
we forget that if we
restart a process,
we have to name the
data differently.
Otherwise, the other
nodes will fetch
the same data in
the previous instance
again and again.
That's one of
the lessons we
learned from deploying
the routing protocol
and recently deploying
our mobile health
application.
We found that even
though we are doing
researching NDN,
but we still make
those mistakes.
So we don't know
what will happen
if other people develop
these product costs.
They may not realize
they're making
these mistakes.
I think it's very
critical that we document
the good design patterns
so we can avoid
repeating the same
problems in naming data.
That's the first
point I want to make.
The second point I
think is also related.
That is, we don't
realize when we
design the naming
of an application,
we don't sometimes
realized this naming
may affect other
part of the stack.
For example, depending on
how you name the
application data,
there may be different
amount of state
the routing protocol
needs to maintain,
or even the sink protocol
needs to maintain.
But the application
designers
may not be aware
of these impacts.
So that's something I
think that needs to be
further researched.
Even today, we don't know
all the potential
interdependencies
among these different
components in NDN.
And the third part is
that I think Lisa
has mentioned that
one of the most
important thing
NDN introduces is
you can secure data.
And the name in the data
actually allows
us to express
the relationship
between keys and
data names and
different keys,
that's very important
to secure the data.
I think what we are not
doing enough
today is to use
these names to express
other relationships
between names.
Schemas can also be used
to express access
control policies.
And that's something
we're doing
in our mHealth project.
How do you
express policies
about who can access
what kind of data?
I think we really need
to make use or leverage
these semantic names to
simplify the management
of data and keys.
>> Hey, thanks, Lan.
I should've said we're
going to have each
panelist speak for
a few minutes and then
I hope we'll have
a few minutes to
take questions from
the audience or
for the panelists
to respond to each other.
And I want to remind you,
if you have a question
for the panel,
please put it in the
Slack and not the blue
jeans because
I'm monitoring
the Slack up here and
I will relay those.
Next, we have Jeff.
>> So this came from
stuff that I put very
quickly in an e-mail,
but I'll see if I can
try to make it make sense.
So most of what
I've been doing
over the last
couple of years is
I often work with
developers who don't have
a CS or stem background,
even and have
been watching.
They're not an NDN
but had been thinking
a lot about what are
the way that names are
used in systems for
real-time graphics,
in other types of
distributed systems,
and things like that,
and where the
connections are to NDN.
And then thinking
back to maybe some of
the lessons learned and
how to proceed
differently on,
at least for my
interests in
application development
going forward.
And maybe to start
just at the top.
I guess something that I
was thinking about in
this email conversation
is that we've
had obviously an emphasis
from the beginning
of the project that Lisa
and Van started an
emphasis on App-centric or
application-level
semantic meaning of data.
But that doesn't
always translate into
something that is
developer-centric
or developer friendly,
I think and I was
trying to think
through what that meant
or if that was
a completely true
statement or not.
And there seemed to be
generally in our
applications,
I think it certainly
in my group and
in the applications that
I've seen mostly
from the NDN team
in the examples in
the literature tend to
mostly if they're
looking at
hierarchical names,
to look at names that have
hierarchy in
three sections.
One that's about maybe
not global forwarding,
but how you get packets,
how you get interest
to the right place.
So some global
forwarding component
that you can't change
as a developer.
That at least not if you
want to get your packets
into somebody
else's application.
In the middle, maybe
you have something that
represents the
application data
model in some way.
And this is where there
seems to be a lot
of excitement and
opportunities.
How do you go from a
data model that makes
sense to the
application to,
and maybe as a developer,
you get to make choices
about and map it
into packets in an NDN
or names in an
NDN network?
And then maybe at the end,
you have things
like versioning or
segmenting that are more
or maybe even object.
Things related to object
definition that
you should maybe
think about how
they're consistent
within your application or
across applications.
And the level
to go back to
the original point and
maybe a lesson
I'm trying to
think through a
little bit is
developers get
to intervene
and companies intervene.
Or people making
NDN applications
in different ways that
those three levels and
the tools and
thinking about
different name components
might be quite different.
And I think that's
maybe something
that I guess I'd love
to take that lesson
forward and think a
bit more about
namespace tools
that are more explicit
about the types of
control that exist in
the names and who
makes choices and who,
I think I've
focused a lot on
the second part and said,
Well, somebody who figured
out global forwarding.
And then in the
library development,
we were thinking a lot
about the third part.
But I don't know
that really
thought holistically about
what are the tools and
approaches to
dealing with this.
Then there's some
observations,
I think on the
slide that were
from the email discussion.
Then the last point was
a little bit of
a throwaway one,
but one of the things
that I think the NDN
project has struggled
a little bit with
is to try to
explain the value of
this fundamental shift in
the networking layer
to other people,
to people that are
building applications and
can do similar things
higher up in the stack.
And also have to figure
out what it would
mean to deploy a new
network protocol.
And so for me,
the NFT the pop
culture phenomenon,
the NFT as broken and odd
is that whole thing
was fascinating
because people
got the idea of
a chunk of data that was
cryptographically
verifiable
and could be owned
or at least verified
as being owned
by somebody.
And I think there is
some way in
popular attention
to networking
to explain or
create a
connection between
the type of work
that's happening,
that has happened
historically
for 10 years in NDN
and the pop culture
phenomenon,
NFTs and interesting
crypto and so on.
And that's something
I'd like to
see. Let's put a
little bit more.
>> That was
perfect timing.
Yeah. Thank you.
Luca, are you there?
I'll just note
that one person in
the Slack is disagreeing
with the statement
about NFTs.
But it wasn't
really that you
were stating an
axiom there.
I think it was more
about leveraging
this pop culture thing.
As you just said.
>> It's absolutely not
a technical point.
>> Yeah. Luca, are
you on? Not yet.
Well, Luca,
I don't know how much
people know about
HICN and I won't
try to channel him,
but he had just a couple
of points about that.
But one of the
ideas of HICN
is that the
application deals with
the application namespace
and then Maps provide
some mapping to this
existing IPV6 namespace.
And then he had
some anecdotes about
things that they had
worked on in media
streaming space. Luca?
>> Yes. Can you hear me?
>> Yes. Now we can hear
you. Please, go ahead.
>> So I guess
this part of the
conversation was related
to when you start
using these things
in production,
then you start
asking yourself,
where should I get these
names than the namespace?
Where should I start?
And especially
when you have users
and they ask yourself,
what is the bootstrap?
How do I bootstrap
all these things?
And this goes back to
the discussion
with Jeff about,
I need a place where I can
go and say purchase
or get my namespace
and start working
from there.
And leaves and
releases these
namespaces while
I'm using these
applications.
But I was mentioning
in the conversation
offline,
HICN because there was
one roadblock that we
wanted to remove
by just saying,
let's use a
simple namespace.
There is also a routable
and which is the
IP namespace.
And which wouldn't
be the case,
for instance,
for dominance.
But there was just
an observation.
But you need to
have a place where
when you start using
and having adoption,
you need to
elsewhere a plan
for bootstrapping your
applications like you
need that step to
be sold before you
even start deploying.
>> Yeah. The second point,
I don't know if
you have time
for the second point,
which was related to
a second observation
made by Jeff which was,
Now I have this namespace.
I want to use my
existing application
which already
has a semantic
and I'm not thinking
about the AN application
that is written
from scratch.
That's something
that exists already
with the logic that
exists already.
And I want to
map this logic
into routable
lanes because that
logic is an abstraction
that leaves only inside
the application.
And then when you go
into the ICN space,
these things become
routable name since
it's different.
And so one of
the things that was
mentioned in the
conversation
here offline was that
it's immediately
very specific to
the application.
And every time you
change application,
you need to build
another middleware.
And also the way you
map the application
logic into
readable names it has
to be optimaly made.
I was mentioning
in the case for
online meetings where you
usually want to make
sure that what has
to be shared across
a number of users in
the application has to
be mapped into a
namespace that
is shared across
all the users.
Otherwise, you risk
to map broadcast into
unicast and so you
miss all the advantages
of using ICN.
>> Great, thanks.
And Alex will have the
last word on naming.
>> So I want to make
it two points for this one
and one which is
captured in these
two bullets,
is actually a
reflection of
what Jeff said and what
just Luka mentioned.
Is the fact that
I don't know whether
it's a lesson
learned or not but every
time you're talking to
different people
about naming,
they will have
different opinion.
From the application
perspective,
they want
application names.
They want to deal with
the networking aspect
or aggregation
of anything.
When you talk to
forwarding people,
they don't care about
the application stuff
all those
sequence numbers,
not sequence numbers.
They only care about
the prefixes the one
that they need
to route faster,
like look-up
something faster.
When talking about
the security,
then there's the
security context
that needs to be there in
a name in order
to associate
keys to the data,
data to the keys or
keys to the keys,
as Alicia
mentioned before.
And yet, if you fill up to
different security
people, they will say,
oh don't expose
those things,
those looking private,
those should not be there.
So is it a lesson?
How do we reconcile?
And in the end, we
have a data path or
name that
used everywhere at
different levels.
So it has to be
defined by the
application but
your application
potentially have
no idea about what network
is supposed to do,
or what kind of prefix
it should be there.
It's a challenge. I put
some aspects here
like levels,
libraries, re-directions,
linking or board
linking, or something.
So I think we tried to
explore it some way,
I forget what
application we did with
the Geo co-ordinates
so you can
look over different paths,
not necessarily
hierarchical naming.
Again, not necessarily
less and not
necessarily any
actionable item
from this lesson,
but that's what I stated.
And the second bullet
that I didn't put here.
But I think this is
a re-curring issue
that we have.
We overthinking
the concept of
global routing.
This may be touching
upon the second question,
I doubt we're
going to have
the global replacement
of the internet
with NDM anytime soon.
So we need to apply
Indian concepts in
smaller environments.
And in those environments,
those are not
the problems,
global routing, who cares?
You just run in the
home environment.
You do whatever you
need to do at home.
You assign name and
assigning names as Luka
mentioned the
boots trapping
process. Yes, it's needed.
You have to have
some guidelines at
home to how to assign
a name to the
specific devices.
But what prefix I'm
using, it's my problem.
But I'm not exposing this,
the further
constellation project.
You're also use your name,
you're not
bothered with like
Microsoft looks
at defining
what DNS namespace
but doesn't matter.
And I think
there's a lot of
research in this area.
There's a lot of focus
and it just
doesn't matter.
So that's two points
I want to make.
>> Thank you. We have
maybe a minute or two,
does somebody who
have a question
from the audience?
There are several
comments in Slack.
Does anybody want
to ask or rejoin?
Anybody on the
panel want to
respond quickly, Alicia?
>> I don't know
what kind of
questions are raised
in the Slack.
I cannot see,
but I want to
respond to Alex comment.
We don't have many
layers of conflict,
we only have three things.
We know that from Day one,
that name Titus is
three things together.
Identifying
application data used
for forwarding and then
used by security policies.
So, therefore,
it just that three
things come out.
There's definitely
trade-off,
those great
advantages doing so.
The same identifier used
across application
to the network.
And the problem with
the conflicts that natural
but doesn't want to
see [inaudible] names.
And was fundamentally
address that problem by
folding on to say that
event a network layer.
Let's use the semantic
names to call ADT.
ADT instead of to
these 3.78 or
something like that.
Because once you
use semantic names,
you can easily configure
your policies,
and how you've treated
ATT announcement
versus how you treat
somebody else in the
doc announcement.
But then nonetheless, to
mark the name
for all things,
for topological
connectivity,
fabrication data.
Then there's a
conflict absolutely.
And then forwarding
that [FOREIGN],
we say reclaim and
then pegging
actually carries the
both can carry both
what that is the
data name and aware,
which is a
forwarding hint.
This resolved is a
fundamental dilemma.
That's a phrase
that Yacco Islah,
essentially Yacco Islah,
created with regarding to
PGP scalability
problem I say,
go with either the
identifier payment
for our end users,
otherwise,
with your connectivity
in a peak one.
And we say, we
can carry both.
So that carrying
the real data name,
you can always
hit the cache
if the data is
in the cache.
Otherwise, you
move forward
to following the
direction pointed
out by the formula hint.
So the other problems
with the security.
I don't quite understand
this for this part,
I need to learn from Alex,
from others because I
admit I don't do coding.
And then has a great
advantage of helping
security solutions
in the sense
that everything has
a piece of data.
The case of the data
your schemer and
the data trust anchors
piece of data.
We can play so
many games putting
individually different
data components to
satisfy your security
schemers definition
automating all the
security checking
and that.
Either debates but
the ventilator.
>> I'm going to suggest we
move on to the next.
The second question
which I asked
about and there is
now a couple of
questions in
the Slack which we
will come back to.
But I'm going to let
Luca lead off on
business, the question is,
what's the importance of
business cases for
deployment and adoption?
And Luca, as our
panelists from industry,
will go ahead and
lead off on this.
So go ahead, Luca. Thanks.
>> I wanted to first
answer one of the points
raised in the truck
by Derek related to
which is also related
to business in way
on the mapping of
applications names
to network names.
And this is independent to
mean that in
the end or HAC.
And the point is if
you have an existing
applications,
the logic of
the application
is the application
developers' business.
You cannot change that.
You just need to
honor that logic
or in the best way
you can on the
network side.
So when I was
talking about that.
The point was the
applications,
we don't really care about
how the logic in
the network work.
They just want
to use them more
efficiently for the
specific usage.
And I was thinking
about online meetings,
which is a use case
than in a well.
And also because in
some cases you need to
support a hybrid
environment where
some clients may be ICN
enabled and some clients
are not ICN enabled.
So you want the
application to continue to
work in all situations.
So I'm not
advocating against
or for a specific mapping,
just that you need
the application to
efficiently explores with
your exposure from
the network side.
Now from the business,
I don't know
where to start.
But one thing that
I think is important
is that you need,
at least from my
bias point of view,
you need a way to increase
adoption by having
businesses that can take
advantage of
that technology.
And so that
technology can evolve
with the businesses
and vice versa.
So you can use
the running businesses
I feedback provided to
the application
designer so
a technology
designer to that,
that is taken
into account.
So I would say
that up to now as
a lesson learned
in the case
of ICN in general,
there's a little
feedback from the field.
So the adoption,
not huge and so
that makes the
feedback coming from
the business and
from the fields
experience lacking
a little bit.
So that was my point.
It's important to
have that kind of
feedback from
real deployments,
real adoption,
and relate it to
their go-to-market
that I was mentioning
that a go-to-market
fully based
on a network product is
hired and he's getting
harder and harder.
There are some
examples that I had in
mind where the adoption
is relatively higher in
terms of go-to-market
because we go more into
something where a
go-to-market is built
around a full,
complete service.
To be an
application, could
be an integration of
different
components and so
that you can get
easy adoption
into the market.
So that's my personal
understanding
of in general, adoptions.
And it'll be just based
on a specific
network technology.
It has to cover a more
integrated service.
Yes the other
thing is more
the last component when I
was saying platforms and
there was my
personal experience.
You need to support
essentially all
platform since Day 1.
Otherwise, from
the market,
you get back immediately
like I cannot deploy
these applications unless
it works everywhere.
Even the platform
today are
consolidating to
a smaller number.
Very much centered
over mobile and
Cloud and so
that's simpler,
but this will be available
immediately to
get adoption.
And I think I'm
more or less
done for this item.
>> Great. Thank you.
Jeff had a couple of
comments and again,
I'm taking these
somewhat out of context.
I apologize from
an email exchange
among the panelists.
Well, there was quite a
bit more in the email,
but I didn't think
we would have
time to go through
all of it.
So Jeff and then
Alex is next.
>> So I thought
the exchange
with Luca in the
email around
the viable go-to-market
strategies
was really interesting to
reflect on and make
sense even from outside
the business world,
and think about the
idea that Andean,
maybe it's most
likely to have
some commercial
viability in
the context of
an application.
And like Alex said, within
these application
deployments,
you have less of the
global worry and
different kinds of
interesting problems.
I think the point that I
was making here
and probably would
elaborate on a little bit
was it seems like
in parallel with
the pursuit of
supporting the needs
of the industry,
there is, I think still
an opportunity to
do more in terms
of usability of the
research code bases
and things that
are available.
So this was lessons
learned panel,
and so my thought was
that the lesson is
still the emphasis on
usability and specifically
usability for
application
developers to develop
non-toy distributed
applications.
So I think at the time,
maybe three or four
years ago we were
thinking of what
does it mean
for a set of
libraries to compete
with something like
firebase or
something where
I want to have
synchronized data
across many
different devices
that's managed by some
understandable application
supported namespace
and what's
the time that it
takes to develop and
deploy something
with the research code
bases that we had or
this semi research
code bases that were
around versus some
commercial solution.
And they're orders of
magnitude differences
in difficulty.
Sometimes because I
think maybe we're
trying to solve many
larger problems
within and I think this
has changed now with
the evolution of
different libraries
and things that are coming
out that trying to solve
really big problems.
Instead of looking maybe
at how can we provide
some immediate
usability within
an application developer's
contemporary context,
and so the last
comment was
a slightly more specific
version of that,
which I think that
the time over
the last couple of years I
have been looking like
I mentioned it at
networking in real-time,
shared real-time
graphics engines
and game engines and
things like that.
The solutions
are not great.
Especially in terms of
the semantics for large
shared applications.
And the direction towards
granular manipulation
of content in
these applications is
not really reflected in
the network layer in
the way that it
could be an NDN.
They're not
particularly resilient
to issues with mobility.
They don't handle
multi-homing well,
all the things that
NDN should do.
Luca had a really
good list of
three or four
main qualities
that NDN and I
see in general,
it might provide,
for example, easy support
for multi-homing.
The multicasts
support security
and then robustness
in mobility.
And there might have
been one other
in that list.
But because the
research code bases
are trying to do so much,
sometimes it makes
it difficult to
demonstrate those specific
points of values.
So how do I make a
complex shared
distributed application
that also demonstrates
those key properties
that come from NDN,
and so it'd be
flipping it and
looking at making sure we
can really
demonstrate the value
of NDN to the
business use cases,
since the topic
with a simpler,
lower amount of code
and less
sophisticated code
and looking at a single
application world,
the way that
Alex described
was definitely
a takeaway from
the last six or
seven years I
think for me.
I don't think I
have anything more.
>> That's time, and
I think we may come
back to some of that on
the next question
about APIs,
we'll revisit some
of those thoughts,
I think so. Alex.
I'm just trying to
remember what I said.
[LAUGHTER] I think there's
a good several points and
I'll probably start
with the second one.
There's a lot of
words in there.
But essentially,
I'm not good about
business cases
and in academia,
so I'm not 100%
sure about that.
But what I have
been observing is
a lot of time we get
into the performance
trap trying to
compare NDN to the IP
solution of some sorts.
And that's probably
not feasible,
neither with our
academic codebase,
nor even some companies
started doing an
implementation
of some sorts.
It's still not
going to be able to
compete at the levels
of current products that
can do performance
wherever,
because so many years,
so much amount
of money was
invested in development
of those solutions.
So what we need as
a business product
as a business cases is
something qualitative,
something that brings
completely new
features not
necessarily performance
because that's
not going to get
there anytime soon,
just in case to some
level maybe but again,
just not feasible to just
assume we're going to
do terabytes per second.
One small computer just
because we
suddenly use NDN.
NDN brings
different features.
It's the security.
What else?
Security again.
And more security
and not necessarily
layering,
but some other stuff.
So that's what
one dimension
and another lesson,
we need money.
Anybody, any
more companies
that want to give money
to us to develop?
[LAUGHTER] But the
first point is
there may be a
little bit of
a missed opportunity or
still, there is a
chance for that.
There's a lot of
current research
is going over
data-centric security,
or at least some aspect of
data-centric security
in the HTTP world today,
introducing some
signatures of
some sort of HTTP objects.
Jeff mentioned
the NFT object
is a datacenter,
completely different
purpose, but
some kind of a
data-centric element.
This is not
necessarily NDN world,
but it could have been,
or it can be
something some aspect
of NDN and apply it.
Maybe not missile
with networking part,
but data centricity could
be as a business case.
>> Thank you. Lan.
So my first comment
is related to
what Jeff said,
usability is key
for adoption.
So I think most companies,
they will adopt the
technology only
when our code base
is well-documented
and easy to use.
Of course, there are
exceptions like
Operand's networks.
They are willing to work
with imperfect code base.
But that's exception
rather than norm I feel.
But how are we
going to bridge
the gap from the
current imperfect code
to something that's
easy to use.
So my thinking
is we need to
leverage more funding
from NSF, DOD,
and other agencies so
they can help us develop
the code base itself.
And there are some
opportunities,
for example the NSF
opposed program that
is pathways to enable
open source ecosystems.
And I think we should
pursue that funding
to make our open
source code
more reliable, more
user-friendly.
And we need to leverage
community's support
to develop the code.
So that's the first point.
My second point is related
to what Alex said.
So security is
really one of
the major advantage and
Bienga has compared to IP.
So applications
that prioritize
security as well
as robustness in
a disconnected environment
and decentralization
will be best initial
business use
cases for NBN.
I think there are
many such use cases
like what Operand
has been doing.
They're using endian to
distribute data related
to energy production.
So that data has
very high security
requirement.
So definitely
that direction
has a lot of potential.
And for my group,
we've been working with
other researchers on
how do we use
NBN to support
communications between
drones or UAVs.
That requires a lot of
robustness in a
disconnected environment.
And I think
there's a lot of
business potential in
that direction as well.
So another case is
decentralization.
For example currently
a lot of companies
are trying to make use
of machine learning or AI.
And that machine
learning training
requires a lot of
computation power.
And also you need
a lot of data.
But oftentimes the data
has security concerns
or privacy concerns,
so you cannot
centralize the data.
So how do you
make sure that
the machine learning
model can be trained
in a decentralized fashion
on data that are private?
I think that
will have a lot
of business use as well.
I'm just giving
some examples.
I think there's a lot of
potential endian in
business use cases.
>> You got 30 seconds.
>> Before wide adoption of
NBN I think we can use
academic or scientific
use cases to drive
our application or code
based development.
They can serve
as use cases
for initial NBN
deployment,
just like ARPANET
and NSFNET,
they connected the
academic sites
or DOD sites.
[NOISE] Thank you.
>> Thanks. We're going
to hear from Lixia
and then I have
a question from
the Slack for the panel
that I'm going to pose,
I'm going to relay.
So Lixia go ahead.
>> I wish I could
help follow
the locus comments
because there's some
clarifications.
There was this keyword,
was it go-to-market?
We never spelled
out exactly
what other things
go into market.
There's a breakfast
cereal go into market,
and there's Tesla
car go into market.
I figure that because
the initial community
learned and got
excited about
NBN or mostly people
in networking area.
And therefore,
taking advantage of
this design to improve
network seems to be
just first instinct.
So therefore, although
it's not spelled out,
but that's what I
see as the thing.
How we can take
this new technology
to improve the
infrastructure.
I think it's HICN
using ICN to
disseminate radio
conferences
is in that direction.
I said in the
email exchange,
new revolutions they were
started by building
infrastructure.
IT already told us.
Well now if you
first started up,
there's no
go-to-market to say,
hey guys, the telecom,
ain't you going to switch
to packet switching.
That would be very
bizarre if anyone
ever said that.
IVs started by just
connecting computers and
have this magic application
called the email.
Everyone, at the
time learned about
the email wanted
to get email.
And therefore they install
the TCPIP protocol stack,
they tail off to
other machines like
email servers.
That's how IP started,
and that produced
the traffic.
The traffic all carried
by and large on
the telephony
infrastructure until
sometime later when
the volume get so big,
then smart guys like
Cisco vendors figured out
they can figure the box,
called it authors or
gateways at the time
to offer the product
in the name of
ISP business.
So I think the
new architecture
do not start from
the infrastructure,
the applying, and
the end to improve
infrastructure support.
Definitely a brand's
great advantages.
But look from the
legacy of your points,
where the heck without
the solutions?
There's the CDNs.
All kind of different
CDNs has worked.
Worked pretty effectively
to make the end-users
high-paid so that
the huge revenue
to make there.
And therefore, I
don't think that's
enough incentives to do
improvement by
adding cash,
by adding
multicast to say,
we do a better
job than CDN.
This is not the thing.
So I think I
agree with Alex,
said it too Jeff too.
So I think that's really
the critical point
is go-to-market with what?
If we have something
like an email
back 40 years.
I remember wanted, then
you don't know how
to put too much
effort on this,
the go-to-market
direction,
since will happen.
I lost many things,
people said.
So Jeff mentioned about
usability for
application developers.
I think that
Jeff basically
implicitly hinted,
not that I'm
being very bland,
hinted that really we need
to focus on developing
applications so that we've
got traffic than the
architecture would.
I mean, the infrastructure
will change
afterwards not
before that.
I agree with Alex.
I think we said
the same thing in
different ways.
He was saying
that, let's not
put all the effort
on improving
the performance because
the research community
are not the ones to
improve the performance.
And if I make
an analogy, that's
the same thing.
When the IP first started,
nobody wanted to carry
on the business
telephone calls.
That's what the telephone
company is doing.
Hey, we'll do
telephone calls
and get with the
same performance.
That was, again, at
the time, I think of.
IP was started
by supporting
[NOISE] the applications
that people wants.
The telephone feed
more l to IP.
But that's after the
infrastructure for IP
developed and we
automatically support
the performance.
So I'm done. I have
more points but
I'll wait later.
>> Question from
Dirk Kutscher,
does the panel think
that from a go-to-market
perspective,
endians should move
up a layer running
in quick slash
mask overlays?
And there's a little bit
of back-and-forth in
the Slack about the
question about improving
performance versus
qualitative improvements
and different
ways to do that.
So does anybody want to
respond to
Dirt's question,
moving up a layer? Alex.
If I'm not necessarily
answer the question,
but maybe in a
different way.
It's again about
the question about
the qualitative
properties of
the, whatever
new solutions.
It's something that can
be today implemented,
maybe with some
overlay implementation
or wherever layering
on top of something,
then we don't need NDN.
But we really want
to look for the
solutions that are
not feasible to be
implemented
today using IP.
And then I only have
maybe right now,
very simple example today
, inter vehicle
networking.
But with IP, you
may need to think
about IP addresses,
but talk between the cars,
what is the IP
address of the car?
What's the point of it?
What is the communication?
I don't think that
is even possible
to build the overlay
if you want to
have this communication
versus if you
have names then it's
a different story.
There is no anything
underneath.
There is an
overlay that is
possible to do there
in the first place.
So my point to
those questions,
we'll really look for
the business case.
We need something unique,
something like new areas
that are not covered
with the IP.
If something's
covered by IP,
maybe not working as
well, it can be improved.
We don't necessarily
need NDN there.
>> I'll give a different
answer for that.
I think that like
a quick use,
it really take
advantage of
the semantic
identifier part.
So you can think that
NDN is not NDN but
I think it will
push on the direction of
how to do future
and networking,
maybe not check
on the details.
But I do agree
with Alex that
is those applications that
don't have solutions
or IP would be
the breaking points for
the new things to
come up first,
that I fully agree.
Also, with regarding
to more of the layers,
I think that's the nature,
it seems, of the
architecture.
Look at the
California started by
building the
physical layer and
the IP really get rid
of this worrying about
the physical layers as
Turkey, so whatever.
They say, just to
deliver the packets
to the destination,
take it whichever
way you want.
So therefore, NDN as
the next
architectural change,
we don't really
have to worry
about the points
or destinations,
broadcasted nature or
not for the media.
Let's just talk about
what application want and
see how we can get the
objects that people want.
I think it's moving app,
the layer is a necessity
of the new architecture.
You can keep addressing
the same problem
or deliver
packeges from this
node to that node.
That's another new
architecture [inaudible]
>> So several points
in the Slack.
Dirk asked
another question,
is there is a
similar problem to
the 1990s problem
of solving
global interconnection
that NDN can address.
Use several people while
Adam A says usability,
maintainability is a
key sticking point
to wider adoption.
The easier it is to
deploy, stand up,
and maintain an
NDN network,
the more adoption
you will get.
Which brings us to the
next point about APIs.
And Dave wants to disagree
a little bit with
some of your points,
Felicia, about business.
He said that new
infrastructure
like quick plus
TLS plus load
balancers had a strong
business case without
any new applications
and that did
just upgrade the
infrastructure.
So rather than go into
that long debate,
let's move on to
APIs because so far,
we're just right
on time and I
would like to
stay on time.
So we're going to move
to the next question
and Jeff is going
to lead off
on APIs and then
Luca will be next.
>> This is, I guess,
a good follow-up to
the question and
conversation that
was here in which
I was thinking
about during the
last conversation.
Is that I wonder if
it might be worthwhile
in some projects
to drop the emphasis
on networking
and really think
about name data itself
and how does the
cured name data
and building on
that concept,
change application
design and whether
it's for existing or
new applications.
So that we can get
a little further up
in the stack in terms
of the support that
we're providing
to developers
with now the
understanding that there
is research that is
happening on once
you have that data,
how to get it forwarded,
how to get it
moving around
in-between
individual nodes?
So it's interesting.
Just tiny example was
that as a developer
thinking about
name data at
the very beginning
of the NDN project,
one of the facilities
I think many people
were looking
for or wanted
was how do we do
wildcard matching
on names?
How do we get all
the data that's out
there with a wildcard
in the hierarchy?
And it took a
while, I think
Felicia, and
Van, and others,
and maybe all the
networking folks
to explaining that that
maybe wasn't the
right way to think
about what was going on on
the network and
the efficiencies
of name-based interest
data communication.
But later on,
once there were
some workable
synchronization protocols
and you could keep
a chunk of the
namespace information
in memory on
different nodes,
we could return to
that idea of giving
the developer wildcard
matching against
named data.
Whether it was at a
high prefix level,
or really on
individual packets
that were moving
around the network.
So seven or eight
years later,
that concept that sort of
intuitively
seemed helpful to
developers could
be implemented
somewhere up in
an API without
necessarily trying to
push something that
was very inefficient in
terms of the network
communication
itself and that example is
stuck with me about
not giving up
on intuitive uses
for named data at
the application layer and
things that we can
do to make it easier
for developers to
work with the idea
of managing their
data in that way.
I think that's maybe in
the interest of
time all I'll say
here and let it go on
to the next panelists.
But we'd love to continue
the conversation
about what happens if
we drop the last end for
a little while
and think about
providing support
further up in
the stack for
these concepts.
>> Great. Thanks. Luca.
>> I was reading
the Slack channel
[LAUGHTER] conversation
ongoing there.
Trying to focus on this
slide for a second.
What I was trying to
say here is mostly
based on my
personal experience
from the last three years,
essentially integrating
with applications
and mostly WebEx, WebRTC,
and game engines and
every time and again,
our user base for
us just application
developers.
And our effort was
convinced them to
use our technology
in a simplest way.
So when I come
here to APIs and
consummability
have a product
that is easy to consumer,
there was top of
mind, definitely.
And a difficulty was
that everyone has a
different idea of
how that middleware should
work and how that
middleware should
be consumed.
And this is where
adoption helps
because there's
nothing worse
than having two customers,
especially if these
two customers
they have completely
different opinion.
And that's something that
goes hand by hand
with adoption.
And when I say adoption,
adoption of users,
application developers
using your technology
for solving a
problem they have.
In our case, the
problem was mostly
the same scalability which
was measured as
cloud offloading,
being able to scale up
without using the Cloud
because it's very
expensive and
the second one
was quality of
the application.
And then when you talk
to an application,
they think about quality
very differently.
And so if you have
video quality is totally
different than
a game quality,
or degradation of an
application is measured
differently and
so it's very
hard for a single player,
like in our case,
our Cisco team,
to address all these use
cases because they might
be completely
out of phase.
And so the
application developer
will always go to give
me high-level APIs that
I can integrate in
my application writing
very little code,
maintaining no
code, and using
something that is easy to
deploy and to maintain.
It's more than APIs.
Of course, API is
a big word today,
especially for Cloud
native applications but
in my specific experience,
it is more than APIs,
it's more about how can I
map this technology into
my applications
without any friction?
Again, adoption would help
because once you
have adoption,
you may have the
different use
cases addressed
by different people and
so also that's something
that we need to consider.
There's not one
single application.
There are several
applications.
We decided to start
with some which
are close to us,
but that's an
important component.
There's not a single
API for sure.
Just as an example,
in my personal case,
we started with
the very low-level
API so interesting
data pockets.
Then you go up
consumer producer
API then still pull
low-level for
application developer,
and then we went
up again with
different middlewares
where these APIs
are very high
level and usable.
It's a lot of work and
so we need to
understand that
that's something that is
important for
application developer,
but very hard to
maintain at scale.
But again, it's
more than API.
It's more complex and
this is why in the
discussion offline,
we mentioned that
our research team
cannot do that.
If the industry,
when I say industry I mean
a specific
application community
like a game engines,
completely
different to online
meetings communities
like WebRTC or even
the internal community
inside Cisco for WebEx.
Completely different
kind of skill set and
mindset when developing
an application.
Definitely not a
research community.
>> Thank you. Lan will
be next and then Luca.
>> My first comment
is about why
the current API
or libraries are
not as good as we wanted.
I think one of
the reasons is
that when those APIs
or libraries
were developed,
we just had some
toy examples
or imaginary
applications in mind.
We didn't have real
concrete applications
providing
requirements to us so
we didn't experience
or we didn't
understand the real needs
of these application
developers.
So only when later
these libraries
or APIs were used by
real applications then we
discovered problems,
but the original
developers of the API or
library has already
left the team
and it's hard to
make major changes.
I think that maybe one
of the reasons why we
have usability problems of
these APIs or libraries.
And my second point is
related to what Luca said,
maybe application
developers want
less code or no code and
NDN really is
very different
from IPs design patterns.
So it takes effort for
people to understand,
to change their
mindset to use
the NDN way of design.
So one thing maybe
we can do is
to try to understand
their application
needs and we take
the step to provide them
a prototype solution
and then they only
need to add their own
application logic,
which they understand
very well.
So this also is
based on what I'm
doing right now.
Basically we are helping
mobile health or Mhealth
researchers
develop a system
to distribute their data.
They don't know about
NDN but they know
their data very well.
So what do we do is
we talk to them,
we understand what
their needs are,
and then we provide
a framework so they
can plug in their
application logic.
I think this may help
faster adoption of NDN.
The last question
is also related
to one of Luca's
comments earlier.
He mentioned that
we need to support
a lot of different
platforms,
various operating
systems, browsers,
so and so forth.
But the question we have,
the problem we have is,
well the research team has
very limited resources
and it's impossible
to maintain all these APIs
or libraries for
various platforms.
So given these
limitations,
how should we prioritize
which APIs to
develop or maintain,
which libraries
to maintain?
That has been one of
our major challenges.
>> Thank you. Licia and
then Alex will have
the last word.
>> My memory card
had limited size.
I saw last question
and I remembered.
Jeff, the first question,
so I'll just address these
to forget what I
put down there.
Regarding the
different OS types,
I don't think that's a
challenge we worry about.
I remember the
early days of
an API implementation,
Berkeley just put
out Berkeley BSD and
everyone adapted
their protocol stack
according to that.
Fundamentally I think
that whether there's
a desperate need
out of a market,
they want this thing and
whether to rely on
the community to
actually port
the new protocol stack
onto different platforms.
If you have to pack people
to implement this
on that platform,
that means those
people are not really
desperate to the
one that got
it yet and you have
to pay for that.
But this is a side,
I want to clarify Jeff.
So first of all, he
said it's more
about the name,
the data than networking.
I just want to
clarify what you
meant by dropping
the word networking.
Because this could be
exactly the same
thing we are talking,
just using
different words.
I don't know if I
remembered back in
2020 in the
community meeting.
Thanks [inaudible]
for recordings.
There's a student from
UCLA, John Levison.
I don't know how to
pronounce his name.
He actually
went up to say,
here is actually our new
model of networking.
Forget the other
softwares,
addresses, and everything.
You think about the
so-called networking
merely just the laws of
semantically named
entities with whereas
trust relations
among themselves
and this is what
we're networking.
That is the focus
is really on
who you are dealing with
and then what are
relations in between.
I don't know if you
say just the name of
the data and it support
the networking whether
you mean get rid
of the worries
about connectivity.
That connectivity
whether it's
a firewall to
block things.
If in that case I would
have fully agree with you.
Just to think
about this is
semantic world
with trash relations
among each other,
all the different
players artificial,
otherwise human, how
they interact
with each other.
If that was your
main point,
focusing on them the data
, then I fully agree.
That's what we said.
>> It's not what I
meant but I'm in
favor of what
you said too.
I meant more in terms of
the community emphasis on
the networking part
research wise,
the emphasis on
the networking
versus the emphasis
on the name,
data, and the type to
land second point I think.
Helping developers
really to
write named data
applications.
And Luca had a point
about that includes
not just the named
data part but
the control and management
of those applications
as well.
So I agree with
what you said.
Here I meant something
a little different.
>> Got it. So I
think from now on,
whenever people talk
about networking it's not
about the connectivity,
the guys.
We have done connectivity
40 plus years
so we know how to do that.
Currently the
connectivity challenges
are not so much which
we cannot connect.
But rather when there's
this obstacles
because the IP
is a point-to-point
connection,
so therefore
broadcast media don't
really get used in
many situations.
And second thing under
the title security,
we got so many
blockage between
point a and point b so
that things just
don't get through.
But nevertheless,
getting things through is
understood and
solve the problem.
So now it's how we build
applications in a
way that we want
it with the security
directly into it.
There's one thing, I had
one more point to make.
It's about whether to
have in the end to
build applications.
I think one
thing is really
about how desperate
one would.
Can we build secure
applications?
You cannot say we cannot,
because there's almost the
infinite supply
of patches.
You've got the
middle boxes,
the firewalls, DOIs
and a bunch of
other things.
So you can somehow
patch up a stuff.
But in critical
environments,
I think at the
dinner conversation
last night with
Randy I talked about
the power plant scenarios
where the security
requirement are
extremely high
and the tolerance
for any misstep
is extremely low.
When you put 10 different
patches together,
you have this
challenge how you
approve there's actually
no gap, no leak.
You have the [NOISE]
security assured whether
with those
end-to-end security.
Data is sealed, when
they produce then
data they seal it
when it's used.
It's much easier to prove.
I think those scenarios
would really have
more motivation to look
into this new
direction. I'm done.
>> All right. Alex,
and then we should
have some time for
questions from the
audience or rebuttals.
>> So again, I
forgot to put there,
but I think I want to make
a two and a half points
and maybe three
and a half points.
So first,
I don't know whether
it's a lesson or not,
is we do need
a low-level APIs but
that's going to give him
because without having
low-level APIs for
Indian in different
languages
for different
operating systems,
you just cannot do much.
You just cannot
do anything.
So that's going
to small point.
But the actual
lesson from this is
maintainance of libraries
is a nightmare.
It requires constant
dragging developers
to do the mundane tasks
like the boost library.
Update it again.
If it is not supported
we change API.
And out of blue,
something that
was working,
you have to update.
It doesn't bring
any benefit to
anybody because
it's already
low-level API that
needs to work
but it needs to
be maintained
and it's constantly
constant.
So that's the
lessons about that.
It's just hard to do.
In an academic environment
I don't even know
how we're still keeping
up with some of
the libraries.
I'm not saying we keep up
with all of them
but some of them we
just have
forgotten because
we don't have
manpower or interest.
But again, this is that
low level of interest.
And the second one is I
think related to the
bullet that I put there,
related to bullet that
Jeff was talking about.
Probably and most likely
need high-level APIs and
the higher level APIs
that some of us
talking about.
Not even considering
what pops
up or sync APIs
as high level.
I will put them
as a meteor,
APIs and something like
CNL but maybe even
different from CNL.
For example, if
we're considering
new areas of the
applications
where IP is not working.
We need to think about
what APIs would be there,
like for example,
the sterics
work on, what's the name?
>> Informats.
>> Yeah, informats.
It's like namespace
harvesting.
So somehow it's
not pops up.
Not necessarily,
it's not a sync.
It's not D&L necessarily
, it's something
different.
It's some model,
if we want API for the
gaming industry or
something then
it has to be
some object oriented
where attached.
We need to look at
the lower levels because
we need that basic support
somewhere but
the actual thing
for developers will be
at a high level and
this high level most
likely will be
something new,
not replacement of
some existing APIs
that at some point we
also were looking at.
So not replacement with.
Again, I will bring
worth quality for
new stuff even though
I don't exactly know
what I'm talking about.
And the important part
that I really
wanted to mention,
this is related
to security part.
So in order to
support security
in our implementations,
other implementations,
we need support of
security primitives
in wherever
available because
we're not
really developing
this ourselves.
And the huge
problem with this
is that a lot of
today's security
is focused
on point to point.
So even though
there are a lot of
research focusing on
data oriented security,
attribute-based
encryption,
attribute based
signatures,
those things exist in
concept but not supported.
We found a library that
was working. That's it.
Two years ago
it stoped being
supported. We
cannot use it.
>> Because the
current market
doesn't need
that solution,
so nobody work on that.
>> I've made that
same observation that
our existing
security tools,
TLS, are entirely
point-to-point.
And then that also
is an issue in
the context of
other things
like Edge computing,
Edge Cloud
federated things.
So that is a challenge.
We have six minutes
and Dave Orran says
that we haven't
talked about
name privacy enough.
So that's something
that relates
to perhaps naming and
possibly also APIs.
So would anyone on
the panel care to
comment on that?
>> I threw out
the first system,
namely privacy.
There are multiple factors
that cause the people
to have this concern.
One, they think that
the IP is somehow
obscured.
So therefore nobody knows
whom you're talking to.
And that's a completely
misconception.
Today's networking
doesn't have
the privacy people
thought they would have.
For one, it's trivial
to map address to a name.
Second. You just see that
the backbone or sitting
in front of the Google,
then you can see exactly
all the packets,
so where they
come from because
they carry source
addresses.
So in that regard,
I think at the end,
I already had the
privacy advantage.
That is, the
interests doesn't
carry where
they come from.
And somehow this is
advantage together
overlooked.
On the other hand,
IPs obscurity,
so-called get over
exempt, you exaggerated.
Second thing is
that misconception,
that Indian, because
we'd read papers,
will say cn.com and
therefore you'll keep
an impression that
all Indian names
are ascii coded.
I recently talked to
are leading
researcher in Europe.
And they said, look,
let's just, for your eyes,
it's not necessarily
your encode data
into the Indian packets.
Is that really?
I thought the Indian names
is for human readability,
so that it has
to be husky.
I was speechless.
Directly related
to the third point
is that how you
encode the names.
Basically you can
easily achieve
the equivalent way
of IP addresses,
do some simple
encoding of the names.
Then there's an art ASCII
so you can read it,
not human
readable anymore.
And the first one, they're
the all different things
you can encode in
different ways.
The paper I do
advertisement for
the ICC is coming in May,
our collaborator paradigm
and poverty with paper,
talk about Indian
packet for encryption,
where they encrypt
the names entirely.
That's a one extreme
way I think,
to hide the names.
But the fundamental
point is
that naturally it doesn't
understand names.
They just forwarding
according
to the binary
bit presence.
All you will
need to agree is
apprehended producers
and consumers,
how their names
are encoded.
And if you're not in
ASCII is not
human readable.
>> One comment.
>> Go ahead, Luca.
Please. Go ahead.
>> One quick comment about
this problem about
name anonymization.
Considered that at
least in my experience,
when you start
operating ICN,
you have also the
component of lease and
release of names because
they don't stick forever.
You can also rotate
names and the mapping
from the application
logic to the name,
the network namespace very
frequently so
that the mapping
is a femoral somehow.
So it's less of
an issue if you
do things right,
and we know how
to do that.
But it's not necessarily
a huge attack
surface that you
have right now.
But it's an issue.
I don't think it's
not an issue.
It's an issue, but
you can fix it.
You can have a
huge attack vector
if you have stickiness,
you don't have
lease or release in
our specific
implementation in HHCN
because we use the IP
namespace lease
and releases
the part of the deal.
You have to do it. And
so you can rotate.
And so it's not
necessarily
a huge problem.
It is a problem.
>> Interesting. Thank you.
Wendy, were going
to say something?
>> Oh yeah. I just
want to follow
up on Lucas comment.
You can anonymize
the name.
But this data name
at the same time,
you also need to
anonymize the key name.
Because the key is
used to sign the data,
so they need to
go hand in hand.
And there are mechanisms
to anonymize the keys,
but you have to
reissue the keys.
There are ways for
you to issue a lot of
anonymized keys and try
not to reuse those keys.
>> Alex, you want to
make a last comment?
You got 30 seconds.
>> I don't know if I
can do that quickly,
but I just wanted to
bring again the point
of if we're looking
at the new domains,
this may not be a
problem at all.
Like for the
Vehicle Networking,
if you're talking about
the security issue,
safety application
of some sort,
there's no privacy there.
There is a name that you
want to have been exposed.
Talking about the name
privacy in general.
And then it's nice
long conversation.
But without talking
for what exactly we're
talking about,
it's pointless.
Overstating this
by a huge margin.
But again, I would like
to have conversation in
more specific contexts
of new domains.
[OVERLAPPING]
>> So let me encourage
people to look
at the chat,
the Slack channel,
because there
is quite a few
comments in there.
We could have
a much longer
conversation about this,
but we are actually at
our time for this panel.
So I would like to
say thanks again
to all the panelists
and to everyone
who commented.
But let's thank
the panelists
[APPLAUSE] for sharing
their insights.
>> Thank you very
much the panelists.
Very interesting panel,
lot of discussions
on Slack, keep them going.
And now we move to
the first
presentation session
on vehicle and
public safety,
which will be chaired
by Davide Isevardo.
Davide is a
researcher at NIST,
he has been a
core developer
of Indian code
base since 2014.
And he has been
involved in a number of
Indian projects at
least since 2016.
I'm going to load
the presentations.
>> Thank you,
Godfrey. Hi everyone.
Am I close enough
to the mic.
So the first
presentation session
of this Indian community
meeting is about vehicle,
networking and India
for public safety.
So these are two topics
that I care deeply about.
I think they're
very interesting.
And there are
two topics where
I believe India can
make a difference.
In fact, I also did
some work on both
of these areas,
both before joining NIST
and more recently at NIST.
But yeah, I'm very
excited about
this session.
I'll stop talking now.
You're here to hear
from the speakers
, not for me.
So let me introduce
our first speaker.
So up there is an
Assistant Professor at
the Department of
Computer Science
at the University of
Missouri, St. Louis.
He is also occupying
the position of
Director of the
cybersecurity
program at UMSL.
>> Thank you Davide.
>> Hey everyone. So I'm
happy to be here
again in person.
So this is good to
be in person again.
So today I'm going to
be presenting REsCue.
So this is a project,
an NSF project that
recently awarded.
So they're going to
give you an overview.
I'll be focusing
a little bit more
on the NDN part of it.
So the project is titled
Resilient Edge
ecosystem for
Collaborative and
Trustworthy
Disaster Response.
So it's on public safety
and disaster recovery.
And there are
some components
that they use NDN,
there are others
that do not.
So again, I'm
pretty much give
you a general overview.
I'm going to go
over some of
the tasks and some of
the papers quickly,
but I'll focus a
little bit more
on the ones that
are related to NDN
this is an NDN venue.
Let's start with the
collaborators for
the projects.
So the main PI is
Jay Misra from New
Mexico State University,
there is also Reza Tourani
from St. Louis
University and myself.
So the three of us
actually have
been working on
the NDN cybersecurity and
we're still
working on NDN.
So we have two other
collaborators.
Roopa, she is mainly
a crypto expert,
so and I going to talk
a little bit more details
about what are we
using in crypto.
And David has
more expertise
on information
and code theory.
So these are
the collaborators
for the project.
This is a special and
NSF RINGS projects.
So I want just
to have a slide
here to introduce
about RINGS.
So RINGS is Resilient and
Intelligent the Next
Generation Systems.
So it's a unique part.
The uniqueness about
it is collaboration,
cross academia
and government and
many industries.
So these are the industry,
so NIST is part of
it and we have DoD
and we have many
companies involved in it.
So they encourage
collaboration
between academia and
industry and government.
So they're of,
virtual organization
that settle those
kind of meetings
and they'll put
a team from
industry or government and
a team from academia
and we collaborate
together.
So this is the goal
for the project.
So even though, again,
it's a public safety and
it's disaster recovery
scenario that we use.
But we believe this can be
extended to anything that
has what we call a
federated network
of networks.
Today, we have many
networks that they
are autonomous
network pretty much
and they are administered
by their own network
administrators.
So the goal is,
how can we use
these federated network
of networks to do,
we're going to
present the different
challenges and how we
can really deal with
some of these challenges.
And this is where we just
proposing NDN as one
of the solutions.
So we believe, again,
I don't have to argue much
about why we need NDN
versus IP in this venue.
But again, one
of the arguments
that we just put there is
pretty much the fact that
in disaster recovery
where you're not relying
anymore at
centralized entity,
as for instance, Alex was
mentioning
everything that it's
pretty much
centralizing security.
So you see how
NDN actually can
work in a completely
seamless,
de-centralized way
in a better fashion.
I'm not saying that
it's going to be easy.
But this is part
of the project,
whether we are
seeing how we can do
things in easier way.
So that's what pretty
much we propose
and this is how we
are setting NDN at the
core of the solution.
So this is how we put it.
So NDN is in the
middle here.
These are the set of
tasks that we
are proposing.
So the one in the
bottom is the
one mainly using NDN.
So we're talking mainly
about network resiliency,
how we can use NDN
for resiliency.
We're talking also about
computation, orchestration
edge computing.
We are talking also
about a verifiable
computing,
which I going to
cover a little bit
more in few slides there.
So we have other tasks or
we call them
research thercast.
One is on mainly access
control and security.
And again, Alex
was talking about
attribute based
encryption and
signature and how
they are difficult,
so we're working
on some of those.
We are working on
trust and reputation
management.
So if you think about
the disaster
recovery scenario
where you don't have
an infrastructure,
you need to make sure that
you're relying on a set of
reputation and trust
to make sure that
everything is
trustworthy there.
So the architecture again,
when I talked about
multiple ANs or networks.
So these are the
autonomous networks.
What we are taking this
is the architecture.
So we assume that we have
some nodes that they
are running NDN,
that they form
what's called
the backbone network,
and this we're going to
create the resiliency
between all
these networks.
So what we claim is
each of these networks,
these autonomous
network will pretty
much comment or put
what we call a
periphery node,
that is an NDN node
and it's going to be
integrated to the whole
NDN network there.
And these have edge
computing capabilities,
and to allow some of
the challenges and
some of the work
we're going to be
talking about.
You can interrupt me
at anytime I like
questions and they come
here so I can answer
them right away.
I don't know if this is
how it should be or no,
but just FYI.
So this is the first task
that they're going
to be talking about.
So the scenario here
I want you to
think about it.
I talked about
disaster recovery,
but we are
considering what we
call a pervasive
edge computing here.
Pervasive edge
computing is,
think about a network
where you have
even user devices
can be used as
edge computing devices
and in disaster recovery,
that's going
to make sense.
Again, we have many of
these compute
phase capability
that they are
not available.
So we need to make
sure that we are using
all the resources
that we have
around us with
first responders,
with everybody
just moving ahead.
So this is the network
that we call it a
pervasive edge computing.
So it has a combination
between what we
call iServer.
These are
infrastructure servers.
These are what we know
today as Cloud or
edge computing server and
what we call them
user servers.
And user servers can be
even a laptop or
even a mobile phone.
That's going to get
some services there.
And we're using here NDN.
So this is an
orchestration algorithm.
It's called, you discover
the paper is accepted
in IEEE edge last year
and we have a journal
version of it.
So there are many ways you
can do service
discovery and
orchestration of
tasks in literature.
So this is one of
the idea of this
that we're going
to do it from
a user centric
perspective.
So usually we
have a network
actually making
decision on forwarding
the task to the least
utilized servers.
So this is a way we can
do it from the user.
We argue that the user
have a better idea
about the tasks and the
profiles of the task.
So some task are more
compute intensive,
some task are more
communication intensive.
And based on the
collection from
the availability of
all these resources,
we're going to favor,
either going to these
infrastructure servers
or we are going to the,
what we call the
user servers.
So that's one of the work.
So if you look at the
plot here on the right,
we're plotting
here a delay,
for instance, and
what we have here
and iServers,
this is what
we have today.
So if you rely only on
infrastructure server,
this is how much time
it's going to take
you to execute
all these tasks.
And why is that?
Is simply because these
iServer become overruled.
So now if you are relying
on other devices that
they are around us,
this is how much
you can cut
the delay by, now.
Yeah, I forgot how much.
But these are two
different solution.
We have proactive, and
reactive approach,
but again, these are
you'll discover idea.
So this is the
the first task
that we are working on,
the second one again,
as I said for
NDN in disaster recovery
we're talking
about resiliency,
the placement of
this backbone node
that I presented before,
and the periphery node.
And we are talking
about placements,
so this is also where
the information,
and code theory expert is
helping with
the resiliency.
So we have a paper in 2019
where we propose control.
The transport protocol,
this is TCP, not NDN,
but instead of using
TCP we are using
rateless code, or
fountain codes.
So fountain code
pretty much
saying you don't
have to deal
with error correction,
and anything,
just you send
everything via UDP,
and let the end host deal
with it with encryption,
and decryption.
That's what's called
a fountain code.
So it was an ICC
paper the time,
and we're working
on it where we're
proposing on how we
work on it also in NDN,
and if we can use
that also in NDN.
So it comes with
a caveat or an overhead
that you need to
do an encryption,
and decryption at
the beginning.
So it's not really good
for all applications,
but it's actually
good for application,
let's say large datasets
or something like this,
because there is
an overhead at
the beginning
that you need
to do an encryption.
You need to set how
many chunks you're
going to be putting,
and how much overhead
you need to put.
And then you send all
these rateless codes,
and then you need
to decipher,
and decrypt at the end.
So the other task
also that we are
working on currently
is verifiable computation.
So verifiable
computation in
an edge computing
scenario,
as we mentioned, impact.
So we rely on
remote devices
or remote servers to
do the computation for us.
And if you, for instance,
using an application
like autonomous driving
or something else
that you rely only,
you just get the results.
You're not able to do
the computation yourself.
You're going to get
the results, and
usually the car
will make decision based
on the results
that is receiving.
And the caveat here
is there is no way for you
to verify because we
assume that you don't
have the
capability even to
run the test yourself.
So we need to
have a mechanism
to do verifiable
computation.
And there are
many ways you
can do very verifiable
computation.
So in here we're doing
things that are based
on crypto solutions,
and this is why we
have a crypto
expert in the team,
and we're working on
some crypto
solutions there.
I'm mainly involved in
the non crypto solutions.
So the crypto
solution I can
put you more in contact
at frankly speaking,
I don't know much detail
about what's
going on there.
I'm not really
a crypto guy,
and I should know more
about it, but I don't.
To the non crypto solution
that are
replication based,
and secure hardware base.
So we're working on
both by the way.
The replication base
is very simple.
Replication base
to think about it
like now in order for me
to verify the computation
I need to send,
instead of just one task,
I send multiple tasks,
and gather multiple
results, and I compare.
But there is a huge
overhead for that.
So the solution itself,
it's not novel.
What sexually, what
we're working on on
that part is the
collusion there.
If there is a
collusion between
all these servers,
you need to be able
to detect it
because you are
relying on
majority voting.
You are sending three.
If you get two that,
they are saying this
is a stop sign,
you assume it's
a stop sign.
Now, if these two
are colluding,
then you can assume it's
a stop sign while
it's not a stop sign.
So collusion mitigation is
actually a big
problem there.
Using secure
hardware we have
a paper actually
there, and CCS.
Actually, it's
under submission,
and CCS, sorry.
Yeah, this year.
It's still need
to go through
some iteration.
So the idea here is we
are using Intel SGX,
which is the
secure hardware
to do the computation.
By the way it's
very expensive,
so you cannot
really rely on
that to do pretty
much all the tasks.
So what we do is you send
a task for execution
to the server,
and locally what you do,
we have a distal model.
Again, this is used
for machine learning.
We have a distal model,
and we compare
the result of
the original model with
the result of a
distal model,
and then we can detect
whether there is
malicious or not.
So we have some detection
of malicious attack
or no based on
the distal model that
we have at the server.
So distal model is
the one using SGX.
Let me see how
much time we have.
So here we are
working also on trust,
and reputation.
So the goal here is
we're trying to do
trust as a fuzzy truth.
And the goal, we have a
blockchain where
we're setting
first responder
doing a certain
transactions,
and we put that
into a blockchain.
And this is how we going
to build reputation,
and this is how we're
going to build trust.
So the problem in a
disaster recovery.
So blockchain,
unfortunately,
they assume that
this is one chain
like when you
are working in
completely
disrupted network
you're going to
end up having
multiple chains
that you need
to merge them
together later on to
verify which ones are
more reputable
than others,
and they're going
to be conflicting.
So there is merging
of these blockchain
that needs
to happen in order
for you to understand
what's going to happen.
So whenever the
networks now come back,
then you're going to
have multiple chains of
these smart contracts
that they need
to be merged together.
So I'm going to I think
end with this slide.
So part of the
evaluation as well,
so this is where
we're using NDN.
I told you that I'm
focusing mainly
on NDN stuff here.
So what you're
trying to do
is we're trying to
build this small test,
but the testbed
is not fancy.
So what we have there
is just a very simple,
I think, five
month ago testing.
But the goal is
we are saying
testbed today
people do not
use them because they
are not easy to deploy,
and they are
hard to set up,
and hard to configure.
So that's a problem
that we have today.
So that's why we end up
really using ndnSIM,
and it's easy to NGS.
And so the goal is,
can we do something
as simple as ndnSIM,
but still we are
using testbed.
Know it's not an emulator,
but it's just a testbed.
And we have just the
Raspberry Pi is there,
but it can be
anything else.
And the goal is we
want the
configurability to
be like you set
any topology.
So you can set,
for instance,
you give it a
topology as file,
and it will set a
topology by itself.
You can create whether
it's NDN or IP.
You can just work
wireless versus whatever.
So the topology
for instance,
let me tell you
how we do it.
So we have wireless
or not wireless.
So we have all the nodes
are configured
into a switch.
So they all can see
each other in one hop.
But when you set
the topology,
you create the fibs,
and you push them in
all these devices so you
can force a topology,
even though they all
are in a MAC layer,
they all can
see each other,
but we are forcing
a topology
to go through
certain nodes.
So you can have five hops,
six hops, eight
hops like this.
And again, we do
it in wireless,
while these are an
ad-hoc network,
of course you have
interference that's
going to be something
that we need to
deal with or
wired while you put
a switch, for
instance there.
So that's what we
do. Thank you.
[APPLAUSE] [NOISE]
>> So there are mics in
the room if you have
questions and
if remote attendees
have any questions,
there's a Slack
channel for
each presentation
as you know,
so please ask any
questions there.
Slack will stay there
so even after the
presentation,
even after today,
I hope they
can answer questions
that are over there.
I wanted to ask you
a question on well,
actually also
are questions on
the crypto related topics.
But maybe we can talk
about that offline.
As I've been
trying to convince
the NDN community to
work more on those.
I think there's a lot of
new techniques that NDN
could take advantage of.
>> In the coding
part or the crypto?
>> All of them.
>> Okay
>> But the question
is actually on
the last slide on the
testbed and we just
heard the front and
from the panelists
how hard it could be to
have a high level ways
to build applications,
high level ways to
test applications,
simple ways to deploy and
Andean on a network.
So I hope that what
you're building can be,
I'm not asking you to
generalize to
every use case,
but I hope it's something
you can share with
the community,
so they can be re-used.
>> Yeah, so that's a
very good question.
Again, part of Tennessee,
we're going to
be sharing this,
so we're working on it
and we're sharing it.
And again, I agree
with you on the
application side.
So this is pretty
much we are
thinking more on
the networking,
so thinking
about something
as close as
possible to NDSM,
but in just the
real hardware,
just think about
it that way.
So again, in NDSM,
you can build
any application.
You can bring all your
application and just
use those as so
we're not building,
for instance, the
compute capability yet,
or we didn't propose that,
but we wish we can do it.
And so right now the
way we propose it
in the project,
we have like
different campuses.
So each one of them can
have an island running
NDN and they're
going to be
connected through a
tunnel so that tunnel,
of course, you cannot
change the topology,
but in each of
these islands you
can play with
whatever you want.
So you have just
a control device.
That control
device will get
all these information
and it will push
all the config file
to all the devices that
they are connected.
And then they will
set what topology,
what interfaces are using.
And then the task
that if you have like
just sending some data
or you have an
application,
just run the application
for how long?
And it's a
genetic disorder,
like you're using NDSM.
>> Yeah, sounds
great. I'm looking
forward to it. Thank
you very much.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank our speaker
again [APPLAUSE] So
our second speaker is
Zack from Tennessee Tech.
Zack will talk about in
Vehicle Networking
with NDN course.
Zack is a recovering
comedian,
but it's also pursuing
a master's in
cybersecurity and
is a DOD scholar,
any hope to continue as
a carrier like a
DOD. I'm I right?
>> Yes
>> And he also tells me
that he can ride
a unicycle.
Though maybe
you can give us
a demonstration at
the break [LAUGHTER]
>> I wasn't aware of
everyday conversation,
so I do appreciate it.
So we're going to be
talking about NDN
for the inside of
vehicle networks.
Obviously this
is in contrast
to networks of vehicles.
This is how the
electrical control units,
the insides
vehicles actually
communicate with
one another.
So we're going to talk
about the current
situation
that's motivating
a conversion and
the research,
as well as the directions
that the majority of the
automotive community
is heading in
and where we see
NDN could possibly
find a home there.
And the benefits of
using it in this work.
I'll talk a little
bit about an effect.
I will talk a
lot a bit about
a benchtop testbed
that we've been
developing,
as well as the
software test harness
that will actually help
us execute these things.
We're going to discuss
the results and then
where we're heading
in the future
and what we hope
to do with this.
So currently, vehicles
are more digital than
mechanical and there
are distributed set of
electrical control
units referred to as
ECUs that taken
physical input.
So touching your pedal
and convert that into
digital signals that are
then received by
other electrical
control units
to convert that into
mechanical output.
Now, I'll tell a lot of
times these electrical
control units
exist on bus architectures
like the one
demonstrated here.
And the predominant
form of
communication protocol
used for these
is the control
area network or
CAN as it's mostly
referred to.
Now the way CAN
works here is nice.
Is it this little
button right here?
If it has a data field
which describes a set
of signals inside of it,
they all normally related.
In this case, we're
talking about
maybe the accelerator
pedal position
and an identifier
which names those signals
for our
conversations here,
as well as building
in an arbitration
mechanism so
that the lowest
identified message has
the highest priority
on the bus.
And so obviously if
you press your brake,
you would want
it to override
any messages about
acceleration,
so it's identified
with a lower priority.
But in addition
to these signals,
we would also
see a number of
other signals
also on the bus.
And so the reason
why it's gained
such popularity is
because it's
incredibly fast.
Arbitration,
error detection,
and other things are
already built into
the protocol.
And so it's able to
operate in real-time
microseconds.
And so it's been
very successful
and implements in
a number of diverse
applications,
some of which are
mentioned here.
The issue is
that it has no
built-in or
overlaid security,
and this has resulted in
DOS attacks proven
across the industry.
The Jeep attack is
the most cited,
we can talk about
that later on.
You can also program in
custom frames
to manipulate the
functionality of the bus.
We're just replay
messages that you've
already seen in the past.
All of these have
pretty devastating
consequences.
And maybe
the reason we don't
hear so much about
this because for most
of vehicle history,
vehicles has been
closed system,
you need direct access to
actually execute
these attacks.
However, in the future
we're going to start
seeing more advanced
technologies,
vehicle to vehicle,
vehicle to infrastructure.
And what this is
going to mean is that
you're going to be
able to execute
these attacks remotely.
These same in
new technologies
additionally require
new hardware.
And the reason for
that is because CAN is
incredibly low
bandwidth and
the range of
17-70 kilobytes.
Compare that to the
requirements for
new technologies
like lidar
and lane detection,
which needs 70 megabytes.
And so we need
to do something
about this to secure
it and to build a
path for the future.
And so the community has
presented something
called automotive
Ethernet.
This is just like
traditional Ethernet.
It offers high bandwidth
and contrast it
can and it's very
fault tolerant
to stuff like electromagnetic
interference.
And so what are they
going to do with this?
You could potentially
replace things like CAN
or its companions
with something.
One of these things that's
presented as something
called some IP.
But this probably
won't happen
because CAN is pretty much
a ubiquitous part of
vehicles right now.
And so we doubt that
there'll be a complete
overhaul of it.
And so what we'll
probably see is
an integration of old
and new technologies.
And in the form of
maybe a hierarchical
network where
lower layer protocols
act as leaves
connected to
gateways which
then distribute
information between them.
And so the assumption
is that TCP IP will stand,
be implemented to
connect these
gateways together.
And this is where we
really think that
CAN could be used
as an alternative.
And there are a number
of reasons for this.
And so the architecture
that we foresee
maybe coming
across here is
a place where
we segment the network
into segments defined by
their functionality
as well
as the protocol that
they're running.
And so we have
one maybe running
CAN over here and
another protocol called
FlexRay running
over there,
and then something
else called
Lynn running over there,
each of which
are connected to
a dedicated gateway
that are themselves
running automotive
ethernet between
them running NDN.
And NDN does a number
of things for the
automotive space.
It maintains this
content-based networking
that we're
already seeing in
things like CAN where
messages are
identified and leaving
ECUs the ability to
actually see
whether or not
it's important to them.
It has a really
great opportunity
for modular developments,
which again, is something
that we're going
to need to see,
as well as maintaining
the multicast,
which security for
TCP and IP cannot do,
which might be a
very important
thing as we move forward.
And it applies all
of its security
by its own design,
which will help in
that real-time
environment.
We've actually built
a benchtop testbed
to demonstrate some
of these things.
It's consists of
Raspberry ***,
each of which are
equipped with
CAN hats to allow
it to communicate.
And CAN, we've
built three
segments of these,
each of which have
three simulated ECUs and
a dedicated gateway.
And so these ECUs are
connected together
over CAN and
the gateways are
connected together over
Ethernet to simulate
that automotive Ethernet
that we foresee.
You can see the
gateways are
listed here at the bottom.
And they have connections
to their Canvas so
that they can monitor
the transactions that
are actually
occurring over there.
In addition to this,
we have built this
software harness
that will actually
allow us to connect
these two technologies
together.
And so I've put a
brief demonstration
of how this works at
a very high level.
So we have an engine
and a dashboard.
Your dashboard
needs to have
consistent and
accurate speed and
RPMs for the driver
to make decisions.
But maybe the ECUs that
control these
things shouldn't
be on the same network.
We segment them and put
gateways in-between
each of them.
And so the engine
is listening,
where specific
subset of messages,
one of which is the one
relating to
RPMs and speed.
Once it's received,
it goes ahead and makes
an Indian packet and
buffers that so that
the moment that
an interest
comes in from the gateway
controlling the dashboard,
RPMs and speed can be
sent back immediately.
Now, the interests for
gateway are standing.
So they're sent
repeatedly,
whenever they're fulfilled
or they timeout,
so that they can always
be in a position to
receive the most
up-to-date and
accurate information.
And so at the
same moment that
the Gateway receives
this interest,
if it doesn't have
something buffered,
it goes ahead and sets
appending interests
for that.
The next time this
message comes in,
it can instead
of buffering it,
go ahead and send
it right over.
And setting this
pending interests does
a great deal to
limit the effects of
interests denial
of service
attacks that could be
committed from one gateway
to another in the
event of a compromise.
Once the gateway and the
dashboard receives
this message,
it converts it back
into CAN and sends
it over to the
dashboard controller.
Now, and here we've shown
two segments of CAN but
there's no reason why
this couldn't also be
the other
technologies that
are already implemented
in vehicles.
Lynn and flexor, as
I've already mentioned,
but also more
advanced things
like the vehicle to
vehicle and vehicle to
infrastructure
segments as well.
And so this is
a little bit more
detailed breakdown
of how the software
actually works.
You can see CAN
message coming in.
It's not set in the
listeners filter.
How are we doing on time?
I have two. That's fine.
So I can actually
show you guys
this a little bit
later on if you
are interested.
I'm pretty excited
about where we've
gone with it.
But I think the big
takeaway is that if
you remove the CAN
listener part and they
can send a part and
replace those with
something else as well as
replace the conversion
technologies,
you can use this
same design to
interconnect
Indian branches to
any other protocols
that you might want.
And so results.
So far we've been
using J1939.
It's a CAN standard
data to run on
this testbed to
demonstrate its ability.
These were
obtained from CSU,
which I'm very
happy about,
you find them
at that link.
And so we did some
performance tests on
a previous iteration of
this testbed and found
that pregenerating
the data packets
greatly helps with serving
that data in real time.
However, we do anticipate
needing greater
performance increases
to actually
present this to the
vehicle community.
Additionally,
we found that
vehicle networks
really might
benefit from
Indian caching.
CAN messages in
particular are
majoritily repeated.
So we can make
those Indian packets
ahead of time.
We can serve
them much faster
than otherwise
we'd be able to.
We've done a little bit of
security evaluation,
but this is really
where we want to spend
most of our time
into the future,
is really testing
to see how
this is going to help the
security of these
environments.
We already understand
that it can help
them in their performance
and their bandwidth
capabilities.
But what is this going to
do for the security?
And that's where
we'll spend
a lot of the time
in the future
working on these as
well as comparing
accurately to
the presented alternatives
for these
architectures again,
namely TCP and IP.
So, just in conclusion,
we presented the
problem here.
Security and bandwidth are
current
implementations just
can't stand for
next-generation.
And so what we need
is something new.
It's likely going to
be a hybrid approach,
and we present Indian
instead of TCP.
What I've shown
you guys here is
a testbed and test
harness that we use to
execute and demonstrate
the capabilities
of Indian in these
environments.
We're going to
continue to do
that here into the future.
So thank you so
much at this point.
I'll take any questions
that you have.
>> Thank you.
>> Absolutely. [APPLAUSE].
>> I will start with one.
You have the slide and
the pre-generated
signet packets.
I was wondering,
"How frequently can
you pregenerate the
packets overall?
Is that a common use case?
Is it a common occurrence
when you can
pregenerate the packet?
The message here
was that there is
some inherent delay
caused by- [OVERLAPPING]
>> Yeah, absolutely.
In this environment
and please stop me if I'm
not answering
your question,
but the requests between
gateways are
maybe disjointed
between when the time
the message comes in.
And so you can
receive a message
without having an
interest for it,
allowing you
the opportunity to
pregenerate it.
And so that's where we're
actually seeing any
benefits at all
would be at this stage
right here before and
interest has come in
sending that over.
But further, just because
the Gateway we know
needs that message
to operate,
it doesn't mean
that it needs it
at that exact moment.
And so what we're
trying to do is
provide it as
much information,
logically connect
all controllers
that it needs to
operate over NDN.
And so what are
the advantages of
pregenerating?
We're still seeing
those play out,
but they would
be at this point
right here before
interests have come in.
Currently we have
standing interests.
However, as new
iterations of
our testbed come out and
new iterations of
our tests come out,
we better understand
the environments
that we're
implementing these in.
We might have
interests that
occur in a certain
time-frame,
30 seconds, 10 seconds,
depending on the
functionality and
the connections
that actually
need to be implemented.
And that's where
we would see
the advantages of
pregenerating those.
However, we would
also see it in
the caching of those
messages as well.
So you see it once.
You can generate an NDN
packet for it and then
serve that however many
times it needs to.
When I say majority here,
the initial results
indicate that it's up to
98% of the messages
sent on the bus are
actually duplicates.
So we would see a lot
of advantages there.
>> Thanks.
>> Absolutely.
>> That answers
my question.
>> Yes sir.
>> Previous slide, what
are the percentages
[inaudible]?
>> This one?
>> No, the one before
it. [inaudible]
>> So we were doing
signings NDN,
we were calculating
how much time it
actually takes to do
the signing and
validation.
Now this is more of
an analytics on how
the Python
library actually
works on these
Raspberry ***.
But they represent
the percentage of
the total time
that it takes
to send a package
that is represented
by signing and
validation respectively.
>> Let's see, those
are relative to the
number of account?
>> That is correct.
[BACKGROUND] One question.
>> SOME/IP, was that
part of the evaluation?
>> SOME/IP is
an alternative.
We haven't done any
work on it ourselves.
And so they presented
as a middleware.
My understanding and it's
basic is that it
could replace things
like CAN and be
used in-between
electrical controllers
that are running
automotive Ethernet
instead of
something like CAN.
And so it's a middleware
over IP technologies.
Awesome.
>> Okay. Thank you, Zack.
>> Thank you, guys.
Appreciate. [APPLAUSE]
>> So we have
our last speaker
of the session,
but certainly not
least, Ahmed.
He will talk about secure
truck-tractor-to-trailer
communications
based on, you can guess.
Ahmed is in the
enviable position of
separating you
from your lunch.
No, I'm just kidding.
He is currently working as
a senior systems engineer
in the autonomous
vehicles industry
and also pursuing a
systems engineering PhD at
Colorado State
University. Thank you.
>> Hello everyone. I'm
excited to be here.
It's my first time. So
we're looking forward
to collaborating
with the team here.
And today I will be
talking about one
of the use cases for NDN.
The title sounds
really boring,
but if we talk about
the technologies
and the recent changes,
it gets more exciting.
A quick question,
has anybody
reverse drived a
semi-truck before?
Anybody? As you imagine,
even for a skilled driver,
it's a complicated task.
So starting with
the background,
reverse driving is
a complicated task
for a human driver
and even AI.
So autonomous vehicles
look at this point,
for example, it's
a complicated to
drive forward.
Think about a trailer
backing up with a trailer,
it becomes more
complicated.
And there's no sensors
in the trailer
itself to guide.
So it creates a blind
spot for a human driver
and for self-driving
software as well.
Therefore, the
direction is to add
sensors on the
trailer for example,
whether it's
ADAS-related or
autonomy like
level 4 or 5.
The problem is the
existing tractor
and trailer
communication is
very limited bitrate,
it's like 10
kilobits per second,
it's extremely low.
And this is the
boring parts
about this type of thing.
So it's time to do
an upgrade and
the direction
is to go towards something
like Ethernet for example,
as a communication
method between
the tractor and
the trailer.
And we also propose
using a wireless
harness because
the wireless harness
concept supports
a multi-gig type of
communication as well,
so it's capable of
meeting bandwidth,
latency, and so on.
But comes a question,
what type of
networking approach
we're using?
There's a bunch of them
in the automotive
industry.
So which one do we use?
And we're going to
touch on some of that.
I want to show
an overview of
the architecture.
So the concepts here
on the communication
basically
utilizing the
wireless harness to
[LAUGHTER] no
CAN interface.
Everything's going to be,
let's say if we're
going to do this today,
It's gonna be over IP.
And the trailers have
the telematics unit,
so it's some TCU.
So the concept here
integrates everything
into one gateway,
which is going to be the
trailer ABS for example.
And on the autonomous
tractor's side as well,
there is another gateway
that has an
Ethernet switch,
another telematics unit,
and a microcontroller.
And sometimes the
trailer could be
a completely
different OEM in
an attractor from
a completely
different OEM as well.
Now, this is a
data flow diagram
showing different
interactions between
the different components,
and I just want to
highlight the interaction.
So on the left side
is the self-driving truck,
and on the right side is
the trailer for example.
And we're assuming they're
communicating over
a wireless harness using
Ethernet through
Wi-Fi bridge,
and the trailer has a TCU
and a gateway
which is the ABS.
Similar situation here
on the truck side,
it has a gateway that
connects two different
databases for example.
J1939 CAN FD and
most importantly
for self-driving is
a sensor fusion ECU
because the
sensor fusion ECU
will take the data
from the sensors
and feed that into
the vehicle planning
decision-making
vehicle controls.
So if for example, the
sensors are faulty,
if somebody was
able to inject
a false positive
or something,
it might cause
safety hazards
for the autonomous
vehicles.
So for some of the
new threats in
this particular flow
or this particular
architecture,
we're adding sensors
on the trailer side.
So that is subject to
be tempered with because
these sensors are
going all the way from
the right side to
the left side,
to the sensor fusion ECU,
let's say if the
atomic structure
is self-driving in
reverse for example.
Also, there is a
wireless link.
The data integrity
might be questioned,
access, authentication,
and so on.
And each TCU might be
communicating with
a cloud-based
fleet management system.
For example, that
might be used for
authentication,
pairing the two.
So if both are
communicating over
a wireless harness,
how do we authenticate
that this's
a legitimate
self-driving truck,
and this is a
legitimate trailer,
not a hacker trying to
pair over Wi-Fi
for example,
or the wireless harness?
So fleet management
could be used for that.
For example,
the truck gets
the Wi-Fi credentials
and access to
communicate or connect or
pair with a trailer.
Now, let's use the
automotive approach
to figure out how
we communicate.
The question was, what
networking approach
do we use?
Now at a high level,
this is how would
it look like.
For cloud communication,
let's use the
MQTT for example
, certification
management,
let's use the
traditional ones,
for sensors data,
let's use DDS,
data distribution
services,
and for CAN
communication over IP,
let's use SOME/IP
for example.
And each of these
networking approach
is not secured by itself.
Therefore requires
another solution,
another plug-in
basically that
goes on top to
make it secure,
something like SecOC to
make sure that
the CAN messages
are authenticated
or signed properly,
for example, secure DDS,
a plugin, TLS, and so on.
So the integration and
implementation become so
complex in one vehicle.
And this is talking about
only three
communication links.
This is between the
wireless harness
between the truck
and the trailer,
and the other one is
TLS for the cloud.
The car has 50 plus ECUs,
like modern cars, so
imagine how many
components would be there.
The complexity is high.
And this table, a
quick overview of
the existing
protocols that are
commonly used in the
automotive industry.
Multicast is a desired
or a needed type
of communication.
So TLS for example
does not support
multicasts.
MACsec supports it, but it
requires keys at
every receiving ECUs,
whether it's forwarding
or consuming.
SecOC for example,
it's an AUTOSAR,
it's not like
an open source,
it's
implementation-specific
and supports only
authentication.
It's usually used for
two devices that
are leveraging
AUTOSAR type of OS,
we can call it.
IPSec is a VPN essentially
and does not
support multicast
based on implementation
from AUTOSAR,
the automotive
implementation, I would say.
And there's the issue of
the security association
where there are
so many devices,
let's say we have 50 ECU
in the car we cannot
really do IPSec
for 50 ECUs,
it's going to complicate
the communication.
Now, how can NDN help?
Or how would their
communication look
like for NDN using?
For example,
different use cases
like the certification
process or
the NDN cert could be used
for provisioning
because provisioning
happens at the
vehicle end of line,
and also certificates
are needed during
the authentication
process if we're
pairing a truck with a
trailer for example.
Also between the
TCU and the cloud,
like the fleet
management system,
NDN could be leveraged
in that as well,
and between the truck
and the trailer
more importantly,
because we can split the
types of data coming
from the trailer for
example to the truck.
So the flexibility of
choosing the security
or signature or
encryption really
helps reducing
the complexity of
the implementation.
So for example, here
we can say, okay,
we'll want that
Lidar sensors data
to be signed but
we want the CAN
data to be signed
and encrypted for example.
High level. So the
Cloud communications,
autonomous vehicles
could be used also for
telemetry data if the
vehicles offloading,
but sometimes
it's needed for
real-time communication.
Like a totally operation
for example if there
is a remote operator,
basically remote actively
driving the car,
the latency becomes
critical in this context.
So speaking of
performance,
that this bed here
that we have used to
compare the SOME IP
over UDP against NDN.
So here three receivers
and one producer which
acting as the trailer ECU.
And they are
connected over
an Ethernet switch.
So this was also done,
a similar setup was done
over the 5 ghz WiFi.
But I did this one
because if he's
a multicast,
so basically
each receiver is
sending and
interests packet
to get a fresh
data basically.
So basically first
one and second-order
ascending at 20
milliseconds rate.
And the third
one is sending
at 10 milliseconds rate
and getting a
kilobytes in return.
So SOME IP is scalable,
service oriented
middleware over IP.
It's very common,
popular because
it's implemented in
AUTOSAR are very
complex in terms
of configuration
service oriented,
so supports RPC, event
notification and
service discovery.
So that's why it was
compared against NDN.
And if we wanted to play
in the end for cars,
then we need to
have a reference when
you can see what's
performing well
in the automotive
industry and say,
okay, here's an
alternative.
So in terms of results,
so the bottom here
we have SOME IP 1,
2, 3 inch, basically
the first device,
second device and
third device.
And then same thing for
NDN over TCP and UDP.
So overall it's a
very close race,
is very similar
performance.
NDN was late by about
four milliseconds.
And one interesting
observation here
is the SOME IP
both devices
requesting the data
at 20 milliseconds,
you're not getting
it at the same time.
While NDN is going to
consistent in terms
of data delivery.
The bottom here is the
power consumption because
one of the things,
if you want to
replace automotive
protocol, how heavy is it?
Is it a lightweight?
Does it
have a lot of overhead?
And the bottom
is a comparison
between the power draw
and the core
CPU percentage,
which seems reasonable.
Nothing abnormal there
in terms of NDN.
Now, the extra time
taken potentially
due to the amount of work
that NFT has to do
and the amount of
steps that each node
has to go through.
So in this diagram
for example we have,
let's say 50 ECUs.
So it puts a lot of
work on the gateway
side or the NFT.
If if all this is trying
to get the information
from the right side,
the NFT in that
ECU is you will
be doing a lot of heavy
lifting basically.
So this NDN basically has
a strong potential to be
it's tenderize for
automotive, I would say.
But some topics for
discussion like one
interests packet,
too many data packets,
for example
supporting like
symmetric keys like what
the way to SecOC he does
for example reducing
the number of lookups
or steps supporting a
data content struct.
Similar to what some
IP does as well.
So as I mentioned,
if we have,
let's say 50 ECUs
transmitting
interests packets
and data packets
at the same time,
at a millisecond range,
the network is
probably going to
be overwhelmed.
It's going to be
flooded. So at the end,
I see a strong potential
for NDN to be center
raise for automotive and
brings a lot of benefits.
It's basically a
one stop shop for
networking since supports
security as well.
And I'd like to
open it up for
questions or comments.
>> Okay you are
right on time.
>> Yes. I know
people are hungry,
so [LAUGHTER] I didn't
want take too long.
>> Thanks a lot.
Great talk.
I have [LAUGHTER] a
couple of dozen questions.
>> Oh no, just
for him from
me [inaudible] go ahead.
>> Thanks.
I have question about
the wireless harness.
So the tractor is
going to talk
to the trailer
over this
wireless harness?
>> Correct?
>> You're worried about
the security of
the communication.
What if I just set up
a nice broad band
waveform generator by
the side of the road and
wait for this
thing to drive
by and jam the
wireless harvest.
>> Well, that's why
we need security.
Multilayer, I
would say security
at wireless harness level,
at the EU level.
Are you talking about
jamming or interference?
>> I'm talking about
physical layer jamming.
>> That applies to
anything. Any IoT device
we can make the arguments
for any IoT device saying.
>> I guess that's
what I'm asking you.
Why would you do this over
a wireless thing as
opposed to a cola
acts or something
like that.
>> Good question.
So an autonomous
structure is expected
to physically coupled with
a trailer with no
human intervention.
Should have mentioned
that an intro.
So that makes the trailer,
when its self-driving
with no human present,
supposed to plug
into cables as well.
For moving to
automotive ethernet.
The connector is
extremely tiny,
connector failure modes.
I'm not saying
it's not possible.
It's possible
there's a bunch of
solutions, but it's
very expensive.
We can use a robotic arm,
we can use a mechanic
couplers that
why do we need to go if
there is a way to
go this route?
If there's a
way to do multi
gig wireless harness
that is robust.
And actually in vehicle
communication multi,
the millimeter
wave 60 ghz WiFi
is being proposed strongly
for like in vehicle
communication.
But obviously it's
all research phase.
>> I wasn't I
know that's not
part of your
design as I'm part
of your research
presumably.
That's what the industry
is doing. I was
just curious.
>> Oh no problem.
Any other questions?
>> And there is an
additional comment
on Slack from Dave.
He says that if
you're using a highly
directional antenna,
you maybe able to
avoid jamming attacks.
>> Exactly. So the idea is
to use omni direction.
There's a bunch
of ways limiting
the physical range of
their antenna basically.
So whoever wants
to jam either use
a very strong broadcasting
method or be physically
present near
between the tractor
trailer, for example.
There's there's a lot of
opportunities for
resolution there.
>> I'm going to
go ahead and ask
you another question.
I think in the last
slide you mentioned
symmetric keys.
I was wondering.
I don't know what
the OS thing
you mentioned
is [LAUGHTER]
A question from I
ignorance and said,
are you referring
to symmetric keys
for encryption like
confidentiality or
integrity authentication?
>> Good question.
So mainly
for authentication.
Because secOC is
an artist's our
specific implementation
and it's very popular.
So it's a lightweight type
of luck signing and
authentication,
basically using
end-to-end both devices
is obviously I have to
say they have
the same key,
like something like CMAC
for example, or HMac.
So this is
something that is
used in the
industry as well.
So it appears
that NDN supports
the PKI infrastructure
or popular I would say.
But this symmetric key,
for example for automotive
is an important
one as well.
>> Thanks. Not a
question but a comment.
You also mentioned
the standardization
at the end.
So we have a panel
tomorrow about
standardizing NDN.
Maybe you think about
it in the meantime,
you can let us know
what you think about.
You seem you
wanted to say.
So that is you could be
important for
the use case?
>> Definitely.
>> I hope you can
now interact with
the panelists
on that panel.
>> Yeah sounds good.
>> Thank you.
>> So now we
have [APPLAUSE]
right on time for lunch
will be in that room.
There's a door
there that's
close now, but
you can open it.
So you can go
ahead and grab
your food and come
back here to eat it.
To sandwiches and stuff.
[LAUGHTER] Now
the door is open.
>> Thank you.