Welcome everyone to day two of the Name
Data Networking Community Meeting.
And today's agenda starts with
session three on routing and
forwarding, headed by Alex Athanasian
from Florida International University.
Alex, go ahead.
>> Sure, sure, so in this session,
we're gonna have three talks and
I guess Teng can already
prepare slides for sharing.
So Teng, I think he received his
Master's and PhD in Computer Science
from University of Arizona and
this year is a very challenging year.
His research interests focus on MDN
including the protocol application,
deployment design, and right now his
intention lap as Postdoc researcher.
Tang, please.
>> Hello everyone.
This is Teng Liang.
I'm a Postdoc researcher
at Peng Cheng Lab.
Today I'm going to introduce our work
on the Prefix Granularity Problem in
NDN Adaptive Forwarding.
So in the current IP network,
the foreign plane is stateless and
has no adaptability.
So it's simple, it's robust.
But this has several disadvantages.
I'm going to introduce one of them here,
which is Link failure.
If there's a link failure
happens in the IP network.
Suppose the link layer did not detect it
and it's not informed them network layer.
So the network layer relies on
the rocking protocol to detect it,
which is the parodic KeepAlive messages.
And this message can take up to
tens of seconds to detect that.
So in NDN, the forwarding
plane can have adaptability,
because NDN has interested exchange and
it's stateful.
So, our receiving a data packet,
you can know the data retrieval
measurements on that particular path.
So in NDN, the falling plane is able to
detect the link failure much quicker.
This idea was arranged on
a proposed by chain and
later it was implemented
in an NFT ASF strategy.
So to summarize, NDN Adaptive Forwarding
is able to observe past
data retrieval measurements
different parties,
and they can use it to improve the
forwarding decisions for future interests.
Here is the processing flow for
NDN Adaptive Forwarding.
As you can see,
the interest when the interest comes in,
it will be recorded in the PIT table,
the Pending Interest Table and
when the data comes back,
it also will look up in the PIT table.
So the states of PIT can help the forming
plan to achieve adaptability.
Then what is
the Prefix Granularity Problem?
NDN adaptive forwarding assumes what
they call Interest Routing Locality.
The assumption is that interests
sharing a longer name prefix are more
likely to take the same forwarding path.
So therefore, they can use
the path measurements to indicate
future interest forwarding.
For example, here are two data
packets with their names such
as ab segment 1 and segment 2.
They're just two segments
of the same file and
they are likely to stay
in the same location.
While slash a slash c segment y is
another segment of a different file.
So they are less likely to
stay in the same location.
Then the real problem here is which
name prefix length should be used
to record path performance measurements.
So as we can see when measured with y
interest data exchange on the full name,
right?
And their measurements such
as the round trip time,
which name prefix should we
put some measurements on.
The truth of states here,
if we put it on a longer name prefix, and
by the assumption this means we have
better interest routing locality.
However the fewer interest you will cover
so it will generate a bigger FIB table.
And we'll define it as
the Prefix Granularity Problem.
What are the Existing Solution
to this problem?
Existing designs they use a static
name prefix to record measurements.
For example, we have interest
/edu/ua/cs/people/teng/ndex.html.
And when we have the measurements, this
full name will record the measurements,
our prefix and typically that's
the field name/edu/ua here.
We record amendments and
FIB name like the RTT,
our particular next hop, and
then we have a ranked list of next hops.
And this is known to have issues seeing
dealing with partial network failures.
For example,
we have a topology with two consumers
connecting to one router,
R1 another router R2,
R1 also connects to a producer repo 3,
P3 with a longer delay.
And then to another producers
P1 serving slash a slash b,
P2 serving slash a slash c.
With a routing protocols R1
aggregates the registered
prefix slash a slash b slash
a slash c to slash a and
propagate to R1 and
P3 also register slash a to R1.
So, at R1 it has the FIB slash
a with a ranked next hops
which is R2 and P3 and
R2 is preferred to R3 to P3.
And C1 is retrieving data
under slash a slash b.
So, there is a blue flow
here between C1 and
P1 to retrieve data and for C2,
it is retrieving data from P2.
At some points there's a link
failure between R2 and P2.
So, our expected behavior
is R1 can forward the green
flow to the lower path right to P3.
So, because there exists
a path it still works.
The current measurements on P2 between
C2 and P2 will be recorded at slash a.
So if we update slash a to P3,
R2 both C1 and
C2 is traffic like both blue flow and
the green flow will be forwarded to P3.
So the problem is C1 will suffer
from a longer path even there
exists a shorter path.
But if we do not change the FIB ranking,
since you cannot
retrieve any data even there exists
a problem and there exists another path.
So that's a problem that existing design.
While we simulate this scenario and
the same with ASF strategy.
And when you find that after the link
failures C2 is unable to retrieve data,
this is because the flow
keeps recording amendments.
R1 that's R2 is able to retrieve data so
R1 always believe R3 can't
retrieved with a short delay.
And our proposal or our idea to solve
this problem is Dynamic FIB Expanding.
So if the FIB can expand
the current FIB slash a to slash a,
slash c with a different ranking,
which is P3 is preferred.
The green flow will choose a different
path and is able to retrieve it.
So that solves this problem.
And we'll also simulates
this scenario in ndnSIM and
we'll assume R1 is able to find this
name and expand it to a correct name.
And by doing this, C2 is able to retrieve
data from P3 after the link failure.
So how can we do
the Dynamic FIB Expanding?
The first question is
when do we trigger it?
So when our idea is when
you have made a new
ranking of next hops,
you will trigger this FIB expanding.
And then how do you trigger?
How do you do the expanding?
There are different strategies for
example, you have this full name,
you have FIB name, you can expand it
to different name components, right?
First, say simple like intuitive idea
is to start from the FIB name and
expand to one level down, /edu/ua and
then you add it to /index.
It may not be accurate maybe because
the problem may have had a longer name so
you keep doing this.
You can also do from the Bottom up
strategy like you start from the index
dot HTML like from the tense name
prefix then you go one level up.
In the paper, we also mentioned the
Shortest Name Prefix with several ranking
acquisition which may find the optimal
solution, but it also has other overheads.
So the next question is,
we can have different strategies,
how can we evaluate them.
In the paper, we come up with two
metrics why is a number of names to be
inserted because by the doing different
strategies you may have different speeds
to find the accurate name granularity.
So the number of names inserted
means how fast you can find it and
the more number means more traffic
will suffer from sub optimal packets.
So then you can have better
measurements then you will object.
The second metric is the length
of the newly inserted waves.
So the longer the names, the name when you
do the fade the longest prefix lookup,
it may have impact on
the local performance.
We also propose the FIB Collapsing
Mechanism because the dynamic FIB
expanding would find that it may
not do the optimal expanding and
end up with a trade that
can be optimized a lot.
And also we don't want the trade
to be expanded forever.
So we have mechanisms to control the size
of the FIB and optimize the tree.
Last, we also optimize
the NDN Adaptive Forwarding Processing.
The current design because each state
has a reception you will update
the measurements and because
the measurement is attached to the FIB.
So each data reception we
will do a FIB lookup which is
the longest name prefix match
that is another overheads.
And we want to optimize this procedure and
we do this by keeping
the measurements with the PITS entry.
So most traffic that follow the best path,
so the measurements will be attached to
the PIT entry and this single measurements
does not matter the route ranking.
So they will be removed when
the PIT entry is removed.
Only when the measurement is
made on multiple next hops and
made a new ranking on the PIT lifetime.
This ranking will update the FIB.
So most updates,
most measurements will be filled out.
So the FIB update is limited.
So the summary would define
the Prefix Granularity Problem.
And the key is to balance the trade-offs
between interest routing locality and
FIB size.
Our key idea is to dynamic expand FIB
which is to disaggregating FIB names and
we'll also do dynamic FIB Collapsing.
Another contribution is we optimize the
measurement management in Data processing
just to reduce the FIB lookups.
If you have more questions, you can find
more details about this working ICN 2020.
Thank you.
>> So the next talk is m-ASF by Muktadir
Chowdhury who is a Graduate Researcher
in Department of Computer Science
at the University of Memphis.
His research focus is on
information accentric
networking since the beginning
of his graduate study, and
he has been actively involved in
open source SDN project in NDN.
Has been developer, reviewer,
issue bug reporter of various
engine related projects.
His own research has focused on various
topics related to vehicular ad hoc
networking over NDN as well as routing and
forwarding in wireless and gain network.
>> Okay, yeah.
Hi everyone,
my name is Muktadir Chowdhury.
I'm a PhD student at
University of Memphis.
Today I'll be talking about m-ASF,
An Adaptive SRTT-based Forwarding Strategy
for Mobile Environments.
Wireless networks are everywhere.
And the most of the end nodes these
days are mobile and wireless devices.
So NDN has some unique advantages over
the traditional TCP/IP protocol for
wireless and wireless and
mobile communication.
For example, it has like name based
forwarding, pervasive in inter-caching and
also it also provides
the network layer security.
The goal of the project is to develop
a forwarding strategy for NDN wireless
in wireless network that can make smart
forwarding decisions with minimal or
no routing information.
Here's the little bit about
the NDN's forwarding pipeline.
Here we have the main component of NFD,
which is the NDN's forwarding demo.
So, here we have like PIT,
which records the outgoing interest.
And here is the Content Store which
where the retrieved data is cached.
And here we have the Strategy which
makes forwarding decision based on
the information from routing and
data plane.
And in strategy uses FIB which
maps a prefix to a list of faces.
And we have different strategies
in NFT and one of them is
Adaptive Smoothed Round-Trip Time based
Forwarding Strategy and in short, ASF.
So, ASF periodically a probe interfaces
ASF a politically probes interfaces to get
the SRTT value for each interface and,
and then it uses those SRTT value to
rank phases during the forwarding.
While we are designing m-ASF,
we first looked at the limitation of
of the ASF strategy in
the wireless mobile environment.
One limitation is that it does not
differentiate among faces with
different kinds of failure.
For example, if two faces are timed
out each treats them both the same.
And another limitation is that while
it is doing the periodic probing,
it just probes one face at a time.
So it so so it might take ASF
a long time to discover a new path.
So, m-ASF is basically
a redesign of the ASF strategy.
So, that it works well in
the mobile wireless network.
And, and it can do so
by doing a fine grained ranking of faces,
probing multiple faces at a time and
exploring alternate faces
whenever necessary.
And by using oscillation prevention,
I will be talking about each one of
these topic in the later slides.
First we will talk about the fine
grained face ranking of the of m-ASF.
In mobile scenario,
a face can fail due to various causes.
And emissive does this fine grained
ranking of faces according to their
statuses, as on the left hand side,
we can see that on the left hand side
we can see the ranking of faces for
the prefix P during forwarding.
And on the right hand side we can see
there are an example ranking of faces for
a prefix P during the probing.
So, while we are doing the grain
forwarding, we give priority
to the faces which we already know the
information about, which means that for
which we already know the certainty
measurement, and while doing the probing,
we give priority to the face which about
which we don't know anything about.
So, which for which m-ASF does not
have any measurement information.
And here if we look at group three and
group four,
even though both are timed out faces,
but group three had
the face is in that belongs to group three
has a certain value, which means that you
It used to work previously but for
some reason it is not working now.
So, these are the faces in group
three will be given priority
over the faces in group four
while doing the forwarding.
And if two faces have the like have
all the attributes are the same,
then we use face ID to break
the tie between the faces.
Here, I talked about the exploratory mode.
Parallel talk about the exploratory
mode of the m-ASF strategy.
In mobile environment faces come up and
down very frequently.
So, we saw a m-ASF strategy
needs to discover working faces quickly
when the primary face is not working.
The m-ASF enters into the exploratory
mode into cases initially when
it does not have the information
about any of the faces.
For example, this is our this is what this
is what our forward forwarder is running.
And we have our m-ASF strategy running.
And this is the kind of
status of the of the faces.
So all the m-ASF knows.
It's about the prefix and the face.
He does not know anything about the status
of the faces like it does not have
any information about the faces.
So, all the faces do not
have any information.
Yeah, so I initially when
he does not have, so m-ASF
does the exploration when he does not have
any information about any of the faces.
So, this is the initial phase when
a misstep does not know anything about
the faces, the only thing it knows is
about about the prefix and the face.
And these faces.
So, when it gives them interest,
emissive gives an interest for
a prefix under slash A,
then it is going to forward the interest
to all the faces it knows about,
so it is going to fall out.
Interest to all the faces like one,
two and three, then it will.
Let's say that it gets the data
back first from two and
then it gets back the data from three.
Then it is going to update the uncertainty
value for each of these faces and
this is the new ranking of the faces and
up and for the for the same prefix
the interest for the same prefix, this
ranking will be used for the next time.
And another time when m-ASF does
exploration is when the top
rank faces not working.
For example, if two does not work,
in that case,
m-ASF is going to forward
interest to the top end face.
And it also is going to forward
the interest to the face
which has not been tried for
a long time for the longest time.
And here we'll be talking about
the probing behavior of m-ASF.
Probing is triggered by incoming interest.
If the time, since the previous
probing has exceeded T seconds,
so which is the probing interval and these
probing interval is configurable we can
make the probing more or less frequent
by changing this probing interval.
And while doing the probing,
m-ASF probes a list of face.
So, it probes all the faces with
no measurement information.
And it also probes
the face which is highest
ranked according to the probing ranking
that I talked about in my previous slide.
So, let's pick up from our last example.
So, this is the current ranking of four
of the faces for four prefix slash A.
And here we can see that a new face
just came up face number four.
So, when an interest come under
this prefix slash A, then m-ASF is
going to forward the interest to the top
ranked face which is face number two.
And also it is going to send the probe
to the time to the both
to the time dog faces and
the new face as well so that it can learn
about those faces as as soon as possible.
So, it wants to discover
about new faces and and
this is the mechanism for discovering
the new faces by sending a probe.
And then after that, it will get the data
from let's say phase two and phase four.
And this will be the new ranking of faces
and with their updated SRTT value, so
this and this new ranking will be
used to forward the next interest.
And we also integrated, oscillation
prevention mechanism to prevent
premature face switching.
If your face is working for
a threshold amount of time,
we make it the primary face.
Lifts, that have a look at it.
In the like using the same example here,
this is the current ranking of the face.
We have so,
face number two is the top ranked one.
So, when a new interest will come, so
at least assume that we have been using
face two for the threshold amount of time.
So, m-ASF will make face
two as the primary face.
And here we can see that the current
top ranked face is also the face two.
So MSF is going to send
this interest to face two.
And if for some reason the face two is
not working, the consumer is going to
get a timeout, and then it is
going to retransmit the interest.
And for the retransmitted interest,
this is the new ranking of the face here.
The face two will go to the bottom
because it just got timed out,
so its ranking will go down.
And face four will be
the top ranked face now.
So here we can see that our current
primary face is still face two, but
our current top ranked face is face four.
So what MSF is going to do is
that it is going to send interest
to the both of them.
So we do not want to quickly switch
to a face if it is working just now.
So before switching to a face permanently,
we want to make sure that
that face is a stable one,
only then we make that
face a primary face.
For example, if face four is working for
this THRESHOLD amount of time only
then we make it the primary face.
So whatever I talked about,
we implemented it and
we ran some preliminary experiment
using this simple topology.
And we did not run any routing here, so
the cost is a one for all these links.
And this is the first
level access point and
this is the second level access point and
we have a one consumer and two producer.
So the green one is the consumer, which
will send one interest per second, and
the purple ones are the producer,
which will be serving the data.
And here we wanted to sort of stimulate
this producer mobility scenario.
So whenever node four is up,
node 7 will be down, so
they will alter their status like this.
So whenever node 4 is offline,
node 7 will be online and vice versa.
So we wanted to see that,
by similar thing.
By running experiment in this scenario we
wanted to see how long it takes for SF and
MSF to find a new path
when a primary faces down.
For example, when this access point, where
the MSF will be running, it is using this
face to reach producer four.
When this face goes down, how long it
takes for the strategy running in this
access point to discover that, okay,
there is another face along this path.
But we wanted to see that, and
we ran the experiment in this NDNSim,
and all the access point are running
the ASF m-ASF and flooding.
And other nodes we ran BestRoute.
We use two probing interval,
probing interval two and four.
And we run the experiment for
60 seconds and we run it for 10 times.
So here is the result for
the median of ten runs.
Over here we can see that the result for
when the probing interval is four seconds
and when the probing
interval is two second.
And here we can see that m-ASF
has higher interest count, and
as well as the overall
higher protocol overheard.
It is because m-ASF does
this aggressive probing, so
that is why it has a higher
interest count than ASF strategy.
But in cost of this
higher interest number,
it can satisfy a lot of interest, so
93% of the interest are being
satisfied by the m-ASF.
While for ASF, it is only 63% because for
ASF, whenever a primary face
is going down, it takes a long time for
ASF to find the face which is working.
That's why it has a lot of
timed out interest as well.
And we can also see the similar result
in this probing interval 2, as well.
So when the probing interval is 2,
the probing is more frequent.
So in that case, ASF is performing
a little bit better than the previous one,
but it's still lower than m-ASF.
Okay, so to conclude, and
this is something we observed that ASF is
not suitable for unstable and
short lived link.
Once a working face is down, it takes
a long time to find another working face.
And m-ASF is showing some promising
results in such scenario.
And this is sort of our to do list
that we are continuing doing.
We want to run experiment for the scenario
where new faces are created dynamically.
So when we are running experiment,
we want to create the faces dynamically.
And m-ASF has this feature
which probe the unprobed faces.
So when we have this scenario,
this feature will come in handy.
And since the industry does not support
to write this kind of scenario.
So to create this kind of scenario where
we can create faces dynamically, so
we are fixing minindn-wifi
to support this feature.
And we also want to run experiment,
to test the oscillation
prevention mechanism as well.
And eventually we want to match
the code with ASF codebase.
Thank you.
>> Okay, thank you very much,
I don't think we have that much time for
questioning.
So Junxiao is a guest researcher at
National Institute of Standards and
Technology, Advanced Network Technologies
division.
He's a core developer and
has been developing NDN
network forwarding since 2013.
So please.
>> Hi, my name is Junxiao Shi,
today I'm presenting on the NTP DK and
Dr forwarding at 100 gigabits per
second on commodity hardware.
NDN-DPDK is a high-speed NDN forwarder.
Our performance goal is to achieve
line speed on commodity hardware, and
we are pursuing two avenues to get there.
First, we want to adopt
a better algorithms and
data structures as presented
in last two years.
We adopted a two stage longest
prefix match algorithm in the FIB.
We also combine the PIT and
the CS into a single hash table
called the PIT-CS Composite Table.
The second avenue is to reduce overhead
in the library and the kernel.
On this side,
we use data plane development kit or DPDK.
It provides us with a multi-threaded
architecture as well as efficient
memory allocation using hugepage memory.
It also has the use of space
ethernet adapter drivers.
This is the architecture diagrams
of the NDN-DPDK forwarder.
It has the issue box is a thread,
they are divided into three stages,
the input stage, the forwarding stage,
and the output stage.
Packets are received in the input
stage from the ethernet adapters.
The input threader will decode the packet
and then dispatch packet to one
of the forwarding thread,
according to their names.
The forwarding thread has
the usual PIT+CS and the FIB,
as well as the forwarding strategy.
Then the packet goes out
on the output thread.
>> Since last year we have
improved the packet decoder and
reassembler in the input threads.
We restructured the FIB to better
support for forwarding hints.
We added some CoDel queues
in the forwarding thread,
which I will describe later.
We also expanded the platform support for
the forward software.
So regarding the codec Oculus CoDel
is active queue management technique.
Usually it is used on the egress
side because the link bandwidth is
a bottleneck but for Andy and
dpdk We added a CoDeL
cues on the Ingress side of the forwarding
thread because our initial benchmark
indicates the bottleneck is in the forward
insert or not the link bandwidth.
We give each packet type a separate
queue and then we prioritize data packet
over interest because in Dropping
a data packet was a waste of bandwidth,
wasted server CPU resources all ready
spent on processing the interest.
We achieved that we lose this
power rotation session by decoding
filler number of interest
Zen data in each loop.
Apart from CODEL We
also added a cubic like
condition control algorithm
in the traffic generator.
So if consumer will react will
react to congestion marks inserted
by the CODEL cues.
It will also retransmitted base
retransmitted unsatisfied the interests of
based on RTO We use suppose codel and
the cubicle in our benchmarks.
So next I will present some
of the benchmark results.
We did our benchmark using this
simple three node topology,
there are two traffic generators
suppose they are both the consumer and
the producer and they say fetch data
from each other through the forwarder
As the forwarder machine has
to enter cascadilla CPU and
a number of mellanox ConnectX5
100 ge ethernet adapters.
The big news is we made it
to 100 gigabits per second.
To have this number we measure
the aggregated data forwarding rate of
from the consumers.
This metric only counts the data packet
and it does not contain retransmissions.
Then we multiply that by
the payload the size.
The payload size is only the data payload.
It does not contain the name of
Those signatures with a forwarding
thread we get up to 108 gigabytes
per second aggregate good put
So we started changing a number
of forwarding threads.
The expectation is if we have more
fallenness rather we should get a higher
data forwarding rate in PPS but So
results are shows if we have 1,
2 or 4 for the thread there is linear
growth on the data forwarding rate but
when we have more than
8 forwarding thread, so
data forwarding rate plateaus
at 8 forward in thread.
There is no more improvement.
Our analysis indicates is a bottleneck who
would should be in the input thread and
the current or
forward architecture only allows one input
straight up per face in our future work or
try to improve this We also measured
the effect of non local memory access.
As I mentioned earlier,
our bank our forward machine has two CPUs.
In modern server architecture issue
CPU along with some memory and
the PCI devices, such as ethernet
adapters belong to undo my socket.
That we can even have both
of these adapters on same side of
the machine, same number socket.
So traffic just goes to one more socket.
Or we can arrange them on
different number socket,
and all the traffic can need to
cross the number socket boundary.
Crossing number socket boundary
incurs higher memory access latency.
Our benchmarking indicates if a trafficker
has to cross the new masahito boundaries
and data forwarding rate
will be up to 20% slower.
So our main feature works Is
the hardware acceleration
The goal is to remove
the input thread bottleneck.
But before I describe the hardware Let
me introduce the how the input thread
apparently works.
So, input thread will receive packets We
receive Ethernet frames the frames or
network interface hardware IDs and
it was decoded the packet.
If the packet is an DLP fragment it
will perform reassembly as necessary.
Sent depending on whether the packet
type in layer three if it
interests it what dispatchers
are interested in
By Name prefix is what takes
us name prefix compute a hash.
Then look up the name this patch
tables the MDT entry indicates
which forward is ready to
show the process in a packet.
If the packet is a data or necco packet
is for correctness, so data must be
dispatched to the same point in thread the
data handles a corresponding interest to.
To achieve that we have hopper by
hopper Hydra code is a PID token.
Pitaka is carried in every packet and this
option will return the same PID token.
All the data packet shows the input
thread can just look at for
the thread ID in the PE token
to determine where to dispatch.
The goal of a hardware
solution is to implement
most of the inputs read in hardware,
so that the hardware can dispatch move
most packets directly to
the forwarding threats.
In the hardware there is the modern
ethernet adapters support a feature
called the receive side scaling.
First is the Ethernet Adapter
has a number of received queues.
For each queue,
we can configure which process,
which thread to process the packet
received on this queue.
We can also set a memory pool,
where the hardware is going to store
the packet and ideally it should be
on the same NUMA socket as
a threat of processing the packet.
Then incoming frames are matched against
some receive side scaling rules and
the dispatch to the queue.
Each rule looks like this if
field F has value beats and
dispatch to this queue, so how the world
will match according to those rules and
if a packet doesn't match any
rules a packet gets dropped.
But, what I can use in field
F was a choice on limited
by hardware functionality.
For the Connect x five, it only
supported fields in Ethernet IP, UDP or
TCP headers, but some other cards,
some intercaste.
They support the bytes at
offset IE generic field but
also also restriction in that area.
But now we look back on the input thread
architecture whether we can do it with
the receive side scaling for
reassembly feature.
No, we cannot.
It is infeasible with RSS,
but unfortunately not every
packet needs reassembly and hopefully
only a small number of them needs them.
For the data and equities patient
we can use a few ISS rules to
try to match a bias at offset I and
normally it should be able
to find the where's that afford insert
ID byte is and the dispatcher using ISS.
For the interest this poetry
is also infeasible with
RSS to start with the name
has the variable less.
So our question is can case on
the adapter understand the name?
ICN'16 paper and NDN-NIC-basic Filtering
on Network Interface Card.
It's it'll propose to compute
a Hash of the names and
passes through a BloomFilter to
determine whether to accept the packet.
The requirements on the NTP DK
interest expression is similar,
we want to compute the hash of the name
prefix look up as the NDT understands, and
the dispatcher according to that cue, but
a big difference is on the Nikkor
paper only has Python simulation.
Well, we need a real
hardware implementation.
In industries there are a few ways to
do such a hardware implementation,
including extended Berkeley packet filter.
P4 programming language and
the FPGA hardware logic.
And this is where you come in.
We are seeking collaborations.
If you know how to do hardware
implementation, as well as if you
are good at algorithm modelling
especially in congestion control.
And the disk-based caching policy,
which I presented last year.
If you have access to
some real traffic trace,
to improve forward evaluation,
please get in touch.
We are also looking for
collaboration application use case,
data intensive science is already using
on the NDN-PDK as presented yesterday.
Also live video streaming will be
suitable for high performance forwarding.
And if you'll maintain
some of the libraries,
we can help you to get an dntp
dk support into your libraries.
These are some of the library already
supported on the NDN-DPDK and
your library can be the next one.
The NDN-DPDK codebse is
open source on GitHub
is a codebase that contains
a forward as a traffic generator
graph qL based management tools as well as
one of the libraries, our code library.
And as I mentioned earlier and the
NDN-DPDK has expanded the platform support
as a blue and cyan using philosophia.
We support ubuntu, Debian CentOS
operating systems we added support for
VirtualBox virtualization.
We are also looking at a KVM,
we tested on inter ethernet adapters.
We support VLAN tagging now, and
we're looking at the tunnel
support in the future.
And we added the local
application support,
which means you can run your application
on the same node as a forwarder.
And it is the highly efficient
to share the memory transporter
between the application and the forwarder.
We also reduce the minimum
system requirements so that it
would be possible to run the NDN-DPDK
on a laptop such as you have 4 cores or
8 gigabytes of memory or possibly less.
And remember there was
a presentation on fabric testbed
an NDN was selected as one of
the science drivers on fabric.
So we are looking at developing
our NDN-DPDK experiment profile.
With that, you will be able to launch
a network of NDN-DPDK, forwarders,
and traffic generators
across multiple locations.
Then you can customize your applications,
routing protocols,
forwarding strategies and
attaching algorithms.
And using the tools provided by February,
you can collect the measurements such
as a packet timing and a statistics.
And finally, we our paper is
published in ACM ICN 2020 conference.
And please attend, and the NDN-NPDK
presentation at that conference, which we
will have cover more content of the
completed design as well as benchmarks.
Thank you.
>> Good you Junsho, and I think
there's a few questions in the chat.
So, the first one from Ilia,
he's asking what is the per core
performance of NDN- DPDK folder.
Is it a common metric gigabit
per second core per core?
>> This is 108 Gbps if you divided by
a transaction is 8 forwarding thread.
But we also have inputs and
outputs rate of one per face.
But if you only look at one core,
well forward in thread then you
get about just below 0.24
million packets per second.
But again, this is just copying
the forwarding thread, since input and
output are fixed.
>> Okay.
And the other question is deduced from
question, did you do
the study on the impact on
the size of the field on
the performance of the forwarder?
>> Yes, so we did this, a fiver,
we got up to a million entrance, and
it has very little impact.
I will present that in the ACM as
I don't have time in this one.
>> And the last question from LAN
is what exactly in UK actually,
I had the same question when you're
talking about the library support
defending DPDK,
what exactly you actually meant by that?
>> As a library supporter, Wes,
he is efficient transport like
a shared memory, or at least Ethernet.
You need that there you need a pet token.
Page token has to be, because a producer
said it has to return the page token.
And the Python NDN, it does not have it.
And there's a third one,
is the management integration.
Since NDN-DPDK the case,
the management is GraphQL.
And it currently leads over HTTP, but
in the future, it will be over NDN.
But to say Python do it while you're
gonna have this management, so
it's not going to be able
to read your sub prefix.
>> [BLANK_AUDIO ] Okay so,
we will be out of time behind schedule for
a few seconds so given back floor to
>> The previous
session just ended, so
it's time to start the panel.
And I'll hand it to you,
so go ahead please.
>> Okay, so I don't see the audience but
I would like to welcome everybody to the,
>> Recording is on,
>> Okay, recording is on.
Welcome everybody to that panel.
And I was asked to host that panel.
I think it goes back to 2009 when
I organized the net Ark symposium,
40 years internet where
van Jacobson presented
first approaches to the MDN or CCN.
At that time.
was then permitted to have a sabbatical
at his place at Xerox PARC at that time.
And then later at UCLA also hosted that so
I'm very grateful that I
could be part of that community and
I'm very happy to moderate that panel.
If he could quickly
look at the next slide.
The participants are really
the selection of people having worked at
the core of NDN over the last 10 years.
Here, they are sorted in alphabetic order.
We will keep that order except for
Van Jacobson, which I think is
excellent to start the several rounds, and
if we can quickly go to the next slide.
The first round would be on the highlights
what were the highlights of the last
10 years.
We would like to hear what people Would
show to the world what was achieved there.
What are the important things and
I think there are different perspective
from the people we will have on the panel.
The second round is then on
where things could be improved.
Things about looking back,
which could have been made other wise or
where we still have to do some work.
And I think is round 3 is
about the closing statement
by trying to assess where things are right
now and how it could continue later on.
So with the next slide,
I think we can also start.
I asked everybody to quickly give roles or
what was their participation
in the project?
And you will see that and
if we go to the next slide,
I think it's Van Jacobson part.
I hope he can jump in.
I added the spiritus rector role.
He was really the engine and the motor and
the initiator of the whole thing.
He asked me to put
researcher as a role and
that will then come up in the next slides.
So, we are now in round 1.
We have only a few minutes, two,
three minutes, per person to make a point.
And then we will have a discussion
around where all the eight panelists
can complement, can comment and
trying to round up that first and what
are the highlights of the last 10 years.
And Jacobson, if I may invite
you to take over the floor.
>> And thank you Christian.
I guess, the slide,
pretty much as point when we were
working on multicast backbone,
the backbone and the audio and
video and interaction tools that
became the basis of the RTP protocol.
It got really obvious that the fundamental
model of IP was really limited
if it was a phone call between
endpoints and the goal of the network
was to provide a bit pipe.
That's a communication model that has
a name is the Shannow-Weaver model.
It's sort of the lowest common
denominator of communication and
his main virtue is it's
really easy to monetize.
You can sell the endpoints.
The endpoint identity the device
that creates the endpoints,
the wire between them,
lots of ways to make money which means it
lots of ways to be successful
in the world, which it is.
But if you look at the developments
as a species we've had about 50,000 years
to evolve the way that we use language,
the communication models between
people and groups of people and how
to adapt them to make the communication
effective to accomplish objectives.
And none of that is in
the Shannow-Weaver model and
it becomes really obvious when you
tried to use radios as radios.
Use the fact that things can be
said that everybody can hear so
that you can get some situation awareness
you can get agreement a lot easier
using the broadcast nature, the channel.
There are richer communication models.
The current gold standard is pardon ones.
It includes broadcast channels,
multi party communication, asymmetric
roles, parties doing different things.
There are communication acts,
individual units,
speech acts that mediate
the communication.
You can tell whether they succeed or
fail there some reciprocity so
you can adapt if your apps aren't working,
the communication
system knows enough to say okay well
that didn't work let me try this.
I wondered if it was possible to
make a low level communication framework,
something at the level of IP and
the simplicity of IP that would
implement a framework like farlands.
And I think that that goal
largely succeeded that Indian
is such a framework it can implement
much richer communication models.
The next section I'll say it can but
largely it doesn't.
Which is sad, I believe.
I'll stop there.
>> Okay, great.
That keeps us in time.
So you really present it in
an evolutionary trajectory and
I like very much that.
Could we please have the next slide?
And I think it's Jeff.
He did give me a title I
now assigned one to him.
I think it was really driving NDN for
use cases and library movements.
And Jeff,
please if you want to take the floor.
>> Sure.
Thanks, Christian.
So I've been primarily focused on
trying to build applications over
NDN largely now in media but
looking at mobile health in the building
information systems and someone.
And I think the thing that I responded to
in your question was actually primarily
emotional at this point was some
of the highlights were really
seeing in hackathons and implementation
focused efforts where there were specific
problems and clever ideas on the table.
I thought there were great solutions that
were coming from students and researchers.
And I think vehicular networking and
IoT hacks of various kinds,
different approaches to media, certainly,
those were all things that were very
exciting and I think prompted from the
shift and thinking that man talked about.
And I think the exciting thing for
me was to project forward how those
smaller clever ideas would look in a more
widely deployed Indian context where
you had sort of the robustness to
difficult communication environments.
You have more intrinsic security.
And so it wasn't just the hacks
themselves, but sort of the context in
which they could be deployed using
the NDN based approach and so
that I think are some of the most, those
are some of the most exciting things.
It's kind of combination
of clever reformulations
of applications with the potential for
the architecture to support
a more robust environment in which those
things are would ultimately be operating.
The analogy for me is to Robert venturi,
his way of talking about
architecture in the late 70s.
And this notion of moving away from
thinking of NDN in a quote
unquote pure way, which was.
It is very important maybe from
the architectural perspective and
certainly from the perspective
of the research team, but
to a deployment that's much more sort of
messy and vital in accommodating existing
communication mechanisms above underneath
below and something that is really for
accommodating the current
tools that we have the current
communication infrastructure but taking
advantage of these, the benefits and
properties of in the end that I think
we are, continue to be excited about.
And so,
I think just to to conclude this quickly,
I wanna maybe suggests that it
would be nice to have more of that
kind of experimentation that
crosses the the research purity
of the architectural goals with
really the objective of of solving
small interesting problems and
then getting them out into the world.
>> Great so
pragmatics is really important and
that is what you should
explore explored and applied.
Thanks a lot for your statement.
And we will continue with Dave Clark.
Next slide.
He sent an email with some quite some
text I extracted a few of the sentences I
hope that is fitting what
he wants to tell here
that Dave Clark as one of the original
designers of the internet, but
he was also involved in the FIA project
looking at the different proposals.
Please stay safe.
Is there anything in the mornings?
>> Yes, I think the point I started
with was the first point on your slide.
Van really put forward a bold idea here.
It was a rethinking of the the entire
framing of how you should build a network.
And I think most of the fire proposals
were somewhat incremental and
this one was.
Incredibly dramatic.
It was a tremendous change.
Now, understand I'm sort of
commenting as an outsider here.
I was looking across the projects.
I wasn't deeply involved in this.
I went to a lot of the Indian workshops,
which were quite exciting.
And I had some very interesting
conversations with Van, which were,
I think, useful to me in
extracting sort of insight here.
But I guess what I would say
over 10 years is that what
you have to do when you have a new
idea like this is play with it.
And come to understand what its real
power is and what its strengths are and
what its weaknesses are.
You have to figure out what
the scope of the problem is.
Is the sweet spot for
this something the size of the Internet?
this something smaller?
In terms of applications, as Jeff said,
you need to throw use cases
at it to see what it actually works and
you need to play with it.
You need to figure out what it's good for.
I mean, when Teflon was discovered,
nobody knew what it was.
That was a mistake.
But when GPS was put forward, the original
designers completely didn't describe
what it was actually gonna
turn out to be good for.
And I'd make three comments in here.
I think Van thought that content
distribution might be a use case for this.
And I think content
distribution is a use case, but
the Internet does it pretty well today.
So in fact, that's not a compelling
reason for a transition.
I think a case where the thinking
in this project evolved in
a very powerful way was understanding how
to integrate security into this system.
I think that we're still fighting
the issues of security on the Internet.
And I think this provided an interesting
way to rethink security in
a very powerful way.
I think one of the interesting points,
which may not have been obvious in
the beginning, computer scientists
like to polish the data plane.
And Van talked about the data plane.
But in fact, I think one of
the interesting points about NDN is its
ability to improve and
simplify network management.
And people say, management,
that's such a boring topic.
God, if I write a proposal on management,
it won't get funded and
my career will be over.
And the answer is yeah, but that's one
of the things we really struggle with in
the Internet and
I think there's some real potential there.
I'll come back to that, but
we're trying to be quick here.
So that'll do for me.
>> Thank you, Dave.
Let's immediately jump to the next
presentation then from Darleen.
Please, Darleen
>> All right, can you hear me now?
>> Yes.
>> Okay, thank you.
So I thought you might be interested
in hearing a little bit about the NDN
history from my perspective inside NSF and
what happened that I thought was right.
So to be successful in research is to
move it from product to use technology,
which I think is desired
by the NDN community.
You must start with a great idea,
which I think is the very
hardest part of research.
And Van Jacobson's content-centric
networking that he started at PARC and
transitioned to NDN is such an idea.
But you also have to have funding to
go from an idea to a use technology.
And it was only serendipitous
that such funding was possible.
And in the end only happened because
there was confluence of interests at NSF.
We had a top executive who
wanted to leave a legacy,
a program director who wanted to research
infrastructure and something to run on it.
And another program director,
which has happened to me,
who wanted a new secure Internet.
And this resulted in GENI,
a research infrastructure and
the Future Internet Architecture,
FIA program, which I and
various program directors ran,
and which funded NDN.
We needed a paper and the paper was
David Clark's 2004 New'Arch article,
which provided the idea for
an initial community input into FIA.
And then, as David said, he went on to
help with us in terms of the FIA concept
and coordinating from the community,
the FIA awards.
I think that big successful innovative
projects need a zealous leader and
NDN just simply wouldn't have happened
as it is today without Leisha Zhang's
commitment to making it happen.
And of course, there were many,
many contributors,
including people from this panel.
And funding by other organizations
such as NIST and DARPA and Intel and
others supported to move NDN to enable
new technologies and new applications.
I think it's also critical to create
a research community beyond the initial
researchers.
And I think the establishment of ACM ICM
conferences won such successful approaches
as this NDN community workshops, such as
the one we're having these last two days.
And I look forward to
more NDN successes and
hope that it continues with the same
vitality as it's had today.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
[INAUDIBLE] is really proud
about having funded a project.
Great.
Thank you very much Darleen.
And Christos.
As very timidly said,
he has been working on NDN since 2010.
That's a quite an understatement,
please Christos.
>> Thank you, Christian.
So I'll be brief.
I think the other people before me have
put out the broad and bold vision of NDN.
For me, the highlights of
the past ten years include,
first of all,
the building of a robust Indian community.
And I'm really happy to see that NIST
has adopted the community meetings and
is nurturing the community.
My experience with people in the NDN
community is that those who have
big networking problems to solve,
such as the scientific community.
Once they see and
understand what NDN can do and
they realize their frustration with IP,
they become fervent supporters of NDN and
big believers.
And they have gone off to write
proposals and get funding and so forth.
I thought that was a great success
that we were able to reach
out to a set of people in
the community who have real needs and
they recognized that NDN could be
a real solution to their problems.
The other thing that I believe we
achieved is big improvements in NFD.
Again, with NIST supporting the effort and
watching the presentation
just before this one,
I think the NFD has gone a long way and
it still has a lot of promise.
And it looks like that we'll see
more great things coming out of
the team working on NFD.
That's a real need there, and I'm really
happy to see it and moving forward.
And the final thing I'm happy
to see is the few bolt energetic
companies who have realized
the potential of NDN.
And they're moving forward adopting it and
proving to the rest of the world that
NDN has a real commercial use and
you can actually use it to make money.
So I think that's a good thing.
Okay, thanks.
I'll stop here.
>> Thank you Christos.
Lan Wang next in our panelists row.
>> Can you hear me?
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
So I wrote my slide based on my
own experience, what worked well.
I'm just giving some examples.
So the first thing I think
worked well was that,
we use the routing protocol design and
implementation as an example.
Then the application to actually
validate the idea of multi party
communication through sync.
And we also used it to validate
the design of schematized trust.
And also help to improve
the libraries that implement
the same can the security mechanisms.
I think that is one good example
of an NDN application that
helps improve the development
of these main mechanisms.
The second example is that we,
later on develop this hyperbolic
routing scheme which is largely static.
This actually shows the main
difference between IP and
the forwarding plane is stateless and
cannot do smart things.
It just listens to what
routing tells it to do, but
in NDN the forwarding plane has stayed and
can be very smart.
So this kind of largely static routing,
forces us
to to make the forwarding plane
more smart in our own design.
And it actually works very well,
we deployed this hyperbolic routing
in the NDN testbed, along with
an adaptive forwarding strategy.
So that's another example of how we can
show the difference or
benefits of NDN over IP.
The third example, I think,
is decentralized applications.
Today a lot of social media and
other applications their
centralized cloud based.
Users don't really own their own data.
NDN, shy in that domain by
decentralizing these applications, so
users have their own data,
they can control their own privacy.
So in this area, I think we've started
to look at decentralized social
media applications,
decentralized smart home systems.
I think these are very good applications
to show the advantages of NDN over IP.
So these are the some of the examples.
I think that can really
help people appreciate how
NDN is different in terms
of the architecture.
>> Thank you for
showing the spectrum of things covered
in the project in that
ten years looking back.
I would like to invite Beichuang
to continue with his points.
>> Yeah, so Christian in the email
gave us sort of guidelines a thinking,
building in the end as building a house.
And what are the highlights and
improvements and what is the status?
So maybe I'm the only one
follow in that direction.
So, I'm not an expert in
building a house or building.
But think of a house.
I think there are three aspects,
one is the aesthetic aspect of it, and
second one is the functioning of it, and
the third one is the engineering of it.
All back to beauty.
But so [COUGH] thinking from this angle.
And to me the biggest highlight of NDN
is really the very basic core idea,
as Dave said is very bold
idea many other proposals.
But I think that not only is it bold but
also very simple, right?
the very core is your name the data.
After that,
if you accept that as your basic
starting point without anything else.
You naturally do have other things,
like myspace in the network,
the data centric security,
trust schema and
so, it's very powerful idea.
And I think to me,
I really appreciated this authentic
aspect of this NDN house.
And the highlight is,
I think in the last 10 years.
We've seen the emergence of the ICN/NDN
resort community, really means more and
more people start to appreciate that and
are willing to work on this idea.
So, to me that's the biggest one.
And in terms of functioning, I think it's
application development by the users.
So in last 10 years,
we have quite a number of developments.
And we have application users like,
data intensive scientists and
media and crystals walking with.
And we have the AR VR application
Jeff work has been working on and
a bunch of other applications.
In terms of the engineering of it.
We did designed a bunch
of protocols implemented
them in the prototype, and
we deployed on test flight.
And we also come up with new mechanism
to deal with providing new features.
So, looking at an NDN house,
it seems like we
have achieved quite
some very basic things.
Okay.
I think it's a far from finish,
but quite some components already there.
And it's more and
more people are working on it.
So, I think that's pretty much,
I think it's the highlights.
Yeah, that's it.
>> Thank you very much.
That's the topic per se but
really nicely told the story and
the aesthetic parts also
being part of the equation.
Thank you.
And the next slide now and
that is now rounding up past with she,
when asked about the role,
she also said keeping the team going.
And I think Darlene already pointed out
that role, so please, Lixia, your slide.
>> Thank you.
I hope you can see me now.
The being the last one, I can echo back
what the people have said already.
I think Darlene is exactly right.
With the great idea NDN proposed
without the NSF funding,
the NDN project without help started,
I think for that the whole NDN team.
And I guess the community really
appreciated the support from NSF So
all these years.
And second, I would say that during this
not just that I, you know, persisted.
I think it's the team.
The team persisted over ten years despite
a number of unexpected challenges.
So we don't have to go
down that path further.
There are really dark times difficult
times almost like someone was killing
the project.
But the team believed this direction.
That is this name.
The security data is the direction
to build the future networking.
So, there's a long road,
but i think we did great.
Going back to the idea that I
think the 10 years of experience
really proved that using
the named secure the data.
As the basic architecture building block
is exactly the right direction to go.
Patron.
I already mentioned that,
I remember that Dave Clark had
this paper many years back
on the design philosophy of
the tapper internet protocols.
That paper make a statement the same
day that the fundamental architectural
feature of the Internet is the use
of datagrams because of that,
correct the building block, and then
the Internet achieved many things that
property wasn't foreseen at the time
of the TCP IP spec publication.
I think that's exactly the same
happened with the NDN lan mentioned
that these days were utilizing the basic
idea of semantically named the data and
security data to push the frontier
of this distributed applications
last to developers that completely
distributed that social app tools.
And UCLA is now developing
this thing called NDN light,
that is completely end user
controlled smart home system.
We don't mean to say Cloud is not useful.
Cloud is a great resources,
just like where the control is
the control has to be returned back to
the end users hands yonder to really move
internet into the next stage of
distributed and the secured system.
So what, I would also want to point out
that I think I named the security data
is that building block but
that idea didn't just drop from
the sky one day need to pass had.
I've been working with one for
many years started from my MIT
student that is when he and
I argued a lot until later,
I started appreciating
the technical insight.
Yeah, we're working on the things
started with say this a scalable,
reliable multicast.
They essentially combined the idea
from still theories multicast
with Dave's idea of
application level framing.
That is the network is not about
the shooting the bullets to test nations.
But it's really about shaping the data.
Lissa application data to deliver
to whoever the dessert parties are.
The, I would also say that since that I've
been involved with IETF for so many years,
you can see that this state centric
direction has been picked up by mania.
Other efforts, just the question
is that how far we push that
a direction for the for the time being
is mostly stayed at a higher level.
And I think that's a really nice vision
that pushes direction all the way down
to build the infrastructure, so that
the whole thing will be more coherent.
Yeah, the secure as a foundation
to support the future networking.
And if I put them in
the last sentence there,
I think that the security has
to be built into the gene.
Of all the systems, I think there's,
you know, one part of the NDN getting
the right story isn't semantically named
and the security data as a building block.
That's from me for now.
>> Thank you, Lixia.
And now we have all eight panellists.
I would like to ask them, how would you
know like to organize the discussion?
Should I bring up some topic or
would somebody like to react on
some panelists others
comments complimented
So, let me make a first step here.
Lixia at the end has that statement
any angles the basic idea,
right and we heard a lot about
the applications being the validation
of exactly why in the end got it right.
Do you have some memories of specific
events where, this now simply becomes
easy or that was really a breakthrough
now with that new building block ID,
the basic ID that you can report on.
That would be one part of the question and
do you see other areas where still.
We might find such nice discoveries,
that now with NDN things get better.
>> And out the letter,
others have their opportunity.
Let me just mention one simple thing,
security.
I think in the early days when the man
talk to me about putting this whole
project together,
he keeps mentioning that it's really
about securing a data directory.
But from there, the utility of that idea,
I just expand it without the boundary.
For example, the crypto keys is nothing
more than a piece of name the data and
if you send it as a certificate,
so therefore NDN makes a security
really straightforward as a built
in the gene into the system.
The certificate is just a piece of data so
you can fetch it from anywhere.
Today if we want to know what's
the UserWay's crypto key,
I really don't know what
would be the way to find it
by the find in everything become
the trivialized to use that word.
And so and so is the trust policies.
If you want to know what are the UserWay's
of policies for this and for
that the one time my students
aggressor of course and
the registration page directed
him to some payment page.
That's not, can we share the website and
this happened to be
a student's work on security.
He passed a special they go there, right?
That's a simple [INAUDIBLE] example to
say that what is your trust policy,
which website you say we
actually trust this or that.
They direct the students to go
there to handle the payment.
What is the security policies
someone mentioned earlier about
NDN has this concept of a trust schema.
And that, again, it's simply a piece of
named security data with established and
naming conventions, again, you can
just refresh that piece of data and
construct the name to say, give me use
your way security policy for whatever.
But then we are working.
I would just stop there.
>> Thank you, somebody that's
fun to joining that discussion.
>> Well, I'll offer up a comment.
I think this may lead us into the second
round of questions you want to ask but
I think that, one of the questions
you have to ask as you explore what's
been discovered here is, what is
the right entanglement of the ideas?
What I mean by that is that, I think,
having data that is self secured state,
that is signed up
as a building block is
a very powerful idea.
It's an idea that could, and
there are limitations here,
that's an idea that could be integrated,
into the internet.
We could have a framework for
data that allows it to be signed and
so forth and so on.
And I think the fact that we
haven't moved in that direction
in the context of the internet or
we've moved further than we have is a is
a really interesting issue to contemplate.
But it's sort of begs
the question of whether
there is a uniform framework for
securing data that's universal.
And I think the the idea
in NDN was that well,
of course, there is a universal framework.
Because in the end,
every piece of information can be reduced
to a bag of bits and bits is bits.
And so
if you put the security at the bit level,
then you've got a universal architecture.
I think that's an area where there's
still the possibility of some debate it,
it might very well be the case that
you might like to apply the security
at a level where you haven't necessarily
reduced it to a bag of bits you need more
diversity and how it's done that
I think should be divorced.
That conversation should be
divorced from packet forwarding.
And the question of whether
you you want to integrate
the security model into
the packet level that is to say,
in some sense the NDN science packets,
it doesn't sign bags of bits.
It I asked for the first packet as for
the second packet, so the third packet.
I think one of the really
interesting questions
that this architecture helped to expose,
but I don't think we've yet answered
is the extent to which these ideas are
powerful when they're coupled together.
Or in fact now that we
understand them all,
you should freshly ask do they
need to be bundled together?
And I think that's a there's
some really interesting lacking
deep architectural questions here which,
In some sense,
you have to have a project as bold and
as as as
vigorous as NDN to sort of help force
the thinking through those things.
>> I like to partly disagree with Dave in.
There was the genesis
of the NDN data up yet
was that Ron Rico's work on sightsee and
some of the theoretical associated work.
Said, every security artifact that we know
how to build that we can
conceive of is based
on certificates is based
on these item potent units,
where you bind together a name that
has some context a key object,
and then a provenance signature that says,
what party asserts that
this name is the name
of this public key, this artifact.
And if you say well,
that data part doesn't
have to be a key,
it can just be arbitrary bits
that you know it's
a speech act you want to
make an edit adaptation that this context,
this data is asserted as
a Indivisible by this party.
Given that that seemed to be sort
of a universal building block, and
we build our global scale trust
systems out of it, question comes up.
Can you build other things?
The constraints of security
means lots of different things.
Usually its product in the context
of internet as some sort of global
trust deriving from global routes of trust
and Domain Name System and a bunch of
other stuff but what if you wanted to
do something bottom up like in a house?
What if you wanted to do something
that was between two parties or
small set of parties that have a common
interest and they just want to
have privacy and trust or
solely around their common interest?
So there was a theoretical proof,
forgetting the paper but
I can forward it to you that said,
well, certs to
the extent we can build those things your
building block is going to be searched.
The way that the search interrelate
is what defines the system.
And that has to do with the structure
that you put in the names.
And so I wanted NDN to have that
building block and I wanted
it to be used for lots of different
systems that mostly hasn't been.
There is work outside of NN.l There's
all area called self sovereign
security that's currently exploding
partly driven by another building
block getting Blockchains where
the security transactions are solely
between interested parties.
There's not a global trust route.
I think models like that.
Kathy Nichols has been doing
baited work in IoT trying to say
okay, a home can be a self sovereign
security environment and how,
how do we bootstrap that?
How can you make it automatic?
How do you make it work without
people having a lot of involvement?
And she's finding that NDN and
a particular take on trust
schemas work pretty well for it.
So I think there's a lot
of potential there.
I don't think the potential is in
the global scale security architectures,
because they're just way too constrained,
but.
I think there's a huge potential
in doing vocal security and
trust architectures in a way that's fairly
automatic using the building block.
>> It's not clear that
Van disagreed with me.
>> Yes I would certainly
agree with point answer
>> Looking at time and also now
And also now that people start to look
into the next step, where are we?
Let's quickly do in the middle the Round
2 and switch to slide sequence
where the question was asked,
where can we improve.
And I keep the sequence of panelists and
I would like to invite Van
to expand on his line that he sends me.
>> Hi, it as I looked through the hundred
thousand lines of c plus, plus that
represents the NDN cxx_library and
NFD the forwarding daemon.
What I see is a bunch of code
that's basically replicating
functionality this in IP is trying
to make NDN be the internet or
an implementation vehicle for
the internet.
There are two or three versions of TCP
congestion control in the cxx_library.
Okay, but this
wonderful things that
you have talked about
increase to serve a huge
unexplored problem areas
where there's just a crying need for
a different way of doing things.
Because the IP model isn't
a very good way of doing things,
things that based on agreement and
broadcast distribution.
Things that are about
the data in fundamental ways
not about conversations
between parties and,
I feel like the balance is wrong,
but there haven't been,
Enough applications driving the research.
Instead, the research is largely what's
in the researchers comfort zone.
Well, I've got a lot of experience
with this I want to apply NDN and
see how NDN affects inter domain routing.
Okay, but
communications vehicle is like NDN or
IP is a tool to solve problems.
It's not self contained
within itself its value is
how it helps people solve problems,
create new things.
And particularly at the start,
it seems like your focus should be okay,
who would like to take
a risk on using this?
Like Jeff Burke signed up early on said,
hey,
it's gonna be really painful
because there's nothing there.
We don't know what's gonna work but
lots of false starts.
It's the gap but
the idea is really intriguing.
So I'll buy into the pain.
It's mature enough so that there's less
pain and think see it this meeting.
There's a lot of people interested
in solving problems with it but
the foundation that
they've got to build on,
I think isn't nearly as
good as it could have been.
Because it's been more inwardly focused
and not outwardly focused towards okay,
what's the right thing to do for
the users?
How can we make things easy for
people who wanna do applications
on top of this framework?
And my feeling is that
resulted in lots of lost
opportunities on both sides,
the researchers in sort of expanding
their horizons in their comfort zone.
And the application developers
in not having a usable,
useful tool they can see as a useful idea,
but
that the usability is my feeling is
not where it should be 10 years in.
Stop there.
>> Okay,
sorry I lost connectivity it seems.
Thank you I get the topic of NFD
maybe we can take it among all
that I might take over but,
>> I assume, Kristen, should I go ahead?
>> I think you should go ahead.
>> Go ahead.
>> So the same bullets as earlier so
maybe I can just in terms of
where things could be improved,
I agree with what Van was saying.
>> Maybe here, Mr.
Bean,
>> Yes.
>> Okay, and
certainly ease of use would go a long
way in kind of two different ways.
One, certainly the act of experimentation
at the application layer.
But also something I think we
learned more recently from ICR
was being able to throw
simple applications into
challenging network environments that
lP deployment would struggle with.
With something that also is hard that
it takes a fair amount to sustain
a reasonable NDN network infrastructure
for testing applications.
And so
it means that some of the robustness and
in particular for
use of multiple even things as simple as
use of multiple interfaces
are implementing redundancy in producers.
And so on those things are challenging
to do so both ease of use for
applications but
also ease of use in terms of
deploying in challenging situations
where NDN's should be well.
And with even very simple applications
that we that we already have,
and so those are two I
think areas of improvement.
I think during some of the conversation,
it feels like we are still orbiting around
network forwarding as the kind of
the key part of the conversation.
And I also think,
Missha I think had mentioned this in
previous conversations in other venues.
We may have missed some of the criticality
of working with integrating storage and
trying to understand the crossover
between at least from an application
developers perspective.
The crossover between what are networking
problems and what our database problems.
And storage problems that kind of come
together in trying to figure out how to
design applications to take full advantage
of a data centric stack underneath.
And so hopefully I know, at least at UCLA,
some of our research will hopefully
come back around to that.
So those are just a few things
that I think could be improved.
>> Thank you, Jeff.
And sorry about getting
the slides wrong for you.
Next in line would be Dave and
here I extracted one line which is not
really where things could improve.
But I think you already wanted to
move in taking up a topic of your own
when it comes to where things
could be improved, please Dave.
>> Well, I wanna respond to what some of
the people have been saying here because,
Along about 1995, I had this
bucket of cold water realization
about the future of the Internet, which is
the technology was not shaping the future.
It was the economics,
it was the investment decisions.
And it was the role of the different
actors in the ecosystem.
That was shaping the future
of the Internet.
And I want to play off again, sort of what
Spanng said and Jeff said and so forth.
One of the challenges you have
when you're trying to set up
a network in your home
is the question of how
much you're dependent on resources
that are not under your control.
And and we do have a problem
there that most consumers
are not qualified to import a Linux box
into their house or on a server on it.
And in fact,
the ability to have services out in the
cloud is very appealing until of course,
you're amputated from the cloud and you
discover your cat on lock your front door.
And I think that the tension we've
dealt with in the global Internet
is the realization that you're in
an ecosystem in which you have to accept
the fact there are actors there whose
incentives are not aligned with yours.
And so
there is a question of what role you how
very carefully how you delegate a role.
And Jeff just talked about storage and you
can't talk about storage in the network,
that sentence is not up I would
like to unstained that sentence.
Because I don't trust all
elements in the network equally.
I am not prepared to just talk about
a homogeneous architecture of storage.
And I think that Vance comment
about trust is dead on that.
That the relationship
between where things are done
in the network has to relate to where
they are trusted and who holds the trust.
And I take a very edge centric view here.
Let me say that which is trust
ought to derive from users,
that is to say,
if I'm willing to trust Google, well,
that's my decision,
doesn't mean you have to trust Google.
I don't want somebody up above
telling me to trust Google, or
trust Comcast,
because Comcast is my provider.
Now, that's the tension here,
that I have no choice as to whether
to have Comcast as my provider.
And because I have no choice,
I want to minimize the trust.
And that actually says,
maybe I don't want Comcast doing certain
things in the architecture I want
to minimize what they do precisely because
I have to use them and I don't trust them.
And I need not trust them,
I want to minimize my trust.
And and once you begin thinking about the
positioning of function based on trust,
I think you may discover that you want
to remodularize some of your thoughts.
I was going to say several other things
that I'll just mention them because i
don't want to run out of time here.
All ideas when they get real
come down with complexity.
And we have to face the fact
that one of the tests of
an architecture is how well it copes
with the complexity of success.
Clearly I'd say the Internet has come
down with a high degree of complexity.
In some cases, it's powerful.
Some cases, it's incredibly irritating.
I want to come back to this point of
the power of state in the routers,
I think that's an idea who was full
utility has not yet been extracted.
And of course, we knew what was going to
be hard about information centric network,
which was information centric routing.
And I think there's a fundamental
challenge there, which again relates to
how much I want to tell different
parts of the network what I am doing.
And I've always had this lurking concern.
And again, Vance and
I have disagreed here.
I've always had this lurking concern that
maybe I would like, I don't want all
of the networks I'm using to know the name
of all the information I'm retrieving.
And that's not a technical comment
about trust and balance of power.
And that's a dimension, which in fact,
a lot of computer scientists are not
well trained to think through.
So this is another forcing function
which I think is becoming more and more
critical for us as the network becomes
more and more a central part of society.
So those are the sort of my thoughts
about what we ought to do and
that may have been my brown
three answer as well.
>> So, of course I come from NSF,
so I have the NSF perspective.
I'm always concerned as
the NDM teams about funding.
So, the bigger the project gets the more
people you have, the more money you need.
It also I think bleeds from research
to development to deployment.
And from NSF perspective, it's always
where does the research begin and end?
And if it's research,
is it still innovative?
And does the research community that
does the reviews of proposals see
the challenge and
understand the challenges and NDN.
And not just say, well,
IPS already solved it.
So what are you doing?
Because it's already been solved.
I think there's a lot of issues here and
other funding sources are going
to have different concerns.
But I think, this is just
a problem of how do you fund and
continue funding big projects like that.
I think another big challenge is
selling the end end concept and
its usage to broad spectrum of users and
making it easy to use.
This has been brought up before.
I think others have noted and I think
I agree that use at the edge or within
an enterprise is more promising than
trying to take over the whole internet.
But even that, even those are challenging.
I think the third up
chat set of challenges
is managing transitions
because the context changed,
expertise may change, funnding may change,
somebody sources, so on and so forth.
And then a question I
have is as NDN moves from
all NDN development and research project
out into usage and community, how
do you create a common base of of NDN?
Or do you just let 100 flowers
grow independently is that okay or
is this going to be a future challenge?
And then finally,
because my original interest in FIA
was in supporting a secure internet.
I want to ask the question about
in addition to designing or
having been secured by design is
that also secured by implementation.
And are NDN folks using formal
methods of verification or
other approaches that helped
create a more reliable and
secure product infrastructures
code set and so on.
And then do we need more research
on new to NDN security risks?
So I don't know the answers to those but
those are some questions I
would raise about the future.
>> So, if I were to summarize
my position on where I think
things can be improved, it would be
simply by saying we need a success story.
We need NDN to solve a problem
from beginning to end,
be adopted,
have users that are outside our circle.
And do something that these is
universally recognized as useful.
I think that will go a long way towards
helping everybody else understand
that NDN can actually do things,
be used in production and so forth.
And I think that can happen.
We started working with
users with climate and
physics and genomics, and
I think that's great.
And I think that that should continue.
And I really wanna see something
useful coming out of them.
And by useful I mean something
that the the scientists will use.
And then actually turn around and say yes,
this helped me to improve my research.
The the other area that I'm looking
at these days and there's by no means
any guarantee that we'll be successful,
is the automotive part.
And then what I see there is
an industry that has rapidly moved
from networking that according
to our standards will be
the Dark Ages the limbus,
the canvas and so forth.
Through automotive Ethernet
into a world where
all the Internet technologies have
now become accessible to them.
I mean, they're talking about security.
They're talking about using
VLANs to secure their devices.
And they have moved from a tiny world
of interconnected things in a car,
to dozens of ECUs in a car but
also through connected vehicles
through the infrastructure,
essentially the rest of the world.
That's a huge leap.
My impression is that they're hoping
that Internet technologies are there and
they're ready to help them solve some of
these big problems that they're facing.
But I suspect that just like what
we have discovered, the problems
in the Internet, they will soon find
out that the Internet technologies that
they're looking at may not be as
wonderful as they initially think.
And I'm hoping to be there with NDN
to catch them when they realize that.
Again, this may completely fail.
I have no idea if this
is going to succeed,
the automotive industry
is very conservative.
It's very standards oriented.
They will not do things that
haven't been vetted really well.
But on the other hand,
they are a very competitive industry.
And they are looking for
ways to be on top of the competition.
And I'm hoping that the reaction
we can get from them is something
analogous to what we got from
the scientists when they saw NDN and
they said, I want this, I gotta have this.
This is going to help me.
So the jury's still out there,
we will see.
But just to summarize,
I think what we need is success stories.
I think we should try multiple places.
We're trying health, we're trying climate,
we're trying automotive,
we're trying other things.
But we need to keep trying and,
hopefully get ourselves to a point
where we do have this success story
that we can point to, thanks.
>> So I think I wrote three points for
what could be improved.
One is more usable applications and tools.
I think that's consistent with what
previous panelists have talked about.
So I think one problem is that we
have abandoned some of the applications or
tools we developed ourselves and
did not maintain them.
That's one issue that we need
to address going forward.
So whenever we update the libraries,
we need to update
the applications,
make sure that they still function.
And also listen to the users and
make changes that they request.
So this is a lot of work,
I think, for a research team.
We are not, at least the funding,
most of it is not supposed
to support maintenance or
features in the tools or applications.
But I think for usability,
for maintaining a community,
we have to do that,
that's our responsibility.
That's something we have
to commit to going forward.
The second one is, Let me see actually,
More wireless and mobile support.
And this has been lacking I think for
awhile.
I think most of us are not originally
researchers in the wireless mobile domain.
So we're more used to doing
research in a wired setting.
But I think a lot of applications
are more edge oriented.
They need wireless and mobile support.
So that is something we
really have to focus on for
the next stage if we really want to
have a successful application
that many end users will adopt.
So that's the second point.
The third point is more running code,
not just designs in papers or simulations.
But this is something I think the PIs and
advisors have to pay attention to.
The students definitely need publications
to graduate and for their job search.
We also need papers for funding.
But in order to have this architecture
adopted by the community,
we need running code.
Just like IETF, we have the RFC plus
the running code, we need that too.
So one, I think in one of
the earlier NDN conferences,
I said before graduate students graduates,
they need to finish their
implementation in NFT or the libraries.
So I guess this is more for the advisors.
They need to keep in mind that the running
code is as important as the publication.
That's my three wishes of
what could be improved.
>> So a lot of people already
mentioned a lot of points.
I will just focus on one.
Back to the house analogy Christian
gave us, I think what we could
The improve is the functioning
of the house and
engineering policy especially
the interface between these causes.
So that occasion and the network,
when we started this Indian project
is new internet architecture.
So people at least me included is a lot
of I think about layer three, right.
That's a network like that you
have a new architecture, but
actually it's a very
much understatement and
the impact or
requirements of both the upper layer,
the applications and as well as the lower
layer two and the network media.
Otherwise you don't get all the full
architectural benefits, right.
For example,
you can just run some very simple
translation run over Indian network.
Then you may be able to run it by your
own be able to get all the full benefits,
though.
But when you design network,
we're constantly struggle between
having systems that can work
reasonably well with given
underlying infrastructure,
existing infrastructure on the internet.
You need to work on those reasonable
while, so that you can compete or
demonstrate but as well as providing
the functionality is required.
Wish applique [INAUDIBLE] So,
I think that was a lot of
struggles through out the years.
With real or not bold enough to
do some of and looking forward,
I think I totally agree with crystals and
other people said, we need success story,
we need applications that
can make the case for any.
I think we need more iteration between
application design and network design and
to, to make that iteration effective and
more often.
I think that API that interface
between the application and
the network,
I think that is a crucial piece.
The common name library
developed by Jeff Burke,
I think that's very good foundation for
this kind of API.
Once we can flush out most of
detail of this API that can help
users to write applications
without understanding,
the underlying details of Indian,
they just look at how to manipulate data
without worrying how
network supports that.
And with that API and
network can also think,
hey, how can I support this
API in a more efficient way?
And of course,
this API can take some time, either way.
But I think that's, to me going forward.
That's the thing.
Well, in the past,
we shouldn't have done this much earlier.
But going forward as a team,
we should focus and have that flush out,
so that we can allow one more application
to be easily divided up by different
users, as well as give
them to evolve over time.
So, if I pick one thing
concrete standpoint.
[INAUDIBLE].
Between the functioning of the house and
the, engineering of the house.
>> [INAUDIBLE].
Yeah, go ahead.
>> I think next thing around
two is leisure, next slide.
>> Well, he put the for
the two of the things together, but
let me just say that my answer
to the second one about,
what could have been done better
is really the first bullet.
That is I wish we had been truly
application driven architecture
development as we claim the in
the early days of the project.
And then that will drive us to
build more usable applications.
For that have some light words.
I have always feel happy that
my last name started with Z so
and end up with the last one.
If things are there, divide the alphabet.
But today after last talk I really
wish my last name started with A,
I can go read after that,
I think neither one should have
put the situation in
the proper time perspective.
Back then in 2010, we are under
the future internet architecture program.
And at that time, although we
didn't say that we do application
driven architecture developments,
whether we're under the pressure
about making the Indian scale
to the global internet.
I remembered we get bombarded with all
the questions, how this can possibly scale
when you keep the state per daily gram,
I think that's where the early
days of effort went into,
which is the two response to the community
about those challenging questions.
But with the hinge site, of course,
we should have totally focused on
just the application development.
And that will actually force all
the hard problems on the table.
For example, the security,
when you divide the usable applications
with the Indians notion that security
has to be built into the gene of every
single piece of the architecture.
Usability and security besides we get
to the basic building block right, but
the usability of the security will
be right there one has to address,
what are the nicest stories about how
Indian can easily support security but
the code is not there
in terms of usability.
They've mentioned about there's
the complexity situation.
But once you feel the real applications,
I think Jeff mentioned this many
times is actually gonna highlight
how you get the architecture right.
That can simplify the system design
really by orders of magnitude.
Look at the today's internet.
Broad applications never
cared about addresses.
That's why people are doing the HTTP
using URL or URI rather than
IP addresses because they look for
that piece of HTTP object, not the note.
That connects to it, for
the today's internet works on the address.
And that created all the complexity about
how we might between this disconnect,
between what the network does and
what the applications want.
I think that how do we focus on
the applications are building the use of
applications.
I think all of these advantages
of Indiana will be again, right.
You can see it on the table
regarding the naming question, and
again, that thing can also be addressed
if we have focused on the application.
The privacy or not worried about privacy
applications were gonna tell us yeah,
and if a privacy becomes really
the fundamental thing, I mean,
where computer science
everyone knows there's a quote
that one level of indirection
solve all the problem.
It's not so much semantical names.
It's the wrong choice for the rather
edges that how you can obscure that name.
All you needed is really consistent
mapping between whatever the names,
you wish to use and whatever the names
that get exposed to the outsiders.
So, back now we do
the Indian light design.
We actually figure out
how we can do that right?
Using semantic names but not exposed as
plain text of what you're talking about.
The, I think Betrand
said things are the if we
want to do the Architecture driven,
I mean, the application
driven architecture development we
had to make the applications easy.
I did that tell people around,
I think Jeff heard this many times that
I think Jeff is really the boss
of the edge-in team because he
has kept telling us in
now what you need to do,
we just didn't listen to that well.
And I think over the last year or so
will help definitely change
the direction of addressing
the challenges of supporting
NDN application development.
And also Tellagami added
the last sentence there.
The history actually is a filled with lots
of kind of random factors you might think.
Yeah and actually say that Indian team
which has been lucky that we can just
work, he really pushed
the architecture design forward
by presenting the real issues that
the applications actually care.
I mentioned this to Jeff myself.
I think that I don't know how the India
would help in over the ten years,
I think 70 we're gonna
eventually end up right but
the probably gonna take longer
without the Jeff's view of unity.
That's all from me for now.
>> Okay.
Thank you, Lisa.
Next slide in Christian's deck on round 3.
The question is, where are we now and
closing statements?
And starting with Van Jacobson.
>> I didn't know how to answer this
one because it's without one answer.
Different people have different
views of the world and
they do their work based on
their views and their goals.
There's a growing interest
in NDN as an idea and
is a toolkit, it, many have said it
needs work to flesh out the idea,
make it more concrete, more understood and
I think the toolkit needs quite a lot of
work because it's been
research vehicle and
it contains many different agendas.
It's way too vague and
as Leisha pointed out,
its original genesis
was the FIA project and
it was very focused on
next generation internet.
So it was focused on global scale,
which is not really the target of Indian,
the Internet does a really really
good job at local scale but
it's not so great at local scale.
Like my house, the solving
local problems locally is not something
that's easy with the internet.
It should be easy with NDN.
But the toolkit we have
doesn't support it.
As land pointed out.
Wireless has been broken in NFV for
several years now, as I discovered,
much to my chagrin when trying to use it
locally, and that's kind of inexcusable.
It still supports a broadcast model but
it's fine replicated unicast and
haven't spoken.
I'm sorry.
You've got radios.
They should be radios.
Hey, I think some of
the problems that they've
brought up both struck me one
because they're gonna related.
You get complexity when you get big
because you have a lot of different
interests that you've got to balance and
control.
And if you want something
with high function, but
it's at a global scale you
don't wanna end up high function means you
don't want the lowest common denominator.
But global scale means you've
got kazillion constraints.
And so you end up with something that's
not nearly as tuned as it could be
in the end lets you do
things that local scale.
And again we're trying to do it
in my house where I'm sitting,
we're trying to set up an IoT system
based on a very simple pub sub
over Indian using local trust schemas that
are more or less automatically set up.
I think
we're avoiding traps, like saying
there has to be a common namespace,
because there isn't,
that namespace is bind, right up.
I generated the search that
anchor that namespace.
They never leave this house, I can't
even get the signing key is buried in
a hardware module,
a TPM that I can't pull it out.
So only things in the house that
can you can use that namespace and
that really limits
the problems that you can get into with a
routing, I never have to worry about these
devices routing over the internet
because they can't get to the internet.
They can't get out of the house.
There's a really limited number of things
that can do anything in that namespace and
they all talk by a broadcast so
they never rout.
There's no net any way that
information wants to get to the internet
is via an agent that republishes it.
And that agent is something that I own.
And it can filter the information
the way that I want it filtered.
I'll tell our solar
company something about the production
of our panels because they need it for
maintenance, but I'm the one that
presents them that information and
it's done by my agent on the border and
they can't talk to my panels.
So, I think that you can.
Make pieces that co-evolve,
if you start locally and
solve local problems, that solution
inherently includes a boundary.
You've got a set of names that you
know exactly who the community is,
and that makes a boundary that
you can then put agents that say,
all right, here's how this community is
going to interact with the outside world.
With some other community or with some
provider that I think lets you grow
in an orderly way, preserve the economics
but not influence the privacy.
I don't think we've done
enough work there, but
I think there's huge potential there.
Stop.
>> Sure, I think we've already talked,
on on this panel I think about the, and
yesterday in the community meeting, about
a lot of different application areas where
there's interest in potential for NDN.
But I think just to add one
different perspective or
different group of users is that we've had
some discussions, and Wayne alluded to,
is that it does seem like there's
a nice opportunity to make the existing
set of ideas and tools available
to people who are not industries.
Who are making smaller interesting
experimental projects in the hacker and
maker space in education that
are basically building on existing
tools for decentralization.
Whether it's coming from the IPFS realm or
DAT, other solutions that may or
may not be compatible with an NDN way
of thinking, but are when you say,
I'm gonna make a decentralized app or
where people are looking.
And it still is sort of fascinating
to me that we haven't yet
been able to position NDN for that
community as an experimental tool set.
I think the other example recently,
being remote from
our UCLA facilities has caused
it to look at zero tier and
other solutions to create sort
of virtualized ethernet networks
among the systems and
devices that we wanna work with.
And so that the half of me
that has to deploy things
is excited about the solutions
that are out there for
reasonable deployment of some remote and
quasi decentralized apps.
And then the part of me looking at an NDN
is like why can't we deliver the current
ideas, which may not be done, may not be
ready for certain applications to that
community that would like to experiment
with decentralized applications.
And that's kind of
a frustrating point to be at.
But it does seem to sort of reflect
this point that we're at now,
which is there really are two faces
to use the NDN term maybe poorly.
For the NDN community and
the NDN architecture which
are the face looking to users
that want solutions and
then the face that needs to continue
driving forward the individual
sort of research topics to make
the architecture viable and secure.
And I think it's an exciting place to be
in, but I think both of them have the type
of funding and structural challenges
that Darlene alluded to earlier.
And putting some energy around figuring
out how to get both of those things moving
is both daunting and kind of exciting.
>> Thanks, Jeff.
Dave, what are your
thoughts on the question?
Where are we now?
>> I know we're running behind,
so let me try to be quick.
I absolutely understand what Jeff
was saying where he wants to get
tools out there in front of the hacker
maker community and so forth.
But if this architecture
is going to succeed,
it has to be usable by people
who do not have that skill set.
And I was listening to Van talking
about setting up his home, and
I absolutely believe in
Van's desire to have
an edge centric solution,
I'm not disagreeing at all.
But whatever he does it has to
be replicatable by his mother.
And what the market has learned is
that users are happy having services
dedicated into the cloud because
it makes them easier to manage.
And we lose a great deal of
autonomy because of that.
And in fact, the users,
if you look at behavior, are happy to give
up that autonomy, give up that control,
and lose control of the trust structure.
Because otherwise they're left
with an unmanageable situation.
And so I would say that there
are two big challenges here.
And one of them is building
applications is big.
Applications are bigger than, I meanif you
look at the complexity of the Internet
versus the complexity of big applications,
applications are a lot harder.
Where you get the resources,
the commitment to build the applications.
And then the second one is to think
through from the very beginning
the question of systemic usability.
And I think that that's a question which
is almost in some senses independent
of NDN.
That is to say, I could ask exactly
the same question about wiring up
my house with the Internet.
If NDN has made it easier, that's fine.
But the proof of that is you can give
this to somebody who doesn't know what
a network is and
they can turn it on and make it work.
And I think that's a really
important challenge going forward.
And it's big and it's clumsy, and
computer scientists don't like
to do that kind of stuff.
>> Darlene, any final thoughts?
>> Yeah, so much of what's been said
in the panel has been extensions
of things that I've heard before or
more or better, more clear statements.
But the thing that I have not heard
before, and I'm curious about whether or
not you knew this in 2010.
Is the statement about should have
focused on applications, not on global
architectures, or focused on smaller
enterprise and location.
Is this something you knew in 2010 or
is that something you've come to realize?
That's my question to the community.
>> That's something we knew in 2010 was,
When Ben was describing
the internet at ICCC in 1977,
Andy Frazier said, are you trying
to reinvent the phone system?
Ben said, no,
that would be stupid, we're trying to do
things that the phone system doesn't do.
And that was I thought
a massively successful approach.
And that's what we tried to
follow within NDN by bringing
in applications that were the pain points
of the Internet Protocol applications
that weren't well served by the Internet.
So it was not reinvent the Internet,
try and invent communications for
things that weren't well
served by the Internet.
>> I don't think that's necessarily what
I heard when you said do applications and
don't do, well anyway, that's okay.
But I found this really
an interesting set of comments.
>> Final thoughts?
>> Yeah, I'll be very brief.
So I think we're still
a research project and
we need to move out of being
a research project into
something that will actually help users.
And we're having great conversations,
discussing
NDN and what it is and what it should
be sort of at the fundamental level.
What I'd like to see too at the same time
in parallel with those conversations
is reaching out to people out
there who have real problems,
trying to understand what their problems
are, where their pain points are.
And then sort of standing up
the NDN approach to these problems,
and trying to understand how
NDN would solve these problems.
I think these approach would not
only help users understand NDN,
but also help us mature
our thinking about NDN.
So I'd like to see a little more of that,
thanks.
>> Thanks Christos.
Lan, the last slide?
>> Okay, so
I'm just borrowing this figure from
the Gartner's research
report of last year.
They put NDN as one of
the technologies that
are still on the up curve.
So that means still,
it's a good prospect for
this technology and
there's interest in it.
I think that is a good
thing for NDN.
I think we need to,
this is the critical stage now,
we don't want to fall off this curve.
We want to expand the community and
make the code easily
usable by other people, so
that we quickly go up this curve.
But I think there's still a good
amount of interest in the technology.
And I believe in this direction and
I think all of us believe
in this research direction.
It's just that we need to
really orient ourselves
to the application developers and users,
so that we can quickly
broaden the community and
develop some successful applications.
Hopefully next year we will
be higher in the curve.
>> Thank you Lan.
Beichuang, are you the first?
>> So,
I think we have the basic foundation for
future development model of NDN.
And more the focus in the future,
I think that really with applications will
be bolder in terms of exploring
the architectural benefits.
So, I think that covers similar points.
We need API easy and friendly to use so
that different users with,
we have no idea and can use NDN code
to create their own applications and
actually can demonstrate or
benefit from the underlying architecture.
I think that's what need to be done
to move NDN to the next stage.
Well, that's it.
>> Thanks Beichuang.
Last but not the least Lixia, your final
thoughts and you get to wrap up the panel.
>> I know we're running out of time,
but I do hope-
>> Yeah.
>> That some more discussion after me.
I would agree with Beichuang either,
after ten years,
I think we built the basic foundation to
let the broader community to explore.
Like I put it here that we actually
learned what are the difficulties
in pushing and where we should push,
that is the edge-in.
By edge, I really mean the two
kind of ways of edge talking about
the local applications that you
don't have to consult your ISP or
clouds, you can just build it yourself.
Today we are in the resource
rich environment, computations,
bandwidth memories, it's cheap,
it's very cheap and everywhere.
The question is really how we
can make the best use of that,
to build a very powerful
applications right in your house.
I would agree with Dave's challenge.
That application has to be usable,
say by my mom, who is 88 years old,
that's a big challenge,
but that is a criteria.
So, another edge is the applications,
that applications can run over anything.
Just like early days of IP.
You do DevOps, you do whatever things
that can carry datagrams around,
then NDN can communicate.
So, that's where we should push.
I would also give them the last one.
I heard other people's questions,
I'd like to clarify a few things.
That is like, what build applications
is now that any of those
are gonna become, This big success
themselves, maybe some would.
But the fundamental thing
to us as the architecture
is to actually understand what works,
what's missing.
So, use the applications to drive
the architecture development.
That is at least, I think is the team's
interest to understand how well
this basically design actually support
applications and make things easier.
But also I agree that the usability
really has two parts, separable parts.
One is the design.
How NDN's design should
best support applications.
And then the other one is
the challenge Lan mentioned,
the usability of the code,
the maintenance, support.
That is a challenge that I think graduate
students being brilliant as they are,
are not the right working
force to provide that.
I think that remains as a challenge.
>> Thanks, Lixia.
We are behind schedule.
There's an interesting
discussion going on on the chat.
But unfortunately,
I don't think we can take questions.
So if there's any final thoughts
from the panel, or a minute or two.
Otherwise, we conclude the panel.
We thank you very much all the panelists.
And we're supposed to come back at 1:15.
I think we can stick to that schedule and
have a shorter break.
So see you all back at 1:15.
Thank you very much.